<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2006/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2006-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Making The Case</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/making-the-case/"/><published>2006-04-25T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/making-the-case/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Why is it that certain days I opt for the Man&rsquo;s coffee and other days I champion
the locals? I thought it had something to do with consistency but that&rsquo;s
bullshit. While the Man&rsquo;s store is well designed and has a familiar atmosphere
it reeks of fake smiles, stale business folk, and overly perfect pastries.
Admittedly those dainty pastries are quite wonderful, but thats besides the
point.</p>
<p>The locals aren&rsquo;t afraid to show attitude, they&rsquo;re real, they proudly bear the
title, Barista. The customers are genuine, eclectic and unpredictable. Plus you
feel honored to support local uniqueness and individuality.</p>
<p>So why do I still drink from the Man&rsquo;s hand? I don&rsquo;t know. Maybe it&rsquo;s because
they have better parking.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Don't Stress</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/dont-stress/"/><published>2006-04-22T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/dont-stress/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Your heart starts pounding, blood pressure soars and you begin to take shorter
faster breaths. Why do we put every cell in our body through such a traumatic
experience?</p>
<p>Stress was hard wired into our bodies for those face to face moments with
mountain lions. It&rsquo;s called fight or flight. Mountain lions don&rsquo;t seem to bother
us anymore so we&rsquo;ve repurposed this reaction to things like client deadlines,
idiots on the freeway, and that bar that plays horrible music on wednesday
nights below my loft. I&rsquo;ve decided for myself this is unacceptable so here is
what I&rsquo;m doing to combat this ridiculous instinct.</p>
<ul>
<li>Exercise: Clears my head and makes me a lot happier the following day.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t Pass the Buck: Some might think this causes more stress but in my
experience it doesn&rsquo;t. Suck it up and move on.</li>
<li>Make Task Lists: This gets the stuff you try to remember off your mind so you
can make room for other things.</li>
<li>Check Off Tasks: For every three tasks I write down I try to immediately
complete one of them. This inevitably leads to checking off more.</li>
<li>Get It Done: When it&rsquo;s done it&rsquo;s off your plate and out of your mind.</li>
<li>Controlled Breathing: This may sound weird but if you control the speed at
which you breath in and out it has enormous calming effects on the body.</li>
<li>Stretching: Certain stretches can make you feel more introverted or extroverted.</li>
</ul>
<p>Stress is very counter productive and we need to be more aware of how stupid it is.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Don't Delete, Version</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/dont-delete-version/"/><published>2006-04-19T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/dont-delete-version/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Lately I&rsquo;ve been toying with the idea of versioning. And I don&rsquo;t mean versioning in the programming sense, although I really need to figure out <a href="http://subversion.tigris.org/">Subversion</a> one of these days. I&rsquo;m referring to content management systems.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t know why but deletion just bugs me. Maybe its my pack rat mentality but to delete is to lose. I write blog entries all the time that don&rsquo;t get published and sometimes I completely rewrite them losing past versions. This seems more important in CMS&rsquo;s where content evolves and sometimes needs to be step back. From what I&rsquo;ve experienced this isn&rsquo;t easy, or even an option in most cases.</p>
<p>Is this a needed feature? <a href="http://www.wiki.org/">Wiki&rsquo;s</a> do a fantastic job of this. <a href="http://www.writeboard.com/">Writeboards</a> by <a href="http://www.37signals.com">37Signals</a> are a great example (love the compare feature). But how often do you see a site managed by a Wiki or a Writeboard? I&rsquo;d like to know your thoughts.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Rules Rule</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/rules-rule/"/><published>2006-04-17T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/rules-rule/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>As children we grew up hating curfew, as adolescence we rebelled against the
drinking age, and as adults we shake our fists at stop lights and speed limits.
What we don&rsquo;t realize is rules set us free.</p>
<p>I came across this simple notion in Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi&rsquo;s book Flow
(<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060920432/)">http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060920432/)</a>. By having laws and rules we free
ourselves from contemplating things that have already been determined. This
provides a framework for thought which is valuable when applied to design.</p>
<p>Have you ever noticed how hard it is to be original? Thinking up a completely
new idea from scratch is extremely daunting. So don&rsquo;t. Stop trying to reinvent
the wheel and start improving it. Don&rsquo;t be afraid to embrace the basic
properties and laws of something with the determination of making it better.
This at least gets you in gear and you&rsquo;ll be surprised what original ideas will
sprout up once the wheels are moving. It&rsquo;s better to be producing than
deadlocked on what to produce.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>My Easter</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/my-easter/"/><published>2006-04-16T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/my-easter/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Woke up around 11:30 after a long night of coding (<a href="http://www.rubyonrails.com">http://www.rubyonrails.com</a>).
Had a turkey sandwich and some pretzels while watching some television (<a href="http://www.historychannel.com">http://www.historychannel.com</a>).
Packed up some essentials: laptop (<a href="http://www.apple.com/powerbook/)">http://www.apple.com/powerbook/)</a>, couple
(<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060920432/">http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060920432/</a>) books (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0465024114/)">http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0465024114/)</a>,
and headphones (<a href="http://www.stanc.net/eggo/)">http://www.stanc.net/eggo/)</a>. Drove to the cafe
(<a href="http://www.broadwaycafeandroastery.com">http://www.broadwaycafeandroastery.com</a>) that breaks for no resurrection. Had a
soy latte while improving some Rails code and listening to some music
(<a href="http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewAlbum?id=2960659&amp;amp;s=143441)">http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewAlbum?id=2960659&amp;amp;s=143441)</a>.
Then I came home, worked out, read (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596007655/)">http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596007655/)</a>,
and listened to some piano. Now I&rsquo;m just finishing up rearranging my loft. Happy
Easter everyone!</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Jason Collett</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/jason-collett/"/><published>2006-04-06T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/jason-collett/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Just got back from a session with Jason Collett (<a href="http://www.arts-crafts.ca/jasoncollett/">http://www.arts-crafts.ca/jasoncollett/</a>)
from Broken Social Scene (<a href="http://www.arts-crafts.ca/bss/)">http://www.arts-crafts.ca/bss/)</a>. I highly recommend
checking this man out. Has sort of a modern day Bob Dylan appeal with fresh
percussion. Their newest album, Idols of Exile, offers quaint morsels of
Canadian goodness. If you&rsquo;re in need of something fresh and lighthearted, look
no further. I only wish Mrs. Feist could have made an appearance.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>After SXSW</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/after-sxsw/"/><published>2006-03-14T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/after-sxsw/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I already miss waking up in the morning and planning my day at the Hide Out over a cup of joe. I miss that walk from 7th and Congress to the convention center seeing fellow lanyards. More importantly I miss seeing those who contribute so much to the beautiful corners of our web.</p>
<p>There were some great panel lineups and as much as I love hearing about tech and code I felt like distancing myself from the technical aspects of our industry and focus on listening to what others had to say about the roles psychology and sociology play in what we do.</p>
<p>One of my favorites had to be <a href="http://2006.sxsw.com/interactive/programming/panels/?action=bio&amp;id=111060">Charles MacInerney&rsquo;s</a> discussion on How To Increase Creativity At Work. His overview of brain wave frequencies, mind mapping, paradigm shifting and yoga techniques really opened my eyes. I&rsquo;ve been practicing his breathing and stretching techniques and they really do work!</p>
<p>Another panel that stuck with me was <a href="http://2006.sxsw.com/interactive/programming/panels/?action=bio&amp;id=103421">Kathy Sierra&rsquo;s</a> presentation on Creating Passionate Users. Kathy summed it up best, &ldquo;it doesn&rsquo;t matter what people think about your brand, it&rsquo;s about how they think about themselves.&rdquo; I&rsquo;m so intrigued about the human brain and this panel was icing on the cake. I raced to the bookstore yesterday to buy <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060920432/">Flow</a> and I can&rsquo;t wait to start absorbing.</p>
<p>There were so many great panels, I could go on and on. I left SXSW enlightened and humble. It was so great met new people and experience Austin. My only regret is not shedding my introverted coat, however, this was my first and hopefully next year I&rsquo;ll be more daring and approachable. Until then, I have a lot of homework.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Gooey Plastic</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/gooey-plastic/"/><published>2006-03-05T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/gooey-plastic/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>At what point does interactive design become temporal art over plastic art? This
question seems to be rare yet extremely important in our decision making process.
This (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060391685/">http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060391685/</a>) book prompted my pondering
of this.</p>
<p>To clarify, temporal art includes poetry, writing, film and music. Plastic art
takes the form of painting, drawing and sculpture. What sets the two apart is
that fourth dimension, time. The success of temporal art is in its progressive
events leading up to a fulfilling end, better known as climax. This all makes
sense, right? So how do we classify interactive art?</p>
<p>My guess is it&rsquo;s both, however, I&rsquo;m leaning toward temporal. Unfortunately a lot
of times we design with a plastic mindset when we should be thinking about a
climactic ending. Should we be treating sites like small stories? Grab peoples
attention, pull them in, building them up, then smack them with an unforgettable
message. Very few do this. The non-linear aspect of this medium complicates the
time quality of temporal art.</p>
<p>So what is interactive art? Still pondering this one.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Visualize Then Talk</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/visualize-then-talk/"/><published>2006-03-04T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/visualize-then-talk/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>One of my favorite quotes from the Godfather trillogy is when Michael Corleone
wisly reminds Vinnie, &ldquo;never let anyone know what you are thinking.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The importance of this is astronomical in client meetings. Never bring new ideas
to the table in a client meeting. Bring vetted ideas. Prepare yourself before
the meeting. Have concept sessions with colleagues, visualize the ideas, make
sure you have the resources and be sure the idea is possible. When it comes time
to present save a few in your back pocket just in case you need some amo.</p>
<p>If the client latches on to a &ldquo;new idea&rdquo; then you take the risk of have to
execute it. If you realize later that it&rsquo;s not possible or a weak idea, too
late. Concepting is your job not the clients. If you transfer this power their
understanding of their role will forever be jaded. This can cause a world of
pain for you and them.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Make It Better</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/make-it-better/"/><published>2006-02-27T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/make-it-better/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Bored tonight so I thought I&rsquo;d impregnate some coders out there with some of my
seed. My hopes are that this will cause you to give birth to better code. I am
pro choice so if you choose to abort I understand whole heartedly. Before you do
so please consider adoption, there are plenty of other good coders out there
that may benefit.</p>
<p>Ok, enough metaphors. This is some actionscript I did over Christmas (download
code (/code/flash_template.zip), see example (/code/flash_template/index.html)).
It&rsquo;s a flash framework for throwing together websites quickly. My main focus was
in and out transitions and the implementation of GDispatcher (<a href="http://www.gskinner.com/blog/archives/000027.html)">http://www.gskinner.com/blog/archives/000027.html)</a>.
Keep in mind this was a first attempt at trying to shoehorn MVC into flash. You
may notice a similar directory structure to Rails (<a href="http://www.rubyonrails.com">http://www.rubyonrails.com</a>),
thats just for my own sanity. I&rsquo;m working on a more refined version with a
clearer definition between Controllers and Views. I may post it for your
scrutiny later on.</p>
<p>Feedback is the purpose of this exercise. If it proves beneficial to me I&rsquo;ll
post more code. So SPEAK UP, I want to hear with you think, good or evil.</p>
<p><strong>UPDATE</strong> Looking back at this code, it&rsquo;s not as cool as I once thought. I&rsquo;ve
since re-factored it a lot so keep that in mind when you begin to judge. This
was my first attempt at using the Event Dispatch model so you might see some
spaghetti. However, it should be helpful to see how things are organized.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>