<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2006 on Nathan Borror</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/</link><description>Recent content in 2006 on Nathan Borror</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 09:31:04 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathan.run/posts/2006/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>So Many Chairs</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/so-many-chairs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2004 19:14:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/so-many-chairs/</guid><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en">&lt;![CDATA[<p>I want to talk about style. What does it really mean? How do you get it? Does it
really matter? I mainly just want to further my understanding of style by
writing down some thoughts and ideas.<strong>Warning! The following is
completely opinionated.</strong></p><h3 id="what-does-style-mean">What does style mean?</h3><p>It means you&rsquo;ve carved out a niche where you can be easily recognizable. People
seek you for your ability to look a particular way. Sort of like wearing Banana
Republic because you like smooth sleek colors and fabrics. Or eating Mexican
food for the spicy entrees.</p><h3 id="how-do-you-attain-style">How do you attain style?</h3><p>I don&rsquo;t really know. It&rsquo;s like saying how do you find love? Some say love finds
you, well, maybe style finds you. I would like to think this quest involves hard
work, research and dedication. However, I&rsquo;m sure that alone doesn&rsquo;t provide you
with a unique style. It&rsquo;s almost like pacing around a large room with many
different types of chairs. Some exotic looking, some very simplistic. Every now
and then you have a seat, paying close attention to how it feels, looks and
functions. Then you move to the next. Over time you learn about all the chairs
in the room and begin to build your very own where you can finally sit with
comfort and assurance. At least thats my guess.</p><h3 id="does-having-a-style-really-matter">Does having a style really matter?</h3><p>No, not really. In some instances it hinders you because your confining
yourself. If a company or firm is recognized for their style it can hinder them
more because they become known for that style in the industry and risk being
pushed to the curb. If you look at companies like<a href="http://www.sagmeister.com/">Sagmeister Inc.</a>,<a href="http://www.weworkforthem.com">Weworkforthem</a> and<a href="http://www.cyclone-design.com/">Cyclone Design</a> they are highly recognized by
their great styles. Eventually three more companies will come along with fresh
new styles that attract attention and they&rsquo;ll be flavor of the week. If you look
at companies like<a href="http://www.pentagram.com">Pentagram</a>,<a href="http://www.rga.com">R/GA</a> and<a href="http://www.hallmark.com">Hallmark</a> that have stood the
test of time; you&rsquo;ll see they don&rsquo;t really have a style. They have an eclectic
collection of designers that create solutions that evolve with time.</p><p>Personally I stay away from locking myself in a style. If it happens to find me
later on in life I&rsquo;ll probably be ok but at this point I&rsquo;m still testing out all
the chairs.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Wireless Revolution</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/wireless-revolution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2004 19:13:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/wireless-revolution/</guid><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en">&lt;![CDATA[<p>In my quest to eliminate wires I purchased the<a href="http://www.bluetooth.com/">Apple Bluetooth</a> Pro Mouse. It&rsquo;s a very charming piece of hardware.
I&rsquo;ve already gone through two of the regular Apple Pro mice. I have a tendency
of wrapping the cord around the mouse when I&rsquo;m &ldquo;on the go&rdquo; and eventually the
wire inside breaks. However they&rsquo;ve been good to me and so far I&rsquo;ve been very
pleased with the Bluetooth derivative. I&rsquo;ve noticed when I&rsquo;m transferring large
amounts of data over our<a href="http://www.warchalking.org/">WiFi</a> at<a href="http://www.neubix.com">work</a> the mouse becomes really jumpy. I guess this is too be
expected with a wireless device? Other than that it&rsquo;s performed wonderfully.</p><p>All thats left is bluetooth headphones (Apple please come out with some) and a
way to power my laptop cordlessly&hellip; (I can only dream).</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>The Reading Trail</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/the-reading-trail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2004 19:12:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/the-reading-trail/</guid><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en">&lt;![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ll be finishing up the Da Vinci Code tonight. Once thats over I&rsquo;m going to get
back on the learning train. Cutting back on entertainment television, movies and
other distractions. Time to get down to business.</p><p>I&rsquo;ve decided to sharpen my skills as an Information Architect. I&rsquo;ve always
enjoyed the organization of large amounts of data and felt like I was pretty
good at it. However, I feel there is much more to learn.</p><p>My first selection will be a classic, The Visual Display of Quantitative
Information by Edward R. Tufte. Scientific American describes it as, &ldquo;original,
beautifully presented, sharp and learned, this book is a work of art. The art
here is cognitive art, the graphic display of relations and empirical data, now
an indispensable tool of science and engineering.&rdquo;</p><p>I&rsquo;ll be sure to post a review when I&rsquo;m finished.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Monster</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/monster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2004 12:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/monster/</guid><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en">&lt;![CDATA[<p>This weekend I went to see Monster. I saw the preview and sort of knew what I was getting myself into. It wasn&rsquo;t going to be an uplifting movie but I could tell these people had something to say. Some parts were hard to digest and some really made me question how I treat and view other people. It&rsquo;s a movie that needs to be scene with an open mind and heart. Charlize Theron deserves high recognition for pouring her soul into this film.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Just Do It</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/just-do-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2004 12:55:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/just-do-it/</guid><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en">&lt;![CDATA[<p>One of my most influential<a href="http://art.smsu.edu/peophtm/kosto.htm">professors</a> from college would always say, &ldquo;Just do it!&rdquo; in his thick Bosnian accent during sketch critiques. I&rsquo;m not sure whether he was saying it before<a href="http://www.nikelab.com">Nike</a> but recently I&rsquo;ve been trying to &ldquo;just do it.&rdquo;</p><p>We all have these lists of things we want to do in life. Things we want to<a href="http://www.risd.edu">accomplish</a>,<a href="http://www.actionscript.org">practice</a>,<a href="http://www.propellerhead.se/">learn</a>,<a href="http://www.bugeurope.com/">experience</a>. We recall the list in our day dreams but loose sight of how easy it is to &ldquo;just do it.&rdquo; Then we come up with excuses and reasons why it&rsquo;s impossible to &ldquo;just do it&rdquo; or decide it&rsquo;s not the right time to &ldquo;just do it.&rdquo;</p><p>Recently I&rsquo;ve been trying to abolish some of my brick walls that prevent me to &ldquo;just do it.&rdquo; I started this weekend by purchasing a keyboard. I&rsquo;ve always wanted to experiment with playing and creating music. Once I get a MIDI converter for my laptop and pending I start to sound good :) I&rsquo;ll post some of my creations in the Lab.</p><p>Good luck with your wall demolition.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Soundtrack of Life</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2003/soundtrack-of-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2003 18:59:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2003/soundtrack-of-life/</guid><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en">&lt;![CDATA[<p>You may find this odd but have you ever consciously listened to a particular CD during a particular time of your life in hopes that the music will in some way encapsulate those memories?</p><p>When I was in New York last March I listened to The Postal Service over and over and now every time I listen to that CD I remember walking up and down broadway and roaming around the subways. Last month I listened to Death Cab for Cutie while<a href="http://www.neubix.com">we</a> were in Los Angeles and now the same thing happens. It&rsquo;s sort of the soundtrack of life.</p><p>Or perhaps I just have a fetish with Ben Gibbard?</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Cross-Processing Film</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2003/cross-processing-film/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2003 18:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2003/cross-processing-film/</guid><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en">&lt;![CDATA[<p>Today I got my first roll of cross-processed negative film produced by my new<a href="http://www.lomography.com">Lomo</a>. I&rsquo;m pretty impressed. It took me a while to find a place in town that would cross process negative film but a little mom and pop shop pulled through for me.</p><p>What is cross processing you ask? Well basically you use the opposite chemicals to develop the film. Normally negative film is processed with C-41 chemicals and slide film is processed with E6. If you use the opposite chemicals you get a very vintage effect. With the negative film, things become very blue and hazy. My next roll will be slide and from what I&rsquo;ve read slide film, when cross processed, creates more bold rich colors.</p><p>One of the secrets to cross processing is over-exposing the film by one stop. This can be easily done by changing the ASA. Example: If your using 200 ASA tell your camera you&rsquo;re using 100 ASA and this will allow for a touch of over exposure. You might even try experimenting with two stops.</p>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>