<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2006/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2006-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Nothing In Disguise</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/nothing-in-disguise/"/><published>2006-07-19T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/nothing-in-disguise/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>A few Sunday&rsquo;s back I was in a coffee house determined to work. Instead, I
quickly fell into a dream state which is the plague of many Sunday mornings. I
felt guilty about being so unproductive, but, I had no pressing deadlines, no
urgent emails, no clients knocking at my door. Later that night I felt a surge
of creativity and began painting, which got me wondering. Lets see what Brenda
Ueland (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1555972608/">http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1555972608/</a>) says:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Our idea that we must always be energetic and active is all wrong. Bernard
Shaw says that it is not true that Napoleon was always snapping out decisions
to a dozen secretaries and aides-de-camp, as we are told, but that he moodled
around for months. Of course he did. And that is why these smart, energetic,
do-it-now, pushing people so often say: &ldquo;I am not creative.&rdquo; They are, but
they should be idle, limp and alone for much of the time, as lazy as men
fishing on a levee, and quietly looking and thinking, not <em>willing</em> all the
time.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It&rsquo;s important to make time for nothing. It allows you to open your mind to
thought you might not normally invite in. In a way, these moments cultivate our
creative fields. When it&rsquo;s time to harvest, ideas should be ripe for the
pickings. Basically, the answers we arrive at are a result of past thought.
Neglect these moments and you limit the quality of creative outcomes.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Some 40 thousand (and counting) elementary schools have eliminated recess in
favor of more time for academics,&rdquo; says David Elkind (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0738210536/)">http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0738210536/)</a>.
This is shocking. From what I recall, recess was the most rejuvenating part of
my elementary day. &ldquo;Our schools are now contributing to the suppression of
curiosity, imagination and fantasy.&rdquo;</p>
<p>As we get older we unknowingly loose touch with our creative side and our
imagination. I remember looking at clouds and immediately spotting frogs, space
ships or elephants. Now I have to concentrate to come up with anything. Making
time for relaxing and dreaming is so important, if for no other reason than to
look up and see a giraffe float by.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Del.icio.us API Interface</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/del.icio.us-api-interface/"/><published>2006-07-17T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/del.icio.us-api-interface/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I finally figured out how to parse the Del.icio.us API (<a href="http://del.icio.us/help/api/">http://del.icio.us/help/api/</a>)
using Python and Django. The solution is quite flexible aside from the fact that
the Del.icio.us API is still under development.</p>
<p>I started by studying FlickrClient (<a href="http://micampe.it/things/flickrclient">http://micampe.it/things/flickrclient</a>) which
is a great interface for Python. The Flickr API is very verbose and this is a
simple approach that scales to future Flickr upgrades. The power behind this
script is the following method:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="color:#66d9ef">def</span> __getattr__(self, method):
  <span style="color:#66d9ef">def</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">method</span>(_self<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>self, _method<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>method, <span style="color:#f92672">**</span>params):
    _method <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> _method<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>replace(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;_&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;.&#34;</span>)
    url <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;http://flickr.com/services/rest/&#34;</span> <span style="color:#f92672">+</span> <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;?method=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">%s</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;amp;</span><span style="color:#e6db74">%s</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;amp;api_key=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">%s</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;</span> <span style="color:#f92672">%</span> (_method, urlencode(params), YOUR_API_KEY)
    <span style="color:#f92672">...</span>
</code></pre></div><p>This basically generates the proper URL string to be passed to Flickr. With this
bit of simplicity you can literally call any API method. All thats left is
parsing the return XML value which is done by XMLTramp (<a href="http://www.aaronsw.com/2002/xmltramp/)">http://www.aaronsw.com/2002/xmltramp/)</a>.
This will parse any XML data into a useful object that you can iterate through
in a Django template.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python">rsp <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> xmltramp<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>load(url)
</code></pre></div><p>I&rsquo;ve retooled this approach a bit to work with Del.ici.ous. The biggest
difference is instead of using an API Key you have to validate with Https. I
created a method to handle this using urllib2:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="color:#66d9ef">def</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">_secureConnect</span>(self, url):
  auth_handler <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> urllib2<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>HTTPBasicAuthHandler()
  auth_handler<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>add_password(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;del.icio.us API&#39;</span>, <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;https://api.del.icio.us&#39;</span>, USERNAME, PASSWORD)
  opener <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> urllib2<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>build_opener(auth_handler)
  urllib2<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>install_opener(opener)
  <span style="color:#66d9ef">return</span> urllib2<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>urlopen(url)<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>read()
</code></pre></div><p>The other big difference is all the data in the return XML resides in attributes
of a single node. (In my opinion this is crap but such is life.) We must create
a new object because Django templates don&rsquo;t seem to like how XMLTramp accesses
node attributes.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="color:#66d9ef">for</span> child <span style="color:#f92672">in</span> rsp:
  posts<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>append({<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;description&#39;</span>:child(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;description&#39;</span>), <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;href&#39;</span>:child(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;href&#39;</span>), <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;extended&#39;</span>:child(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;extended&#39;</span>), <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;hash&#39;</span>:child(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;hash&#39;</span>), <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;time&#39;</span>:child(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;time&#39;</span>), <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;tag&#39;</span>:child(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;tag&#39;</span>)})
  <span style="color:#66d9ef">return</span> posts
</code></pre></div><p>I&rsquo;m sure if I become better versed with urllib2 and Python I could make this
simpler. For now it works which was the intended goal. Here is the code
(<a href="http://media.youknowwhereyouare.com/code/DeliciousClient.zip)">http://media.youknowwhereyouare.com/code/DeliciousClient.zip)</a>. <em>Word of
caution!</em> It&rsquo;s good practice to save these results to a local database thereby
minimizing the API requests. Del.icio.us in particular will throttle back your
requests when it notices an increase in API traffic. My next post will address
this.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>A Bittersweet Farewell</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/a-bittersweet-farewell/"/><published>2006-07-13T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/a-bittersweet-farewell/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>You probably haven&rsquo;t noticed but the past month has been particularly
challenging for me. If you&rsquo;re a close friend then it was probably apparent in
the way I cheaply disguise my emotions. It&rsquo;s not easy to look back at two years
of progress in advertising and realize all along you may have stumbled into the
wrong cocktail party. Once this realization occurs it creeps into all your
thoughts and emotions to the point where you can no longer function until a
change is made.</p>
<p>I can finally say a change has been made. A weight has been lifted only to be
replaced by reluctant excitement. August will mark my departure from advertising.
I&rsquo;ve never felt comfortable in advertising and while I understand its purpose I
struggle with its effects. So in the midst of my search for a new direction I
discovered an opportunity to fill a void with an exciting group of individuals.</p>
<p>If your not familiar with the Kansas/Missouri area you may know them for their
origination of an exciting Python (<a href="http://www.python.org/">http://www.python.org/</a>) framework called
Django (<a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/)">http://www.djangoproject.com/)</a>. If your in the business of journalism
you may recognize them as pioneers of an online publishing tool, Ellington
(<a href="http://www.ellingtoncms.com/)">http://www.ellingtoncms.com/)</a>. Or if you&rsquo;re familiar with the area you can
identify them by their care of Lawrence.com (<a href="http://www.lawrence.com/)">http://www.lawrence.com/)</a>,
LJWorld.com (<a href="http://www.ljworld.com/)">http://www.ljworld.com/)</a>, and KUSports.com (<a href="http://www.kusports.com/)">http://www.kusports.com/)</a>.
They call themselves World Online and what better place to be with a name like
that than in the center of the country, Lawrence, Kansas.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll be doing the impossible task of filling the shoes of Wilson Miner
(<a href="http://www.wilsonminer.com/">http://www.wilsonminer.com/</a>) who has moved on to some small company
(<a href="http://www.apple.com/">http://www.apple.com/</a>) in California that makes a very ambitions music device :)
This was a very difficult decision because I&rsquo;ll be leaving a group of individuals
(<a href="http://www.brmethod.com/">http://www.brmethod.com/</a>) that I have an enormous amount of respect and
admiration for.</p>
<p>This insainly fast pace industry that we casually call The Web is actually a
very small community of extraordinary human beings. We&rsquo;re infected with
curiosity and rely heavily on one another for direction and friendship. I will
miss the Method team but I&rsquo;ll always be available to them as a friend and
colleague.</p>
<p>A page has been turned. It&rsquo;s blank and ready to be filled with a new chapter.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>It's Time To Behave</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/its-time-to-behave/"/><published>2006-07-10T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/its-time-to-behave/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>We are all hypocrites, every damn one of us. Well, actually, just those that are
guilty of inline javascript. Now don&rsquo;t get all puffed up, I&rsquo;m just as guilty but
it&rsquo;s time to change and I have some tips!</p>
<p>Over the past couple years we&rsquo;ve heard a lot about separation. Two types, in
particular, have been evangelized, data from structure and structure from style.
One we don&rsquo;t hear about nor see it practiced very often is separation between
structure and behavior. Why do some of us work so hard at protecting data,
structure and style while neglecting behavior?</p>
<p>For me it&rsquo;s laziness. After designing a site I spend a majority of my time
creating a solid structure then styling. By the time debugging is over I&rsquo;m so
beat, a little inline javascript never hurt anybody, right? Wrong! So how can
I/we change?</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m a firm believer if your slacking in something, it&rsquo;s probably because it&rsquo;s
not as fun as it could be. So in an effort to liven up javascript I&rsquo;ve decided
to investigate a framework called JQuery (<a href="http://www.jquery.com">http://www.jquery.com</a>). It&rsquo;s similar
to Prototype (<a href="http://prototype.conio.net/">http://prototype.conio.net/</a>) but not as bloated, it slides in at
a polite 10k when compressed and has a handsome toolset. The best part about it
is you find yourself unknowingly abstracting all your code. It&rsquo;s designed with
separation in mind and makes it fun to boot! It also supports XPath
(<a href="http://www.w3schools.com/xpath/">http://www.w3schools.com/xpath/</a>) which I haven&rsquo;t really dove into yet but I&rsquo;ve
been assured is quite amazing.  Aside from its core functionality its provides
some simple effects, ajax, and basic events.</p>
<p>So there you have it. We/I have no reason to neglect this important separation
of behavior.</p>
<p><em>UPDATE</em> Two great articles have surfaced on a similar topic:</p>
<ul>
<li>James Bennett: Django and AJAX (<a href="http://www.b-list.org/weblog/2006/07/02/django-and-ajax">http://www.b-list.org/weblog/2006/07/02/django-and-ajax</a>)</li>
<li>Jeremy Keith: Learning JavaScript (<a href="http://domscripting.com/blog/display/78">http://domscripting.com/blog/display/78</a>)</li>
</ul>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Seven Patriots</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/seven-patriots/"/><published>2006-07-04T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/seven-patriots/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>What better way to celebrate our independence than roaring into space in one of
the most complex machines ever built! You can watch this miraculous display of
human engineering at NASA.gov (<a href="http://www.nasa.gov/)">http://www.nasa.gov/)</a>.</p>
<p>Space exploration gives me goose bumps. My heart skips a beat when, just for one
second, I try to comprehend its limitless nature. To think we&rsquo;re able to
catapult seven of our greatest minds into this vacuum of questions and answers
makes me pause and wonder what we&rsquo;ll choose to achieve next. World peace,
hydrogen power, healthcare for everyone, or the tallest of dreams are so
attainable when we place them next to our accomplishments.</p>
<p>What I saw today was remarkable, there was no red or blue, no debate, just a
group of dedicated patriots. Our achievements should show us nothing less than
anything is possible if we clear our hearts, our minds and choose to step
forward. 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, is all it takes.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Django Gotchas</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/django-gotchas/"/><published>2006-06-30T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/django-gotchas/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>One of the biggest hurdles in learning any new framework or programming language
is learning its quirks. By quirks I don&rsquo;t mean bugs, I&rsquo;m referring to the
personality and flow. Here are a few that might help your troubleshooting process:</p>
<p>I get an error when I run syncdb. This could be a number of things. If its an
error in the model you should be able to tell. Most of the time for me was
forgetting to add the project to the <code>settings.py</code> INSTALLED_APPS
(<a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/documentation/settings/#installed-apps">http://www.djangoproject.com/documentation/settings/#installed-apps</a>) list.</p>
<p>I created a templatetag but Django is saying the file doesn&rsquo;t exist. First make
sure you have loaded the template tag
(<a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/documentation/templates_python/#extending-the-template-system)">http://www.djangoproject.com/documentation/templates_python/#extending-the-template-system)</a>,
(i.e. <code>{% load latestposts %}</code>). Second, and this one gets me every time, make
sure you added the <code>__init__.py</code> file to the newly created directory. This file
must be present in directories that contain python scripts.</p>
<p>How do I access the children of a many-to-one or many-to-many relationship within
the template? This puzzled me for a while. I&rsquo;m accustomed to saying
<code>post.categories</code> but in Django you must say <code>post.categories_set.all</code>. Referenced
here (<a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/documentation/db_api/#related-objects)">http://www.djangoproject.com/documentation/db_api/#related-objects)</a>.</p>
<p>I just added my database from my model but I keep getting a 404 error when I try
to view the template. This drove me crazy and people will probably laugh. If you
forget to enter data into the newly formed table Django will throw a Page Not
Found error until you enter your first record of data. It&rsquo;s always the small
things.</p>
<p>I hope these are somewhat helpful. If you have any to add to the list feel free
to post a comment.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>80x80</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/80x80/"/><published>2006-06-26T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/80x80/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I said Friday but I meant Monday. Sometimes things take longer but in my case I
just wanted to compete for attention the same day Digg 3 (<a href="http://www.digg.com">http://www.digg.com</a>)
launched. All amusement aside I&rsquo;d like to take the plastic wrap off my new site
that I&rsquo;ve dubbed 80x80.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s been a long time coming and I&rsquo;ve finally got something I&rsquo;m proud of. She&rsquo;s
still stretching herself out so if you notice any kinks let me know and I&rsquo;ll
call the masseuse. You&rsquo;ll see the <a href="/lab/">Lab</a> grow soon into a dumping ground
for prototypes and ideas. To keep things lively the artwork above will change as
frequently as possible. You may notice the death of my tags, sorry, I opted for
a clear set of categories. <a href="/projects/">Portfolio</a> is simple and should provide
a glimpse of my contributions. <a href="/resume/">Resume</a> is, well, a resume.</p>
<p>That said, I&rsquo;d like to say a few words on the nuts and bolts. I&rsquo;ve parted ways
with Rails (<a href="http://www.rubyonrails.com">http://www.rubyonrails.com</a>). I enjoy Ruby immensely, it&rsquo;s a
beautiful language and I highly recommend it for those of you building web apps.
However, while I wear many hats, none of them include web app developer. My
largest hat is information designer. I spoon feed content to people in a
stimulating fashion in hopes of planting a brand seed in their brain, thats all.
After a few weeks of tinkering around I realized Django (<a href="http://www.djangoproject.com">http://www.djangoproject.com</a>)
was my new muse. In less than a weekend I had a prototype for this site which
allowed me to focus directly on usability, design and content while eliminating
time towards an admin tool. Ruby on Rails made programming fun again but Django
liberated me from back-end development.</p>
<p>I would like to give a big thanks to Jeff Croft
(<a href="http://www2.jeffcroft.com/2006/jun/06/lost-theories-with-source-code/)">http://www2.jeffcroft.com/2006/jun/06/lost-theories-with-source-code/)</a>, Wilson
Miner (<a href="http://www.wilsonminer.com/posts/2006/may/10/are-you-generic/)">http://www.wilsonminer.com/posts/2006/may/10/are-you-generic/)</a>, and those
that maintain Django (<a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/documentation/faq/#who-s-behind-this">http://www.djangoproject.com/documentation/faq/#who-s-behind-this</a>)
for their glowing examples clear documentation. If you&rsquo;d like to learn more
there are a couple great videos by Adrian
(<a href="http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=2939556954580527226&amp;amp;q=snakes+and+rubies">http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=2939556954580527226&amp;amp;q=snakes+and+rubies</a>)
and Jacob (<a href="http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-70449010942275062&amp;amp;q=django">http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-70449010942275062&amp;amp;q=django</a>)
on Google. Thats all for now. I&rsquo;m excited and I hope everyone else is too.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Victory Out of Context</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/victory-out-of-context/"/><published>2006-05-27T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/victory-out-of-context/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <blockquote>
<p>President Bush says, just as the United States persevered and ultimately won
the Cold War against communism, America will emerge victorious in the war on
terror. &ndash; <a href="http://www.voanews.com/english/2006-05-27-voa17.cfm">http://www.voanews.com/english/2006-05-27-voa17.cfm</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>It&rsquo;s misleading and irresponsible to imply the possibility of victory over
terror. It is idealistically impossible to abolish a feeling. People will always
fear and at times that fear will escalate to terror. From the time we are born
we learn fear, it aids in our survival until the day we die. Our responsibility
is to not let fear overshadow happiness. If we choose to be free we must accept
the accompanying dangers.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Highlights</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/highlights/"/><published>2006-05-06T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/highlights/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;m notorious for highlighting. At home, I&rsquo;m surrounded by a rapidly growing
library. Some books have been read cover to cover, some cover to creamy center,
and some randomly picked through. But, I can confidently guarantee, each has
felt the screeching of my fat yellow Avery HI-LITER.</p>
<p>Why? Maybe it&rsquo;s an incessant urge to mark my territory or a worry that I&rsquo;ll
forget a phrase that made my grey matter jiggle. I&rsquo;m not exactly sure but when I
revisit books and read this highlighted material memories flood my mind. The
hard part is remembering what I&rsquo;ve highlighted and trying to make relations
between highlights.</p>
<p>To aid in this I&rsquo;ve put together a little application called Highlights
(<a href="http://highlights.youknowwhereyouare.com/)">http://highlights.youknowwhereyouare.com/)</a>. It&rsquo;s very basic and allows me to
keep a journal of all my readings and thoughts. This also serves as my book list
for those of you asking me what I&rsquo;ve been reading lately. Feel free to peruse
(<a href="http://highlights.youknowwhereyouare.com/)">http://highlights.youknowwhereyouare.com/)</a>. I&rsquo;m thinking about adding some
folksonomies (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Folksonomy">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Folksonomy</a>) to allow for better
relationships to form between entires. Seaching will be available soon. Any
suggestions are welcome with open arms.</p>
<p>Update: I&rsquo;ll be porting Highlights to Django very soon and adding some fun new
features. If you have any suggestions feel free to comment.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Subversion Love</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2006/subversion-love/"/><published>2006-04-30T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2006/subversion-love/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I have a new love (<a href="http://subversion.tigris.org">http://subversion.tigris.org</a>). For the past year I&rsquo;ve been
putting off this slightly important part of being a pragmatic programmer
(<a href="http://pragmaticprogrammer.com/ppbook/index.shtml)">http://pragmaticprogrammer.com/ppbook/index.shtml)</a>.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve heard the horror stories of CVS so I steered clear of it for this new
flavor of life saving loveliness. Gone are the days of, &ldquo;is this the newest
copy?&rdquo; Goodbye to unsettling feelings of cautiously dragging and dropping files
from one server to the next. From this day forth we&rsquo;ll use words like &ldquo;Commit&rdquo;
and &ldquo;Revert&rdquo; and &ldquo;Diff&rdquo; to name a few.</p>
<p>Dreamhost (<a href="http://www.dreamhost.com/panel/features.html#svn">http://www.dreamhost.com/panel/features.html#svn</a>) is my repository
of choice. They make it so simple. Set up a new project in the panel and away
you go. Mike Zornek of <a href="http://clickablebliss.com/">Clickable Bliss</a> has a very
straight forward screen-cast (<a href="http://clickablebliss.com/blog/2006/04/26/introduction_to_subversion_screencast/">http://clickablebliss.com/blog/2006/04/26/introduction_to_subversion_screencast/</a>)
on the subject. Normal breathing may now commence.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>