<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2003/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2003-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Soundtrack of Life</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2003/soundtrack-of-life/"/><published>2003-12-16T18:59:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2003/soundtrack-of-life/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>You may find this odd but have you ever consciously listened to a particular CD during a particular time of your life in hopes that the music will in some way encapsulate those memories?</p>
<p>When I was in New York last March I listened to The Postal Service over and over and now every time I listen to that CD I remember walking up and down broadway and roaming around the subways. Last month I listened to Death Cab for Cutie while <a href="http://www.neubix.com">we</a> were in Los Angeles and now the same thing happens. It&rsquo;s sort of the soundtrack of life.</p>
<p>Or perhaps I just have a fetish with Ben Gibbard?</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Cross-Processing Film</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2003/cross-processing-film/"/><published>2003-11-03T18:58:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2003/cross-processing-film/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Today I got my first roll of cross-processed negative film produced by my new <a href="http://www.lomography.com">Lomo</a>. I&rsquo;m pretty impressed. It took me a while to find a place in town that would cross process negative film but a little mom and pop shop pulled through for me.</p>
<p>What is cross processing you ask? Well basically you use the opposite chemicals to develop the film. Normally negative film is processed with C-41 chemicals and slide film is processed with E6. If you use the opposite chemicals you get a very vintage effect. With the negative film, things become very blue and hazy. My next roll will be slide and from what I&rsquo;ve read slide film, when cross processed, creates more bold rich colors.</p>
<p>One of the secrets to cross processing is over-exposing the film by one stop. This can be easily done by changing the ASA. Example: If your using 200 ASA tell your camera you&rsquo;re using 100 ASA and this will allow for a touch of over exposure. You might even try experimenting with two stops.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>