<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nathan Borror</title><link>https://nathan.run/</link><description>Recent content on Nathan Borror</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathan.run/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://nathan.run/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/about/</guid><description>Just a midwestern kid soaking up the greatest parts of California. If I&amp;rsquo;m not building something I&amp;rsquo;m probably on a trail with my partner or preparing for a very long run.
When I am building it&amp;rsquo;s probably with Go or Swift. I like Go because it&amp;rsquo;s very stable and backwards compatible, perfect for tools that don&amp;rsquo;t get touched for long periods of time. Swift because it&amp;rsquo;s not as boring as Go and I&amp;rsquo;m usually up for a challenge every summer when Apple decides to change everything.</description></item><item><title>Dropbox</title><link>https://nathan.run/work/dropbox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/work/dropbox/</guid><description>April 2014 – June 2015 Product Designer Shortly after I joined Dropbox, a small research and development team formed to investigate new products to compliment the main storage and syncing offering. I helped focus efforts around improving team communication between people using shared folders. We designed and prototyped a number of potential products, eventually launching an internal communication tool just before I left in 2015.
Mobile App We started off trying to figure out how to add chat and collaboration tools to the existing iOS app.</description></item><item><title>Facebook</title><link>https://nathan.run/work/facebook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/work/facebook/</guid><description>August 2018 – Present Product Design Director During my first couple years back I worked on projects that helped bring the Family more closer together. Now I&amp;rsquo;m helping imagine a future full of healthy regulation 🖖
February 2011 – April 2014 Product Designer &amp;amp; Product Design Manager Facebook was my first job at (what was still considered at the time) a startup. Before joining I was trying to quickly upgrade rural newspapers across the country to a more hopeful future from a basement in Kansas.</description></item><item><title>Interests</title><link>https://nathan.run/interests/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/interests/</guid><description>Running and Fastpacking A couple years ago I watched Courtney Dauwalter describe her experience running the Moab 240. It blew my mind and made me realize how complacent I&amp;rsquo;d become with running. Ever since I&amp;rsquo;ve been pushing harder — last year I ran a 50 mile race and hiked a 75 mile section of the PCT.
Born to Run — History lesson. North — Scott Jurek battles the Appalachian Trail.</description></item><item><title>Lawrence Journal-World</title><link>https://nathan.run/work/journal-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/work/journal-world/</guid><description>2006 – 2011 Generalist</description></item><item><title>Logger</title><link>https://nathan.run/tools/logger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/tools/logger/</guid><description>Logger lets you quickly send messages to yourself as a means of fast note taking. All messages you send to yourself show up chronologically. Tapping the spacebar before entering any text puts you in a search mode for easy filtering. Hashtags can be used to categorize notes. All data is stored on your device and not shared with the cloud. Download from the App Store
This was my first personal project to go into the App Store.</description></item><item><title>Places</title><link>https://nathan.run/places/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/places/</guid><description>In 1974 Georges Perec wrote a collection of observations as he sat in Saint-Sulpice Square in Paris. Rather than describing impressive or notable things such as the architecture, he aimed to describe the unnoticed, charting brief details of buses and people who pass. This is my fun attempt to observe 🧐
Blue Bottle on Fillmore, San Francisco It&amp;rsquo;s Wednesday, August 1, 2018 — 3:26 PM
An artist draws frantically before his scene vanishes</description></item><item><title>Play</title><link>https://nathan.run/tools/play/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/tools/play/</guid><description>How I built a Sonos replacement app in 2014 Back in 2014 in my spare time I built an app to replace the default Sonos app used to control multiple speakers in a home. It was a little challenging so I thought I’d share the process. You can check out most of the code on Github.
Finding the API First off I needed to understand how the existing app was communicating with speakers on the local network.</description></item><item><title>Podster</title><link>https://nathan.run/tools/podster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/tools/podster/</guid><description>My attempt at a very simple client-side RSS parser for podcasts after so much frustration with Apple&amp;rsquo;s Podcast app. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been working on this as much lately since Apple seems to have made some major strides but I still think I can get this to be faster using Go for all the feed fetching.</description></item><item><title>Public Studio</title><link>https://nathan.run/work/public-studio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/work/public-studio/</guid><description>June 2015 – August 2018 Generalist Public Studio was an opportunity to work with Aaron Sittig and Justin Shaffer to build new independent companies around sustainable ideas. I helped think through product ideas and build the initial implementations of the clients and services needed to grow the companies. Over three years we produced two companies:
Relay Relay was an attempt to build a modern version of the communities we experienced during the early days of the internet.</description></item><item><title>Readernaut</title><link>https://nathan.run/tools/readernaut/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/tools/readernaut/</guid><description>Readernaut is a social network for people who want to share what they&amp;rsquo;re reading. This has been a passion project since 2008. Register for a free account.
Currently working on an update that resurrects the activity feed and makes it a little more visually appealing.
Work in progress.</description></item><item><title>Steady</title><link>https://nathan.run/tools/steady/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:31:04 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/tools/steady/</guid><description>Steady is an experimental tool for tracking personal routines. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to come up with ways to incentivize and track more steady routines. Having a visualization that kind of encourages a streak seems to help me. Sorta stole this idea from Strava when I realized how much I tried to fill out their daily bar graph.
Current overall look of the app. Currently testing but should have something in the App Store this Spring 2021.</description></item><item><title>macOS Facebook</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2021/macos-facebook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2021/macos-facebook/</guid><description>Had some free time during a long mandatory training session at work and started perusing Apple&amp;rsquo;s macOS Sketch file with all the components that go into making a desktop app. I love imagining how components come together to form something useful 🤓
The training session I was enduring had minimum time limits. For someone who reads fast and watches video at 2x I decided it would be fun to throw together a desktop version of Facebook between modules — the most BORING version possible with nothing fancy, just standard macOS components.</description></item><item><title>Running Cone Peak Trails</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2019/running-cone-peak-trails/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2019/running-cone-peak-trails/</guid><description>Vincente Flat Trail → Cone Peak Rd → Cone Peak Trail ◭ Cone Peak Trail → Cone Peak Rd → Vincente Flat Trail
Last Sunday I packed up all my running gear for another long and steep trail run. Nate recently acquired an old van from the 90s that would be our ride to Big Sur. Old vehicles kinda put me on edge but this one felt oddly familiar because growing up at Lake of the Ozarks we had a van like this so all kinds of memories were lighting up.</description></item><item><title>Running Muir Woods Trails</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2019/running-muir-woods-trails/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2019/running-muir-woods-trails/</guid><description>Dipsea → Sun Trail → Redwood Trail → Panoramic Trail → Ocean View Trail → Matt Davis Trail → Old Mine Trail → Coastal Trail → Redwood Creek Trail → Ben Johnson Trail → Hillside Trail → Dipsea
Woke up around 5AM yesterday anxious to get on the trail. After some morning prep I walked outside to my car and immediately felt the cold air. Almost nine years of Northern California has decimated my resolve towards cold temperatures and there&amp;rsquo;s only one way to warm up this morning!</description></item><item><title>Blind spots</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2015/blind-spots/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2015/blind-spots/</guid><description>Hours of my youth were lost to a game called Age of Empires. This game was crack cocaine for kids and should have been illegal in some states. Each new game plopped you in the middle of nowhere with an axe, a small hut and a goat or pig nearby. You could only see the little parcel of land around you, everything else was pitch black. As you wandered around the world revealed itself.</description></item><item><title>Self-Driving Vagabonds</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2015/self-driving-vagabonds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2015/self-driving-vagabonds/</guid><description>14 February 2015 — Self-driving cars are going to change the world — not many folks will disagree. It’s beginning to feel like our space race, the next leap towards a more efficient future. Google’s got prototypes, Mercedes-Benz and Volvo have adaptive cruise control, Tesla almost has autopilot and Apple’s leaking.
Great, but these are baby steps when it comes to experience. Of course, solving the intelligence bit is really hard but the way we experience this future is where we’re gonna need to decide what type of world we want to live in.</description></item><item><title>Imitation as a Tool</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2014/imitation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2014/imitation/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Imitation is the sincerest form of flattery.&amp;rdquo; We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard this, it&amp;rsquo;s how the level headed react to “copycats” or &amp;ldquo;ripoffs.&amp;rdquo; The truth is imitation is natural. We may not like to admit it but we&amp;rsquo;re all skilled imitators. Without it there would be no way to talk with one another or possess similar value systems.
There&amp;rsquo;s a famous chapter in Richard Dawkin&amp;rsquo;s The Selfish Gene where he coins the term &amp;lsquo;meme&amp;rsquo; to explain a non-biological form of evolution — an evolution of culture from one &amp;lsquo;survival machine&amp;rsquo; to another.</description></item><item><title>My experience learning iOS</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2013/learning-ios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2013/learning-ios/</guid><description>Twice while living in Kansas I attempted to learn Objective-C and Cocoa. Getting past the first few chapters was pretty mind numbing. It didn’t really have anything to do with the difficulty curve. I already knew other languages—Python, Javascript—and didn’t really have a reason to learn something else.
The third time I tried was early 2012 when I started reading iOS Programming. This time I needed a project or I’d fail yet again.</description></item><item><title>Obsolescence</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2013/obsolescence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2013/obsolescence/</guid><description>We’ve witnessed a lot of products in our lifetimes. Some have faded away without even realizing it. Products like fax machines, AOL, desktop computers, atlases, home telephones. Sure, some of us still use these but they’ve all been replaced with better alternatives.
The best companies and people are capable of predicting when these shifts happen — some even have the capacity to obsolesce their own products. They understand if they don’t, someone else will.</description></item><item><title>State Machine</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2013/solvable-problems/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2013/solvable-problems/</guid><description>Last year Philips introduced Hue, a dead simple way to automate all your home lighting. After living with it for a few months and buying into Sonos — a wireless multi-room audio setup—I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to realize how accessible home automation is becoming. They&amp;rsquo;ve both forgotten one thing though, automation.
Automation is the use of machines, control systems and information technologies to optimize productivity in the production of goods and delivery of services.</description></item><item><title>Today</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2013/today/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2013/today/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never been fond of arbitrary markers in time. Holidays, birthdays, anniversaries, they all seem odd to me and I&amp;rsquo;ve never been one to celebrate them. Every day should be special and accomplishments, small and large should be relished, not random days.
As you would correctly suspect I don&amp;rsquo;t do resolutions. But I do think constantly about a question Buckminster Fuller used to ask his grandson, &amp;ldquo;What is the most important thing we could be thinking about today?</description></item><item><title>Ghetto Facebook Registration with Django</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/facebook-registration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/facebook-registration/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to quickly walk you through how to build a server-side Facebook registration flow with Django. This is really basic and doesn&amp;rsquo;t rely on special libraries aside from httplib2 and urlib which are pretty standard.
First you need to create an app. I set my App Domain to localhost and Site URL to http://localhost:8000 for development purposes. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably need to do the same if you&amp;rsquo;re using Django&amp;rsquo;s built in development server.</description></item><item><title>Setting up Apple Push Notifications</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/push/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/push/</guid><description>While trying to figure this out I came across a great article by Matthijs Hollemans. I suggest following it if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in an in-depth tutorial. What follows is a more concise version of that article and instead of using PHP I&amp;rsquo;m using a variant of Jacky Tsoi&amp;rsquo;s Python script. This is pretty tedious and there are a lot of steps you have to get right in order for this to work properly so hang in there.</description></item><item><title>Sending Multipart Forms with Objective-C</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/objc-multipart-forms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/objc-multipart-forms/</guid><description>It took me a few evenings to figure this out so I&amp;rsquo;m writing a quick explanation based on what I&amp;rsquo;ve found to work. My use-case is pretty simple, I want to POST some data to a form on a server from an iOS app I&amp;rsquo;m building. I&amp;rsquo;ll be using NSURLRequest to build the request object and NSURLConnection to make the actual connection to the server.
The first thing we need to understand is how Multipart Form requests should be structured.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with MQTT</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/mqtt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/mqtt/</guid><description>I wanted to play around with MQTT this evening so I put together a little tutorial on how to get started using Ubuntu and Mosquitto (http://mosquitto.org).
Installing Mosquitto Enter the following into your terminal. Remember to replace YOUR_UBUNTU_VERSION_HERE with the version of ubuntu you&amp;rsquo;re using, I was using Maverick Meerkat at the time so I replaced it with just maverick. First add the following two lines to /etc/apt/sources.list
deb http://ppa.launchpad.net/mosquitto-dev/mosquitto-ppa/ubuntu YOUR_UBUNTU_VERSION_HERE main deb-src http://ppa.</description></item><item><title>Simple Panic</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/simple-panic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/simple-panic/</guid><description>Today I posted a public photo of how nicely done a bank start-up&amp;rsquo;s packaging was and didn&amp;rsquo;t realize my card number was in plain view. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty rational individual so I did what everyone else would have done which is call the customer service number on the back of the card. Apparently they have Sundays off so I had to leave two anxious messages on their answering machine.</description></item><item><title>Adams and Jefferson</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/adams-jefferson/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/adams-jefferson/</guid><description>One hundred and eighty six years ago both Thomas Jefferson and John Adams passed away on this day, exactly fifty years after the adoption of the Declaration of Independence.
It’s hard to ignore the coincidence of this timing.
A couple summers back I bought an old book containing a eulogy given by Daniel Webster in August of 1826—I think this sums it up nicely:
No two men now live, fellow-citizens, perhaps it may be doubted whether any two men have ever lived in one age, who, more than those we now commemorate, have impressed on mankind their own sentiments in regard to politics and government, infused their own opinions more deeply into the opinions of others, or given a more lasting direction to the current of human thought.</description></item><item><title>A private afterlife</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/private-afterlife/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2012/private-afterlife/</guid><description>I spent a while last weekend thinking about death and privacy—for no particular reason aside from taking notice of a couple books I own:
The Adams Jefferson Letters Jack Kerouac and Allen Ginsberg: The Letters Rub Out the Words: The Letters of William S. Burroughs There are countless collections of correspondence floating around from a time when an envelope was considered a form of privacy. In many cases privacy died with the individual.</description></item><item><title>Less is more</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/less-more/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/less-more/</guid><description>Hopefully you read my previous post ../sass-isnt-me about Sass and CSS preprocessors and felt my angst toward learning a new syntax. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using LessCSS for about a week and I&amp;rsquo;m really impressed. For starters, no new syntax to learn. This is simply an augmentation of existing CSS syntax. You get mixins, nested rules, and most importantly, variables. You also get operations but I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to find them that useful. Here&amp;rsquo;s my critique:</description></item><item><title>Sass isn't for me</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/sass-isnt-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/sass-isnt-me/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been window shopping the CSS preprocessor world the last week or so. Sass seems to be everyone&amp;rsquo;s new bicycle but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t won me over and here&amp;rsquo;s why:
It&amp;rsquo;s a new syntax that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to learn or support. I have an awesome job where we often hire new people and (hopefully) acquire new clients and the last thing I want is the added friction of having to teach (and sell) a new styling syntax.</description></item><item><title>Curiosity rewarded the cat</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/curiosity-rewarded-cat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/curiosity-rewarded-cat/</guid><description>Good user experience is often found in the most unassuming places. We have a new restaurant opening in my neighborhood this week and I&amp;rsquo;ve been anticipating their arrival for a few weeks now. They officially open today but two days ago revealed a very important lesson in user experience.
Two days ago I was walking down the street this new restaurant is on to get lunch from a neighboring location. The lights were on and it looked like people were ordering and eating inside before their scheduled opening.</description></item><item><title>Interface harmony</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/interface-harmony/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/interface-harmony/</guid><description>Interface consistency is one of those things that, if done correctly, should go unnoticed. I&amp;rsquo;ve slowly been working on a new interface for a side project and thought it&amp;rsquo;d be a treat to share my approach.
Interfaces evolve based on the needs of people using them. Each task may require a different element. Common elements include buttons, dialogs, drop-downs, select boxes, checkboxes, input fields, etc. These elements are like notes in a composition seeking harmony.</description></item><item><title>Save RAM with mobile middleware</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/save-ram-mobile-middleware/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/save-ram-mobile-middleware/</guid><description>A while back I wrote an article on how to set up a mobile site with Django ../going-mobile. Currently I have a Slicehost account which includes 256MB of RAM. My resources are tight and I really dislike having another set of unnecessary Apache processes for a mobile site that, aside from different templates, is using the same code base. The solution is quite simple, write a middleware.
The following code checks the incoming request for &amp;rsquo;m' or &amp;lsquo;mobile&amp;rsquo; in the domain name.</description></item><item><title>Working with Python and RabbitMQ</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/working-django-and-rabbitmq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2009 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/working-django-and-rabbitmq/</guid><description>I recently installed RabbitMQ to handle some message queuing needs at Readernaut and thought I&amp;rsquo;d share how everything came together. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn more about RabbitMQ please read this.
To use RabbitMQ with python you need py-amqplib because Rabbit uses the AMQP standard. To make amqplib a little easier to use I needed a simple script that did three things:
Easy way to connect to RabbitMQ. Easy way to pull stuff out of the queue.</description></item><item><title>Capturing content in Django templates</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/capturing-content-django-templates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2009 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2009/capturing-content-django-templates/</guid><description>As a template designer there are times when you have structural code surrounding a block which is waiting on content from a child template. It may look something like:
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;content_title&amp;#34;&amp;gt; {% block content_title %}{% endblock %} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; Sometimes this block is never filled so ideally I want the DIV element in this case gone. This isn&amp;rsquo;t easy because there&amp;rsquo;s no way to know whether content is headed towards the block so one solution that I&amp;rsquo;ve used is:</description></item><item><title>What's next</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/whats-next/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/whats-next/</guid><description>Does it make sense to reinvent the wheel every time we start a new project? No. My work echoes my past and I stand by it. Some say, &amp;ldquo;that looks like Readernaut&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;that looks like Playground Blues&amp;rdquo; and I say yes, they are me.
If it worked there it will work here. When a problem is solved I move on because each project has its fair amount of new problems and I&amp;rsquo;d rather spend time on new, more interesting problems.</description></item><item><title>Message Queuing imports</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/message-queuing-imports/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/message-queuing-imports/</guid><description>Last week I ran into some problems dealing with large book imports on Readernaut. I tested the system for around 50-100 books but had no idea people would upload lists of 900+ books. This begged the question, how do you handle importing very large sets of data before the browser times out?
Brief example User uploads a list of 1000 ISBNs to be imported into their library. Each book, if not already in the system, needs to be imported via another service like Amazon.</description></item><item><title>Creating a basic API with Django</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/creating-basic-api-django/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/creating-basic-api-django/</guid><description>Creating a simple public API for your site is a lot easier than you may think with Django. You&amp;rsquo;re basically just creating another view and serving it as XML or JSON instead of HTML.
What&amp;rsquo;s public? Decide what you want to be public. The best answer is the stuff you&amp;rsquo;re already displaying in your HTML templates. Then you need to create an entry in your url conf.
url(r&amp;#39;^api/v1/(?P&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;[-\w]+)/notes/?$&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;readernaut.api.views.user_notes&amp;#39;), Create the view In the case for Readernaut I wanted to provide an XML feed for users notes.</description></item><item><title>Capistrano rules</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/capistrano-rules/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2008 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/capistrano-rules/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve grown tired of committing changes to my subversion repository, logging into my server, updating my live checkout, and restarting python processes. I finally decided to implement Capistrano and eliminate this repetition.
Here are my repetitive set of commands:
$ ssh playgroundblues.com $ cd ~/projects/playgroundblues $ svn up $ cd ~/www/playgroundblues.com/www $ touch django.fcgi Now, with the help of Capistrano, I just type:
$ cap deploy You&amp;rsquo;ll first need to install Capistrano which is as simple as gem install -y capistrano.</description></item><item><title>Aspen Simulator</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/aspen-simulator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2008 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/aspen-simulator/</guid><description>As much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to blog about my trip to Austin and SXSW last week I&amp;rsquo;m just too excited over the iPhone SDK goodies that dropped last Thursday.
You may be asking yourself, &amp;ldquo;he&amp;rsquo;s a web guy, why does he care?&amp;rdquo; Well, there happens to be a beautiful gem tucked away called the Aspen Simulator.
This is a complete pixel and functionally perfect replica of the iPhone and it&amp;rsquo;s fantastic for testing web apps.</description></item><item><title>Ah-ha Event Delegation</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/ah-ha-event-delegation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/ah-ha-event-delegation/</guid><description>Wrapping my head around things like OOP took months. It&amp;rsquo;s not because I&amp;rsquo;m an idiot (I don&amp;rsquo;t think) - it&amp;rsquo;s just because I needed all the explanations to marinate before having an ah-ha! moment.
I had an ah-ha today, with regards to Event Delegation. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seemed to completely understand events, yet I use them all the time. They&amp;rsquo;re an essential aspect of Actionscript and Javascript and there are two basic ways of capturing events, Event Handling and Event Delegation.</description></item><item><title>Gadget fast</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/gadget-fast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2008 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/gadget-fast/</guid><description>My iPhone and laptop will be unplugged starting Friday evening for two days. I&amp;rsquo;ve let the fog of distractions generated by these two devices grow too thick so for the next few days they&amp;rsquo;ll be turned off.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there. The following week Twitter, Flickr, an my feed reader will be muted. I have nothing against these services, but it&amp;rsquo;s time to step back and take the pulse of things around me and see if I&amp;rsquo;m missing something.</description></item><item><title>Going mobile</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/going-mobile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/going-mobile/</guid><description>Over the weekend, I decided to whip up a mobile (iPhone) version of Playground Blues. I walked into Broadway Cafe around 3pm on Saturday, and by 5:30, I had m.playgroundblues.com. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it went down.
Step 1 Since I&amp;rsquo;m still using Dreamhost and FastCGI, I created my .htaccess file along with my dispatch.fcgi file for my new sub-domain as usual. Made one little change to my dispatch file: instead of having DJANGO_SETTINGS_MODULE pointing to playgroundblues.</description></item><item><title>iPhone bookmark iconage</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/iphone-bookmark-iconage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2008/iphone-bookmark-iconage/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering how to control the icon that gets generated for your webpage with the new 1.1.3 iPhone release, look no further than Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone Dev Center.
Apple has added a section called &amp;ldquo;Create a WebClip Bookmark Icon&amp;rdquo; and it calls for a 57x57 pixel icon. After some testing today I&amp;rsquo;ve concluded this recommended sizing results in a fuzzy icon, largely due to the iPhone being a 163 ppi display.</description></item><item><title>Flash, meet H.264</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/flash-meet-h264/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/flash-meet-h264/</guid><description>Adobe just released Update 3 of Flash Player 9. This is HUGE. Streaming video is no longer a laughing matter. Streaming High Definition video will become common place and it starts today.
Everyone talks about BlueRay and HD-DVD, but what they don&amp;rsquo;t realize is they&amp;rsquo;ve already been obsolesced before catching stride. VHS is dead, brick and mortar video rental is on life support, and DVD just checked in with chest pains.</description></item><item><title>Django Basic Apps</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/django-basic-apps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/django-basic-apps/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on abstracting some Django applications from past projects so they can effortlessly be plugged into future projects. I hate writing the same blog application repeatedly, so this is an attempt to make life easier. I think this will be a fun, little suite of plug-n-play Django apps that everyone can benefit from.
I&amp;rsquo;m calling this suite Basic Apps with the hopes they&amp;rsquo;ll live up to their name. They&amp;rsquo;re freely distributed under the New BSD License and hosted at Google Code.</description></item><item><title>Django Sprint</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/django-sprint/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/django-sprint/</guid><description>Armed with high levels of legally addictive stimulants, silver laptops, and brilliant minds, Django will get even closer to 1.0 today. If you have any interest in being apart of today&amp;rsquo;s event, scurry over to the Django site and scan for tickets that catch your eye and expertise. Join us in IRC (irc.freenode.net) in the #django-sprint room or if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough to live near Lawrence, Kansas come join us!</description></item><item><title>Juggling Django settings modules</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/juggling-django-settings-modules/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/juggling-django-settings-modules/</guid><description>If you find yourself juggling multiple Django projects and constantly changing the DJANGO_SETTINGS_MODULE variable, try this simple shortcut.
Upon diving into a particular project I define an alias in my .bash_profile that gets me to the project directory in as few keystrokes as possible. For example, to get to my playgroundblues directory I simply type &amp;lsquo;pb&amp;rsquo; and I&amp;rsquo;m in the root of playgroundblues.com. Here is the line of code in my .</description></item><item><title>Care to scrum?</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/care-scrum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/care-scrum/</guid><description>We need more scrums and less meetings. A scrum (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stand-up_meeting) is a 5-10 minute stand-up meeting. About 80% of the meetings I&amp;rsquo;ve ever attended have included at least five people. Any meeting over three becomes a presentation while one bloviates and others wander.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last scrum. It included seven people, complete participation, no dominance, one referee, and was contained within a 10 minute package. Rather than walking away in a typical post-meeting cloud of confusion, I left the scrum feeling clear and informed.</description></item><item><title>Trials of the I-70 commute</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/trials-i-70-commute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/trials-i-70-commute/</guid><description>A while ago I began working back in the big city while remaining in modest Lawrence. This required a 40 min. x 2 drive into the sun five days a week. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t so bad at first, but the race through traffic and mass of incandescent gas started taking its toll.
I decided to evaluate what was wearing me out. The sun, for one, was melting my retinas and giving me headaches.</description></item><item><title>Subliminal Culture</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/subliminal-culture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/subliminal-culture/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading more of Lev Manovich&amp;rsquo;s (http://www.manovich.com) Language of New Media. Manovich discusses the methods in which we access new media. He mentions some research done by Paul Virilio on the collapsing effect technology has on the distances between people and content. Before, if a person wanted to see the works of Da Vinci they&amp;rsquo;d have to travel to a book store or an art museum. With the advent of new media it&amp;rsquo;s as simple as pulling up a browser.</description></item><item><title>Manually Compressing PNGs</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/manually-compressing-pngs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/manually-compressing-pngs/</guid><description>With the advent of some very clean hacks to make PNGs work in IE I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself working them into my designs more. Using them has allowed me to achieve some effects that were next to impossible with JPEGs and GIFs. The biggest hurdle in using PNGs is their file size. The export tools in Photoshop tie your hands behind your back, not allowing you to tweak anything that may lead to a more compact file.</description></item><item><title>iPhone dead; $30 rental?</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/iphone-dead-30-rental/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/iphone-dead-30-rental/</guid><description>This morning I woke up on my own. Normally I hear little crickets chirping around 7am which is my iPhone letting me know it&amp;rsquo;s time to face the coming day. This morning, no crickets. At first I thought maybe the battery was flat, but that&amp;rsquo;s not possible. I charged it the day before and didn&amp;rsquo;t put it through any rigorous usage. So iPhone CPR commences.
First I try a hard restart, holding down the home and on/off button for a few seconds.</description></item><item><title>Blueprints are not final</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/blueprints-are-not-final/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/blueprints-are-not-final/</guid><description>So apparently a little framework called Blueprint (http://bjorkoy.com/blueprint) has reared it&amp;rsquo;s head, born from a few stylesheets that look very familiar. I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat conflicted with its release because I don&amp;rsquo;t think it should be used. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s great, but don&amp;rsquo;t use it.
About five or so months ago I was working on the Journal-World (http://www.ljworld.com) redesign. News sites tend to be very column heavy and I was getting tired of writing the same code over and over to accommodate for my design iterations.</description></item><item><title>First impressions</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/first-impressions/</guid><description>How does a machine have soul? We could try and answer by throwing around terms like usefulness, elegance and grace but all our attempts would sound prosaic next to the device I recently became acquainted with. Run and hide Crackberry, the iPhone is here.
For people to be drooling over a 4.8 ounce device is not unfathomable especially coming from Apple. This is different. During my first hours with the iPhone I literally felt nervous.</description></item><item><title>The waves of creativity</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/waves-creativity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/waves-creativity/</guid><description>There are a lot of environmental factors that go into fostering a creative environment. As creative persons mature, we become more in-tune with what works best for us when it&amp;rsquo;s time to dream up new ideas and solutions. Some of us trek to coffeehouses while others listen to Bach, Satie or Mogwai. Whatever we do we&amp;rsquo;re all essentially trying to achieve a certain state of mind.
Before I go any further here is a quick explanation of the human brain by neuronal scientist, Richard Restak (/people/richard-m-restak/):</description></item><item><title>Transmedia newspapers</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/transmedia-newspapers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/transmedia-newspapers/</guid><description>I just finished reading chapter three of Convergence Culture (/library/books/convergence-culture/) where Jenkins discusses transmedia storytelling. He focuses on the Matrix franchise and how it basically rewrote the rules for Hollywoods future. It got me thinking on my walk home from the coffeehouse, why aren&amp;rsquo;t newspapers doing this?
We&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with the Matrix and have varying depths of involvement with it. Most of us have seen the first film, some the second and third but have any of us played the video game, or seen the Animatrix, or been to Matrix Online (http://www.</description></item><item><title>LJWorld redesign</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/ljworld-redesign/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/ljworld-redesign/</guid><description>So for the past five months or so we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a redesign for the Lawrence Journal-World. For those of you that don&amp;rsquo;t know, it&amp;rsquo;s a daily newspaper that circulates the town of Lawrence, Kansas. It&amp;rsquo;s quite small compared to surrounding markets which makes it very agile and free from shareholders and their evil agendas.
I had a feeling this project would be special and challenging but I had no idea of the scale.</description></item><item><title>Javascript Flash round 2</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/javascript-flash-round-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/javascript-flash-round-2/</guid><description>FIguring out the Javascript/Flash integration kit has lead to a much simpler solution. Looks like Macromedia has slipped in another nugget of usefulness in the Flash 8 release which, I might add, has penetrated the market remarkably fast. It&amp;rsquo;s called External Interface. I gotta thank Bobby for finding this one.
So forget the last post if you&amp;rsquo;re a progressive designer like myself, marching to the Flash 8 bugle. Using the same example as before replace your Actionscript with the following.</description></item><item><title>InspectDB to the rescue</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/inspectdb-rescue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/inspectdb-rescue/</guid><description>In a past life I used to build admin tools using Ruby on Rails. I thoroughly enjoyed spending weekends improving my little tools and libraries but I eventually realized I was spending more time on back-end stuff than front-end. Enter Django. For the past nine months I&amp;rsquo;ve touched nothing but Django so you can imagine how easy it was for me to hop on the Rails bicycle when Dreamhost decided to upgrade Rails.</description></item><item><title>Bringing back the personal</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/bringing-back-personal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/bringing-back-personal/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard wisperings about the death of blogs lately. More and more we see our favorite writters fading into the ether. This begs the question, what next? What do we do with the barren ghost towns that once thrived on eager readers making sure their cache was cleared before stalking their favorites.
Personal sites should be cornucopias which chronicle our lives. They should be open sketchbooks crammed with a maze of twists and turns.</description></item><item><title>Making old content new</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/making-old-content-new-black/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/making-old-content-new-black/</guid><description>Why does old content have to fade so quickly? Blogs, zines, news articles all suffer from &amp;ldquo;out with the old, in with the new&amp;rdquo; mentality. There is a lot of old content that retains relevancy far beyond its publish date. The problem is, how do we resurrect it?
Simple, stats tracking. Amazon solved this problem a long time ago. They meticulously track peoples browsing and buying habits and offer up recommendations based on trends.</description></item><item><title>Make Flash and Javascript Sing</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/make-flash-and-javascript-sing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/make-flash-and-javascript-sing/</guid><description>Yes its true. You can make Javascript and Flash play together! Way back in 2005 the company formerly known as Macromedia threw together a nice little kit to make these two languages play nicely. Here&amp;rsquo;s how.
First we need to secure some crutial files. The first is a SWF called JavaScriptFlashGateway.swf which allows us to setup a &amp;ldquo;proxy&amp;rdquo; between our Flash and Javascript. Second, make sure you link up JavaScriptFlashGateway.js. Third, put JavaScriptSerializer.</description></item><item><title>Not so convergent</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/not-so-convergant/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/not-so-convergant/</guid><description>Talking about &amp;ldquo;convergence&amp;rdquo; is like talking about &amp;ldquo;the war on terror.&amp;rdquo; They&amp;rsquo;re two incredibly broad terms with unforeseeable outcomes. Convergence has been vogue for a while and I&amp;rsquo;m a little skeptical about its usage to describe media convergence. At this years SXSW, for the first time, someone summed up what I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to understand.
When I think of convergence I do so in terms of the classic media outlets converging with the Internet.</description></item><item><title>Austin bound</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/austin-bound/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/austin-bound/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m headed to Austin, Texas today to partake in the South by Southwest festivities. The panel linup this year looks scrumptious. Unlike my pal Jeff (http://www2.jeffcroft.com/blog/2007/mar/01/where-find-me-sxsw/), I have no idea what I&amp;rsquo;ll be attending. I will, however, be attending as many evening parties as I can possibly stumble into. I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely be attending the AMODA (http://www.amoda.org/) Digital Showcase, which was fantastic last year, and the Austin On Rails Happy Hour sporting my Django (http://www.</description></item><item><title>Rating system breakdown</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/rating-system-breakdown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/rating-system-breakdown/</guid><description>I wanna discuss rating systems for a bit. From what I gather there are three flavors: a simple &amp;ldquo;one vote&amp;rdquo; method, a thumbs up or down, and the scale. Each solutions goal is to find out what people think of your content. This is helpful when trying to understand your audience.
The &amp;ldquo;one vote&amp;rdquo; method As simple as it gets. If someone likes a piece of content they simply click a button saying so.</description></item><item><title>Playground is back</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/playground-back/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/playground-back/</guid><description>With every rendition of my person site I must emphasize that this is a work in progress. With that said, welcome to my new playground. Sorry about the neurotic name changes. I can assure you they are over and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty darn happy with the new digs.
Why redesign? I wanted to return to my roots. I started out as Playground Blues and this is where I belong. I also wanted something with room to grow.</description></item><item><title>Easing into Leopard</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/easing-leopard/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2007/easing-leopard/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a UI geek and the first thing I noticed during the iPhone demo was how fun scrolling seems. With small devices and even regular sized computers a majority of our time is spent scrolling various collections of content. Only a company like Apple can step back, recognize this, and make it fun. This will no doubt engage users, bringing them closer to flow.
Easing has been around a long time.</description></item><item><title>A look back</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/look-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/look-back/</guid><description>Two thousand six was full of spontaneous moments with great friends and coworkers. It also had some noteworthy, personal milestones that I thought I&amp;rsquo;d highlight before the clock strikes twelve.
January / February saw the launch of Authentic Films (http://www.authenticfilms.net). It was my first official jump into the world of Actionscript and thanks to Travis (http://www.podlob.com) the water wasn&amp;rsquo;t that cold.
March / April involved traveling to Austin, Texas where I attended my first SXSW conference (http://flickr.</description></item><item><title>RIP Print</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/rip-print/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/rip-print/</guid><description>Print is about to die and we better prepare ourselves. I was doing some christmas shopping last week and stumbled into a Sony Style story. I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of the Sony brand but they do seem to come out with some daring devices. The first thing that struck me was the Sony Reader (http://www.learningcenter.sony.us/assets/itpd/reader/).
The Sony Reader is basically a very thin screen that uses E-Ink technology (http://eink.com/) to display text and basic graphics.</description></item><item><title>I don't like</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/i-dont/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/i-dont/</guid><description>For as long as I can remember I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently heard various permutations of two phrases, &amp;ldquo;I like&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t like.&amp;rdquo; Throw away, easy phrases. I&amp;rsquo;ve never valued the first and I&amp;rsquo;ve had nothing but contempt for the second.
My professor in college would dock our grades when someone uttered one of these phrases. He believed they were lame and comfortable. If that&amp;rsquo;s all you&amp;rsquo;ve got to say, you didn&amp;rsquo;t really have anything to say.</description></item><item><title>The Future Role of Libraries</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/future-role-libraries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/future-role-libraries/</guid><description>If Libraries want to stay relevant they have to redefine their role in communities. The common perception is they have books, lots of books. This is obvious. Over the last decade the perception has grown to include internet access. However, this isn&amp;rsquo;t enough to survive. If you live in a progressive town like myself, WiFi is ubiquitous. When the Library is competing with Henry&amp;rsquo;s Coffeehouse, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t need to tell you who wins.</description></item><item><title>An Open answer</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/open-answer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/open-answer/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s my prediction that over the next few years we&amp;rsquo;re going to see a rise of localized social networks/directories. Localized social networks can augment and enhance real world local communities, if the recipe is just right. The first ingredient is key for any up-and-comming project summoning user authentication.
The key to localized networks and other new applications that fill particular niches is OpenID (http://openid.net/). Consistency among user profiles is non-existant. OpenID brings with it a pure, centralized repository for profile management where you&amp;rsquo;re empowered to adjust the strings of privacy based on sites you&amp;rsquo;ve opened the doors too.</description></item><item><title>Elections by the seat of our chads</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/elections-seat-our-chads/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/elections-seat-our-chads/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve launched a lot of web projects in my career, but none of them have come close to the excitement of this evenings whirlwind. For the 2006 elections our little group called World Online at the Lawrence Journal-World launched a live view of the local and state citizens fulfilling their democratic roles as citizens.
At 7pm CST we flipped the switch, waiting patiently while live data feeds poured in from Associated Press, Kansas Secretary of State and Douglas County.</description></item><item><title>In with the Em's and Percentages</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/ems-and-percentages/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/ems-and-percentages/</guid><description>For the past few projects I&amp;rsquo;ve thrown out all use of pixels and relied heavily on an em&amp;rsquo;s and percentages for layout and font sizing. Why would someone take such drastic measures? Two simple reasons: usability and flexibility.
The current Domaki, circa Fall 2006, uses this practice which makes the liquid layout possible with ease. A non-liquid example would be the Ellington (http://www.ellingtoncms.com) site which uses a container set in EM&amp;rsquo;s with all inner layers set to percentages.</description></item><item><title>A Gestalt point of view</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/gestalt-point-view/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/gestalt-point-view/</guid><description>During my junior year of college I was required to enroll in a cinematography course as part of the Electronic Arts program. The first day of class we received a typical syllabus and course schedule. Then we immediately dove into a topic that I still remember to this day, Gestalt psychology.
In its basic form, Gestalt tries to explain how we perceive more than the collected sum. Musical tunes can be recognized in different keys or with added notes.</description></item><item><title>FTP bad, versioning good</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/ftp-bad-versioning-good/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/ftp-bad-versioning-good/</guid><description>You may have noticed a little downtime Sunday evening. I was able to get the Domaki code under version control (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revision_control) which I highly recommend. It allows you to kick FTP to the curb and do everything with &amp;ldquo;svn commit&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;update&amp;rdquo; commands.
The main reason for doing this was my extreme inability to remember which files I&amp;rsquo;ve changed. Subversion (http://subversion.tigris.org/) takes the worry out of my day by committing the necessary files from my local machine to my repository.</description></item><item><title>Journalists and public discourse</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/journalists-and-public-discourse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/journalists-and-public-discourse/</guid><description>I was involved in a discussion recently about whether journalists should be allowed to comment on news stories. My employer, the Lawrence Journal-World, allows the public to comment on online stories. Quick note: while I may work for the newspaper my experience with journalism at the time of this post is very informal. I am a member of the public, which in my opinion makes this opinion just as valid as any.</description></item><item><title>Damn you Starbucks</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/damn-you-starbucks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/damn-you-starbucks/</guid><description>I despise you and your cranberry oatmeal mountain bars and tall house coffees with room for cream. Your sirens (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starbucks#Name_and_logo) whispering sweet nothings into innocent passerby&amp;rsquo;s. You mock my town by cloaking yourself in local establishments and yet you still survive. You&amp;rsquo;re like a light brown german cockroach impervious to insecticide. My town successfully squashed Wal-mart&amp;rsquo;s ambitions but not you. You somehow slipped through the carpet cracks and built your roach hotel right across from my work.</description></item><item><title>Piercing my tongue</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/piercing-my-tongue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/piercing-my-tongue/</guid><description>I just bought a new nano and Nike+ kit but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want the Nike shoes nor did I care for the recent &amp;lsquo;velcro&amp;rsquo; hack. Instead of looking like a huge geek with a transmitter in my laces (http://podophile.com/2006/07/14/shoe-hacker-nikeipod-sport-kit-shoe-mod/), I decided to surgically insert the transmitter into my shoe tongue.
Step 1 Gather up your favorite running shoe. Find an exacto knife or razor blade of sorts and buy a Nike+ kit.</description></item><item><title>Nostalgic four years</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/nostalgic-four-years/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/nostalgic-four-years/</guid><description>Last night I was doing a little house cleaning and drifted off to reminiscing mode. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize how many redesigns I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through and the ones that never made the cut. In some cases I kinda wish they did. So as a follow up to &amp;ldquo;Slightly neurotic on change&amp;rdquo; (/posts/2006/sep/04/slightly-neurotic-change/) I&amp;rsquo;ll prove this neurosis with the following dusty relics from the past:
!http://www.domaki.com/media/posts/2006-sep-14/big/01.jpg !http://www.domaki.com/media/posts/2006-sep-14/big/02.jpg !http://www.domaki.com/media/posts/2006-sep-14/big/03.jpg !http://www.domaki.com/media/posts/2006-sep-14/big/04.jpg !http://www.domaki.com/media/posts/2006-sep-14/big/05.jpg !http://www.domaki.com/media/posts/2006-sep-14/big/06.jpg !http://www.domaki.com/media/posts/2006-sep-14/big/07.jpg !</description></item><item><title>Switching from Rails to Django</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/switching-rails-django/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/switching-rails-django/</guid><description>So back in the Fall of 2005 I launched (/posts/2005/aug/15/bejeweled/) my foray into the world of Rails like every other designer wannabe programmer. I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest, I did it because everyone else was. Looking back I don&amp;rsquo;t really know why, I just followed the &amp;ldquo;if it feels good, do it&amp;rdquo; principle.
Out of that decision grew a love/hate relationship. I&amp;rsquo;m primarily a designer but I like sticking my hands in the programming cookie jar.</description></item><item><title>Fun with Beautiful Soup</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/fun-beautiful-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/fun-beautiful-soup/</guid><description>So how easy is it to yank out all links in a post and display them as a list on their own? Well with a little Python love and some Django filters it&amp;rsquo;s easy as microwave burritos. Before we get started you&amp;rsquo;ll need a fresh copy of ElementTree and BeautifulSoup.
ElementTree (http://effbot.org/zone/element-index.htm) and BeautifulSoup (http://www.crummy.com/software/BeautifulSoup/) together form a very handy toolbox for parsing structured data. ElementTree is used a lot for parsing XML and BeautifulSoup is tailored more towards parsing XHTML.</description></item><item><title>Warming up to context</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/warming-context/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/warming-context/</guid><description>Context can be described as, &amp;ldquo;the circumstances that form the setting for an event, statement, or idea, and in terms of which it can be fully understood and assessed.&amp;rdquo; Context plays an important role in communication and I&amp;rsquo;d like start by providing better context to posts.
You may have noticed a left column on my blog post pages. It now contains geo location information regarding where the post was written, categories it belongs to, links that exist within the post and photos that were taken on the day the it was published.</description></item><item><title>Slightly neurotic on change</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/slightly-neurotic-change/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/slightly-neurotic-change/</guid><description>Always tweaking here and there. Today marks a big tweak including a name change, site realignment, and a fun little visualization project. Welcome to Domaki (pronounced Du·mock·eee), formerly &amp;ldquo;You know where you are&amp;rdquo; and formally &amp;ldquo;Playground Blues.&amp;rdquo; I am your host, Nathan Borror.
Whats changed? All the markup has been overhauled. I&amp;rsquo;ve been fine tuning a particular CSS framework that is a derivative of the YUI framework (http://developer.yahoo.com/yui/grids/) over at Yahoo.</description></item><item><title>Privacy in context</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/privacy-context/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/privacy-context/</guid><description>In the 20&amp;rsquo;s we fought prohibition, 50&amp;rsquo;s and 60&amp;rsquo;s it was segregation. Today we face a new battle called privacy. I bring this up because in todays Lawrence Journal-World Sarah Benson wrote an interesting article titled Facebook indiscretions plague users (http://www2.ljworld.com/news/2006/aug/12/facebook_indiscretions_plague_users/).
In her article she gives two examples of the unintended consequences of social networking. The first outlines how an employer can peer into prospective employees social pasts using current employee accounts.</description></item><item><title>Collective Soul</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/collective-soul/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/collective-soul/</guid><description>The reviews (http://www.wired.com/news/columns/cultofmac/0,71557-0.html?tw=wn_technology_4) are pouring (http://www.mcelhearn.com/article.php?story=20060808113448585) in regarding this years WWDC keynote. Each critiquing the slightest moves Steve Jobs made or didn&amp;rsquo;t make. This shared keynote in particular has raised the question, &amp;ldquo;is Jobs preparing for departure?&amp;rdquo; Just the notion spreads fear amongst even the most liberal mac fanatics.
This got me thinking about the importance of hiring the right people. Wikipedia defines company (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Company) as a &amp;ldquo;legal entity formed which has a separate legal identity from its members.</description></item><item><title>White Flight takes off</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/white-flight-takes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/white-flight-takes/</guid><description>Holly fucking shit you have to listen to White Flight (http://rangeliferecords.com/listen/listen_WF_02.html) right now! Yesterday I stepped into my boss&amp;rsquo;s very slick auto to pick up some pies for a late night work dinner and I expect some NPR, instead I get a feeling I got the first time I heard Postal Service.
Not since my Postal Service experience have I heard music of this caliber. Justin Roelofs (http://www.lawrence.com/blogs/street_level/2005/dec/09/hownow/), from The Anniversary, has managed to enter a realm that has no explanation.</description></item><item><title>Nothing In Disguise</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/nothing-disguise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/nothing-disguise/</guid><description>A few Sunday&amp;rsquo;s back I was in a coffee house determined to work. Instead, I quickly fell into a dream state which is the plague of many Sunday mornings. I felt guilty about being so unproductive, but, I had no pressing deadlines, no urgent emails, no clients knocking at my door. Later that night I felt a surge of creativity and began painting, which got me wondering. Lets see what Brenda Ueland (http://www.</description></item><item><title>Del.icio.us API Interface</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/delicious-api-interface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/delicious-api-interface/</guid><description>I finally figured out how to parse the Del.icio.us API (http://del.icio.us/help/api/) using Python and Django. The solution is quite flexible aside from the fact that the Del.icio.us API is still under development.
I started by studying FlickrClient (http://micampe.it/things/flickrclient) which is a great interface for Python. The Flickr API is very verbose and this is a simple approach that scales to future Flickr upgrades. The power behind this script is the following method:</description></item><item><title>A Bittersweet Farewell</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/bittersweet-farewell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/bittersweet-farewell/</guid><description>You probably haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed but the past month has been particularly challenging for me. If you&amp;rsquo;re a close friend then it was probably apparent in the way I cheaply disguise my emotions. It&amp;rsquo;s not easy to look back at two years of progress in advertising and realize all along you may have stumbled into the wrong cocktail party. Once this realization occurs it creeps into all your thoughts and emotions to the point where you can no longer function until a change is made.</description></item><item><title>It's Time To Behave</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/its-time-behave/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/its-time-behave/</guid><description>We are all hypocrites, every damn one of us. Well, actually, just those that are guilty of inline javascript. Now don&amp;rsquo;t get all puffed up, I&amp;rsquo;m just as guilty but it&amp;rsquo;s time to change and I have some tips!
Over the past couple years we&amp;rsquo;ve heard a lot about separation. Two types, in particular, have been evangelized, data from structure and structure from style. One we don&amp;rsquo;t hear about nor see it practiced very often is separation between structure and behavior.</description></item><item><title>Seven Patriots</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/seven-patriots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/seven-patriots/</guid><description>What better way to celebrate our independence than roaring into space in one of the most complex machines ever built! You can watch this miraculous display of human engineering at NASA.gov (http://www.nasa.gov/).
Space exploration gives me goose bumps. My heart skips a beat when, just for one second, I try to comprehend its limitless nature. To think we&amp;rsquo;re able to catapult seven of our greatest minds into this vacuum of questions and answers makes me pause and wonder what we&amp;rsquo;ll choose to achieve next.</description></item><item><title>Django Gotchas</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/django-gotchas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/django-gotchas/</guid><description>One of the biggest hurdles in learning any new framework or programming language is learning its quirks. By quirks I don&amp;rsquo;t mean bugs, I&amp;rsquo;m referring to the personality and flow. Here are a few that might help your troubleshooting process:
I get an error when I run syncdb. This could be a number of things. If its an error in the model you should be able to tell. Most of the time for me was forgetting to add the project to the settings.</description></item><item><title>80x80</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/80x80/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/80x80/</guid><description>I said Friday but I meant Monday. Sometimes things take longer but in my case I just wanted to compete for attention the same day Digg 3 (http://www.digg.com) launched. All amusement aside I&amp;rsquo;d like to take the plastic wrap off my new site that I&amp;rsquo;ve dubbed 80x80.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got something I&amp;rsquo;m proud of. She&amp;rsquo;s still stretching herself out so if you notice any kinks let me know and I&amp;rsquo;ll call the masseuse.</description></item><item><title>Victory Out of Context</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/victory-out-context/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/victory-out-context/</guid><description>President Bush says, just as the United States persevered and ultimately won the Cold War against communism, America will emerge victorious in the war on terror. &amp;ndash; http://www.voanews.com/english/2006-05-27-voa17.cfm
It&amp;rsquo;s misleading and irresponsible to imply the possibility of victory over terror. It is idealistically impossible to abolish a feeling. People will always fear and at times that fear will escalate to terror. From the time we are born we learn fear, it aids in our survival until the day we die.</description></item><item><title>Highlights</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/highlights/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/highlights/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m notorious for highlighting. At home, I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by a rapidly growing library. Some books have been read cover to cover, some cover to creamy center, and some randomly picked through. But, I can confidently guarantee, each has felt the screeching of my fat yellow Avery HI-LITER.
Why? Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s an incessant urge to mark my territory or a worry that I&amp;rsquo;ll forget a phrase that made my grey matter jiggle.</description></item><item><title>Subversion Love</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/subversion-love/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/subversion-love/</guid><description>I have a new love (http://subversion.tigris.org). For the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off this slightly important part of being a pragmatic programmer (http://pragmaticprogrammer.com/ppbook/index.shtml).
I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the horror stories of CVS so I steered clear of it for this new flavor of life saving loveliness. Gone are the days of, &amp;ldquo;is this the newest copy?&amp;rdquo; Goodbye to unsettling feelings of cautiously dragging and dropping files from one server to the next.</description></item><item><title>Making The Case</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/making-case/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/making-case/</guid><description>Why is it that certain days I opt for the Man&amp;rsquo;s coffee and other days I champion the locals? I thought it had something to do with consistency but that&amp;rsquo;s bullshit. While the Man&amp;rsquo;s store is well designed and has a familiar atmosphere it reeks of fake smiles, stale business folk, and overly perfect pastries. Admittedly those dainty pastries are quite wonderful, but thats besides the point.
The locals aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid to show attitude, they&amp;rsquo;re real, they proudly bear the title, Barista.</description></item><item><title>Don't Stress</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/dont-stress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/dont-stress/</guid><description>Your heart starts pounding, blood pressure soars and you begin to take shorter faster breaths. Why do we put every cell in our body through such a traumatic experience?
Stress was hard wired into our bodies for those face to face moments with mountain lions. It&amp;rsquo;s called fight or flight. Mountain lions don&amp;rsquo;t seem to bother us anymore so we&amp;rsquo;ve repurposed this reaction to things like client deadlines, idiots on the freeway, and that bar that plays horrible music on wednesday nights below my loft.</description></item><item><title>Don't Delete, Version</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/dont-delete-version/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/dont-delete-version/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying with the idea of versioning. And I don&amp;rsquo;t mean versioning in the programming sense, although I really need to figure out Subversion (http://subversion.tigris.org/) one of these days. I&amp;rsquo;m referring to content management systems.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know why but deletion just bugs me. Maybe its my pack rat mentality but to delete is to lose. I write blog entries all the time that don&amp;rsquo;t get published and sometimes I completely rewrite them losing past versions.</description></item><item><title>Rules Rule</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/rules-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/rules-rule/</guid><description>As children we grew up hating curfew, as adolescence we rebelled against the drinking age, and as adults we shake our fists at stop lights and speed limits. What we don&amp;rsquo;t realize is rules set us free.
I came across this simple notion in Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi&amp;rsquo;s book Flow (http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060920432/). By having laws and rules we free ourselves from contemplating things that have already been determined. This provides a framework for thought which is valuable when applied to design.</description></item><item><title>My Easter</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/my-easter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/my-easter/</guid><description>Woke up around 11:30 after a long night of coding (http://www.rubyonrails.com). Had a turkey sandwich and some pretzels while watching some television (http://www.historychannel.com). Packed up some essentials: laptop (http://www.apple.com/powerbook/), couple (http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060920432/) books (http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0465024114/), and headphones (http://www.stanc.net/eggo/). Drove to the cafe (http://www.broadwaycafeandroastery.com) that breaks for no resurrection. Had a soy latte while improving some Rails code and listening to some music (http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewAlbum?id=2960659&amp;amp;amp;s=143441). Then I came home, worked out, read (http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596007655/), and listened to some piano.</description></item><item><title>Jason Collett</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/jason-collett/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/jason-collett/</guid><description>Just got back from a session with Jason Collett (http://www.arts-crafts.ca/jasoncollett/) from Broken Social Scene (http://www.arts-crafts.ca/bss/). I highly recommend checking this man out. Has sort of a modern day Bob Dylan appeal with fresh percussion. Their newest album, Idols of Exile, offers quaint morsels of Canadian goodness. If you&amp;rsquo;re in need of something fresh and lighthearted, look no further. I only wish Mrs. Feist could have made an appearance.</description></item><item><title>After SXSW</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/after-sxsw/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/after-sxsw/</guid><description>I already miss waking up in the morning and planning my day at the Hide Out over a cup of joe. I miss that walk from 7th and Congress to the convention center seeing fellow lanyards. More importantly I miss seeing those who contribute so much to the beautiful corners of our web.
There were some great panel lineups and as much as I love hearing about tech and code I felt like distancing myself from the technical aspects of our industry and focus on listening to what others had to say about the roles psychology and sociology play in what we do.</description></item><item><title>Gooey Plastic</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/gooey-plastic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/gooey-plastic/</guid><description>At what point does interactive design become temporal art over plastic art? This question seems to be rare yet extremely important in our decision making process. This (http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060391685/) book prompted my pondering of this.
To clarify, temporal art includes poetry, writing, film and music. Plastic art takes the form of painting, drawing and sculpture. What sets the two apart is that fourth dimension, time. The success of temporal art is in its progressive events leading up to a fulfilling end, better known as climax.</description></item><item><title>Visualize Then Talk</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/visualize-then-talk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/visualize-then-talk/</guid><description>One of my favorite quotes from the Godfather trillogy is when Michael Corleone wisly reminds Vinnie, &amp;ldquo;never let anyone know what you are thinking.&amp;rdquo;
The importance of this is astronomical in client meetings. Never bring new ideas to the table in a client meeting. Bring vetted ideas. Prepare yourself before the meeting. Have concept sessions with colleagues, visualize the ideas, make sure you have the resources and be sure the idea is possible.</description></item><item><title>Make It Better</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/make-it-better/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/make-it-better/</guid><description>Bored tonight so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d impregnate some coders out there with some of my seed. My hopes are that this will cause you to give birth to better code. I am pro choice so if you choose to abort I understand whole heartedly. Before you do so please consider adoption, there are plenty of other good coders out there that may benefit.
Ok, enough metaphors. This is some actionscript I did over Christmas (download code (/code/flash_template.</description></item><item><title>Waking The Right</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/waking-right/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/waking-right/</guid><description>Thank God it&amp;rsquo;s Friday. I&amp;rsquo;m planning another one of my &amp;ldquo;introvert retreats.&amp;rdquo; About two weeks ago at 5 o&amp;rsquo;clock CST I turned off all forms of communication. The following day I drove to Lawrence, Kansas sans laptop. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like anything too special but the resulting clarity and relaxation was well worth it.
This weekend I&amp;rsquo;ll be cutting it a little short so I can be somewhat social Saturday night. The trip to Lawrence is a go and I&amp;rsquo;ll be invading an undisclosed dark coffee house chugging away on my laptop.</description></item><item><title>Did You Know</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/did-you-know/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/did-you-know/</guid><description>I work with a small team of designers inside a very large ad agency (http://www.bernstein-rein.com). Like most ad agencies they focus primarily on print and broadcast. Having a small web division can sometimes cause confusion between the different mediums.
I never really realized how different web was from print and broadcast until my time at an agency. So I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled a quick list of a few items that I think set web apart.</description></item><item><title>An Explaination</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/explaination/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/explaination/</guid><description>When the name Playground Blues was chosen I was a junior in college. It didn&amp;rsquo;t carry much meaning other than playgrounds seemed like whimsical places where imagination wondered. I feel I&amp;rsquo;ve grown out of the name.
Playground Blues has meant a lot to me. It&amp;rsquo;s enjoyed roughly five official redesigns, god knows how many unofficial. It&amp;rsquo;s been featured on many sites including The Daily Report (http://www.zeldman.com/daily/0504e.shtml#reboot) by Jeffrey Zeldman, Moluv (http://www.</description></item><item><title>On Air</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/air/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2006/air/</guid><description>The new and improved webcam (http://www.playgroundblues.com/webcam) is BACK! It now allows you to post messages. When you do it attaches the current image and keeps a running archive of past webcam moments. It&amp;rsquo;s quite possible this is a first in web history. Could I be so lucky?
For those of you who were wondering&amp;hellip; Evocam (http://www.evological.com/evocam.html) is being used to FTP images every 30 seconds. Some handy flash work is being used to serve the newest image to my people.</description></item><item><title>Worm Club</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/worm-club/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2005 18:09:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/worm-club/</guid><description>Friends and cohorts keep asking me me to recommend books so in an effort to slightly curb this I&amp;rsquo;ve manifested the list below. Warning: I cannot guarantee I&amp;rsquo;ve finished these books. I have a tendency, possibly fear, of finishing books. I literally get to the last chapter and it sits on my coffee table for weeks. So far, these have been intriguing books to me:
Blink and The Tipping Point by Malcom Gladwell.</description></item><item><title>Ruby Text Search</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/ruby-text-search/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2005 18:10:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/ruby-text-search/</guid><description>I found some great Ruby code to assist in creating a simplistic search engine for your Rails app. It can be found on the Rails Wiki under TextSearch. I recommend clicking on the &amp;ldquo;edit&amp;rdquo; button at the bottom to copy and paste the code out of the text field because some of the syntax gets lost on the page version. Just don&amp;rsquo;t click save :)
You may want to add &amp;lsquo;%&amp;quot; on either side of the search terms.</description></item><item><title>Four Horsemen</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/four-horsemen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2005 18:11:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/four-horsemen/</guid><description>No the rumors are not true. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been kidnapped by the government in suspicion of plotting the end of the world. Although some may suggest it is the dawn of the end. Jesus, yes I do mean you, what the hell is going on? Earth is shakin, wind is blowin, water is getting everywhere, and birds are out of control!
Not too worry, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t disrupted the good old midwest, yet.</description></item><item><title>Innocent Bystander</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/innocent-bystander/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2005 18:12:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/innocent-bystander/</guid><description>Everyone should participate in a little people watching activities. It allows you to jump out of your inner chaotic life and realize that you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. Now, there are a few keys to successful people watching. I&amp;rsquo;ll share some of mine, then you can pass yours along if you wish.
Avoid eye contact. In order to remain a fly on the wall you must avoid eye contact at all costs.</description></item><item><title>Full Steam Ahead</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/full-steam-ahead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2005 18:12:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/full-steam-ahead/</guid><description>Playground Blues is officially on Rails. Approximately two weeks ago I started chugging along and with this new language. Surprisingly it&amp;rsquo;s been quite welcoming and easy to learn. I only wish it were just as easy to ween clients over to this oasis.
Along with the change of language came some other needed changes. One of them being my move from Textile to Markdown otherwise known as BlueCloth in Rails. Markdown just seemed more natural to the way I type.</description></item><item><title>Art Mobs</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/art-mobs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2005 18:14:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/art-mobs/</guid><description>I have a new PodCast to add to your library. It&amp;rsquo;s by Art Mobs and its called Art Mobs MoMA Guides. The descriptions is &amp;ldquo;A &amp;lsquo;Commons&amp;rsquo; for audio guides to artworks at the Museum of Modern Art, NYC.&amp;rdquo; Basically an entertaining discussion about modern art. I think this is by far the most creative use of PodCasting, no pun intended.</description></item><item><title>Bejeweled</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/bejeweled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2005 18:15:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/bejeweled/</guid><description>I spent last weekend learning Ruby on Rails (http://www.rubyonrails.com) and now I can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder why the hell it took me so long. My work (http://www.bradv.com) was kind enough to fetch me a copy of Agile Web Development with Rails (http://pragmaticprogrammer.com/titles/rails/index.html) and I&amp;rsquo;ve had a hard time focusing on anything else.
I&amp;rsquo;ve already started porting some of my apps (http://glide.playgroundblues.com) to Rails and its surprisingly elegant and fun. After figuring out associations between database tables I feel well on my way.</description></item><item><title>Pre-Order Rant</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/pre-order-rant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2005 18:16:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/pre-order-rant/</guid><description>Why would anybody want to pre-order an album off of iTunes? The whole idea of the &amp;ldquo;pre-order&amp;rdquo; is that your John Hancock gets placed on a list of elite few who get first dibs on a product before it sells out. It is virtually impossible for iTunes to sell out of a song, which makes me wonder what yahoo in the war room decided it&amp;rsquo;d be cool to have &amp;ldquo;pre-orders&amp;rdquo; in iTunes.</description></item><item><title>Background Becoming Foreground</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/background-becoming-foreground/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2005 18:17:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/background-becoming-foreground/</guid><description>Since the release of Tiger and particularly Quicktime 7 sporting the new H.264 codec I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to wonder if we&amp;rsquo;re glimpsing a bigger picture here. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t checked out the unbelievable quality of H.264 go over to the HD Gallery and witness the days of pixilation disappear.
With this brings some interesting thoughts; does Apple have a roadmap for video on demand? Well, they&amp;rsquo;ve already started doing it with iTunes 4.</description></item><item><title>Farewell and Hello</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/farewell-and-hello/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2005 18:17:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/farewell-and-hello/</guid><description>This is my last week at my current employer, Look and Feel which would explain my lack of good posts. I can&amp;rsquo;t express how fortunate I am to have spent time with the fine lads of LaF. I will miss them dearly, although, I&amp;rsquo;ll still be living in the neighborhood so I&amp;rsquo;m sure our paths will cross.
My near future rests at a place called Method within Bernstein-Rein. A fortune teller has forcasted very long hours but many laughs and Belgium beer flowing from the hill tops.</description></item><item><title>Hear Me Purr</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/hear-me-purr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2005 18:18:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/hear-me-purr/</guid><description>Time to chim in on Tiger. Dashboard, Spotlight, Automator, Oh My! I was worried at first, things were slow and hard drive was crankin'. Once Spotlight finished indexing my mess of over six years of files I breathed a sigh of relief.
Apple has posted a handy little Dashboard Programming Guide with all sorts of design guidlines and API info. They have done the same for Automator. This little app can save scary amounts of time.</description></item><item><title>PHP on Rails</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/php-on-rails/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2005 18:22:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/php-on-rails/</guid><description>Ruby buzz has been making its rounds these last few months. I&amp;rsquo;m anxious to use Rails but my ISP nor my employer support it. So I&amp;rsquo;ve been stuck staring at the colorful lollypop from a distance.
Cake may be the solution to my problems, at least until Ruby becomes more widely supported. Cake is a PHP framework based on the Rails design. It&amp;rsquo;s still in its infancy but it looks pretty solid.</description></item><item><title>The Bands</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/the-bands/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2005 18:23:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/the-bands/</guid><description>The Faint, The Ataris, The Features, The Futureheads, The Cure, The Hives, The Killers, The Music, The People, The Prodigy, The Roots, The Bravery, The Kills, The Samples, The Shins, The Doors, The Stills, The Streets, The Strokes, The Used, The Walkmen, The Darkness, The Who, The Ramones, The Sights, The National, The Wrights, The Republic, The Congos, The Zincs, The Stix, The Perishers, The Police, Rapture, The Unicorns, The Kinks, The Mollys, The Soviettes, The Winners, The Velons, The Smugglers, The Makers, The Upsidedown, The Donnas.</description></item><item><title>Selling Your Soul</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/selling-your-soul/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2005 18:23:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/selling-your-soul/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been going back and forth with my colleagues regarding pre-built admin tools. My position has been the benefits of adopting a framework outweigh any off-the-shelf tool.
What is the difference between a framework and an off-the-shelf system? It&amp;rsquo;s like buying fake plants instead of real ones. off-the-shelf products leave very little wiggle room for growth and are inevitably more than what you need. They also exhibit poor usability, with there shiny plastic leaves and all.</description></item><item><title>Soft Launch</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/soft-launch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2005 18:24:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/soft-launch/</guid><description>This launch is softer than a baby&amp;rsquo;s bum. Please excuse the possible broken links, sparse content, grayed out links, and unusually shaped big toe.
Things should be up to speed by the end of this week so keep checking back from time to time. Also, if you don&amp;rsquo;t mind, I&amp;rsquo;ll throw you a me update:
I&amp;rsquo;m done photo blogging. It was fun while it lasted but I&amp;rsquo;m out of good photos so back to writing.</description></item><item><title>Broken Window Theory</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/broken-window-theory/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2005 18:25:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/broken-window-theory/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve become a little obsessed with the &amp;ldquo;Broken Window Theory.&amp;rdquo; I was introduced to this theory by Travis and Charlie. Soon after, it began popping into my head at work, home, or while I was coding. Then I started noticing it in books and on the radio.
The theory is normally applied to urban decay and crime, however, it can be applied to almost anything. How did your apartment get so dirty?</description></item><item><title>Double the Pleasure</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/double-the-pleasure/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 19:19:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/double-the-pleasure/</guid><description>Last night two new albums pitched a tent on my &amp;ldquo;oh my god&amp;rdquo; list of music. The Faint &amp;ldquo;Wet From Birth&amp;rdquo; and Tom Waits &amp;ldquo;Real Gone&amp;rdquo; are so unbelievably necessary I don&amp;rsquo;t even know why you&amp;rsquo;re still reading. Go get them!
The Faint marches forward with its sexy themes and lucius lyrics. My uncertainties about how they would top Blank-Wave Arcade were shattered by the first track and continued to crumble through track two until they were disintegrated with &amp;ldquo;Southern Belles in London Sing.</description></item><item><title>Kansas City Migration</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kansas-city-migration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2004 12:59:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kansas-city-migration/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully migrated to Downtown Kansas City from Springfield. It took about a week to get all my stuff in order and my mind is catching up.
Tried Middle Eastern food for the first time, go Gyros! If you haven&amp;rsquo;t had Chile Relleno I suggest you dart to a good Mexican restaurant and give it a taste.
The First Friday Art Walk happened to be last friday. Hammerpress unveiled their Christmas collection.</description></item><item><title>Yo La Weekend</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/yo-la-weekend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2004 13:01:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/yo-la-weekend/</guid><description>This weekend I saw Yo La Tengo for the first time in Kansas City. Definitely worth the bones if they&amp;rsquo;re in your area. Amazing jams and a really hot drummer girl. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with them I recommend first getting &amp;ldquo;I Can Hear the Heart Beating as One&amp;rdquo; and then &amp;ldquo;Summer Sun.&amp;rdquo; If your hooked you&amp;rsquo;ll also like &amp;ldquo;And Then Nothing Turned Itself Inside-Out.&amp;rdquo;
Also did a little apartment hunting before I begin playing/working with the fine lads at Look and Feel.</description></item><item><title>Rip Alvin iPod</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/rip-alvin-ipod/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2004 19:23:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/rip-alvin-ipod/</guid><description>Today is a sad day. I went for a bike ride downtown and in a moment of braveness, tragedy struck. After making a successful jump from a very large curb a sense of accomplishment ended when my pedal clipped the curb halting my bike and catapulting me through the air. The silence that followed seemed to be more painful than my bleeding arm.
Alvin was a good iPod. The first generation of his time.</description></item><item><title>More Adventurous</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/more-adventurous/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2004 19:23:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/more-adventurous/</guid><description>About a year ago a friend of mine introduced me to a little world called Rilo Kiley. Her two albums, &amp;ldquo;Execution of All Things&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Takeoffs and Landings&amp;rdquo;, bring sunshine to a rainy day and lift you up to a place not often visited through music. Jenny Lewis&amp;rsquo;s voice never seems to grow old. They&amp;rsquo;re songs are so diverse and colorful.
I honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t believe they could top their last two releases.</description></item><item><title>Jupiter</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/jupiter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2004 19:22:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/jupiter/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce a new project of mine. It&amp;rsquo;s called Jupiter. Jupiter is a project management solution that began August 1, 2004 after heavy research. Roughly two months of ironing out the database scheme and functionality I&amp;rsquo;m ready to get feedback and suggestions. Keep in mind things are in the beginning stages and this is by no means a finished/polished product.
I was planning to provide a run down of all the bells and whistles but I think I would rather get everyones first impressions and go from there.</description></item><item><title>Textpattern Blues</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/textpattern-blues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2004 19:21:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/textpattern-blues/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve slowly been warming up to Textpattern over the past few months. At the spur of the moment I purchased a nice little plot over at Dreamhost and starting some planting. I&amp;rsquo;m about finished tilling the land and beginning to plant some seeds, however, you might stumble across some rocky areas.
On another note, since when did IE6 not support min-width and max-width? Yet another disappointment handed down from the pearly white gates.</description></item><item><title>A Revolution of Education</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/a-revolution-of-education/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2004 19:21:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/a-revolution-of-education/</guid><description>I believe it&amp;rsquo;s time for a Education Revolution. While I may not be an expert in learning science I did participate in the Education system for 17 years and continue to work for an University.
Currently a majority of institutions force students to subscribe to General Education pressuring them to learn History, Physical Education, Mathematics and so on. While these topics carry an extreme importance this method of delivery is wrong.</description></item><item><title>Heads or Tails</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/heads-or-tails/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2004 19:19:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/heads-or-tails/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been somewhat silent lately with a few whispers here and there. The past couple weeks have been very interesting, stressful to say the least. Job, home and personal changes.
After much thought and pondering I accepted a position at Southwest Missouri State University as Multimedia Producer. I bid a humble farewell to Neubix Studios. The gamut of knowledge and wisdom Ryan and I provided each other was priceless. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful to have been apart of their transformation and growth.</description></item><item><title>Inspirational Journeys</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/inspirational-journeys/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2004 13:12:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/inspirational-journeys/</guid><description>In 1947 sculptor, Korczak Ziolkowski, moved too Thunder Mountain. He constructed a 741 foot staircase to the peak of the Mountain to begin, with his lone jackhammer, possibly the worlds largest sculpture, Crazy Horse. For the next 33 years he chipped away at the mammoth mountain side until his death.
His eye is 12 feet wide, his outstretched arm the length of a subway train. And by the time his horse is finished, we&amp;rsquo;ll all be dead.</description></item><item><title>Wireless Lack</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/wireless-lack/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2004 13:11:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/wireless-lack/</guid><description>Today my coffee house was closed for the holiday. If you could only see the look on my face. It seems to be the only downside to holidays. This didn&amp;rsquo;t detour me from finding a hotspot that provided legally addictive &amp;ldquo;stimulants.&amp;rdquo;
After much driving my choices were narrowed down to Starbucks and Panera. Starbucks uses T-mobile for wifi which costs money so I chose Panera with its free wifi provided by QGO.</description></item><item><title>Far from Modest</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/far-from-modest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2004 19:21:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/far-from-modest/</guid><description>Has anyone else really listened to the lyrics on the new Modest Mouse album? For lack of better words, they&amp;rsquo;re amazing.
The moths beat themselves to death against the lights. Adding their breeze to the summer nights. Outside water like air was great. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I had that day. Walk a little farther to another plan. You said that you did, but you didn&amp;rsquo;t understand. — The World At Large</description></item><item><title>Kottke Critique</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kottke-critique/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2004 19:05:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kottke-critique/</guid><description>Jason Kottke recently released the next incarnation of Kottke.org. I must say, even though visually things are very similar to the previous version, Jason has done an excellent job of perfecting his structure and usability.
Jason&amp;rsquo;s text dominant design reminds us of the power of typography. His subtle choices of font sizes, weights, leading and link color are methodically chosen along with simple dividers to create a harmonious feel. From the looks of things the famous green header has been on the Atkins diet.</description></item><item><title>Fragile Sunday</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/fragile-sunday/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2004 19:35:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/fragile-sunday/</guid><description>Sunday&amp;rsquo;s are supposed to invite rest and relaxation, however, this was like no other Sunday I anticipated. Saturday evening was great. I stumbled upon a public showing of Waking Life in an old art studio downtown. We enjoyed tea and sat on a variety of vintage chairs watching one of my favorite films. Afterwards I was feeling very reflective and philosophical so I read some and went to bed early.</description></item><item><title>Someone Find The Cat</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/someone-find-the-cat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2004 19:04:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/someone-find-the-cat/</guid><description>Why do we still have mice? Seriously, haven&amp;rsquo;t we reached the point in computer evolution where we can discard the mouse completely? Modern operating systems have the ability to solely rely on voice commands, pen devices and touch screens. Why is it taking us so long to rid ourselves of a device that is responsible for such a painful syndrome.
Mice are a thing of the past, much like CRT monitors, parallel ports, walkmans and even the compact disc.</description></item><item><title>Textpattern Flow</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/textpattern-flow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2004 19:03:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/textpattern-flow/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to pose a question to my readers that use Textpattern. Last week I noticed Jon Hicks switched over which sparked my interest. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to switch over to a PHP based system for a while and from what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen Textpattern is very nice. One of my issues is how to structure my content using the Section, Category, Page, etc. method that Textpattern uses. Can anyone out there provide an example or input on how they achieved a solid architecture?</description></item><item><title>Rise of the Documentary</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/rise-of-the-documentary/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2004 21:39:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/rise-of-the-documentary/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a connoisseur of documentary film and rarely do I read fiction opposed to non-fiction. Learning about the actions and habits of society, whether opinionated or not, has always intrigued me. It appears documentary film is rising in popularity. Not surprising due to the rise of Reality TV, they fit right in. Documentaries have allowed those with a story and small voice to speak aloud. Unfortunately, unless you live in a big city you may never get a chance to listen.</description></item><item><title>Flipping Zines</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/flipping-zines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2004 19:33:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/flipping-zines/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve got a bone to pick with design magazines. I used to buy them frequently based on issue topics. I never subscribe, mainly because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to confine myself to one magazine; sounds weird, deal with it. I haven&amp;rsquo;t purchased any new issues in about four months due to the overwhelming amount of advertisements. No-longer can you &amp;ldquo;flip&amp;rdquo; through these magazines without getting stuck on paper company ads or booklets on Adobe.</description></item><item><title>Stopdesign Critique</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/stopdesign-critique/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2004 19:03:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/stopdesign-critique/</guid><description>I felt like revisiting Douglas Bowman&amp;rsquo;s Stopdesign since my previous critique was premature. Douglas did a fine job on many fronts. The architecture is a three column joy. Strategic attention was given to the front page where a great deal of content is displayed without overloading your eye. The subtle use of color to distinguish a hierarchy makes this possible. As you dig deeper content expands to a two column layout.</description></item><item><title>Gmail Big Brother</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/gmail-big-brother/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 21:37:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/gmail-big-brother/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wondering what angle Google planned to take with its new Gmail service, currently in beta form. After some reading it all makes perfect sense. Google will offer 1GB of email space in return for the ability to scan your messages and place ads based on the content. After the excitement of 1GB wears, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to wonder if the trade off is morally right?
Example: I receive an email regarding a relatives grave health problems; to the right ads are displayed regarding funeral homes.</description></item><item><title>Stopdesign and Mezzoblue Critique</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/stopdesign-and-mezzoblue-critique/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2004 21:27:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/stopdesign-and-mezzoblue-critique/</guid><description>I hope the following designers don&amp;rsquo;t mind my friendly critique (they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t, design is meant to be critiqued).
Douglas Bowman of Stopdesign recently &amp;ldquo;ditched&amp;rdquo; his styles and &amp;ldquo;start[ed] over with a blank slate.&amp;rdquo; I immediately noticed the identity. Very well done. The new mark is reminiscent of the previous, however, this one is fresher and more bold. The type treatment on the logo is quite interesting as well. Playful but doesn&amp;rsquo;t set itself apart from the mark.</description></item><item><title>Lapsang Souchong</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lapsang-souchong/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2004 21:26:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lapsang-souchong/</guid><description>This weekend was very rejuvenating. The weather was beautiful and the town was minus over 5,000 college students. Campus was a ghost town, perfect for a little amateur skateboarding. Downtown was pretty desolate as well. Sunny weather invited me to do some outdoor sketching at the square. I drove by my future apartment enough to give my soon-to-be neighbors the impression of a stalker. Added a new Black Tea to my collection called Lapsang Souchong, it smells like campfire.</description></item><item><title>Truth Beauty Power</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/truth-beauty-power/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2004 21:24:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/truth-beauty-power/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Studies In Design by Christopher Dresser. The book was initially published in 1875 as an inspirational guide for designers. Dresser was most notable for his contributions to the Victorian era with his intricately designed textiles, furniture and ceramics. The following are passages I felt like sharing.
Decorations, to be satisfying to the educated, must manifest knowledge&amp;hellip; for unless the decoration is done wisely as well as with understanding , it may yet fail to please those who are best able to appreciate good ornament.</description></item><item><title>Lukova Exhibition</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lukova-exhibition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2004 21:24:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lukova-exhibition/</guid><description>Recently Luba Lukova graced our local Art and Design Gallery with some of her current works and sketches. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a fan of her style and philosophy. She currently teaches at the School of Visual Arts in Manhattan.
Her unique style focuses on metaphorical references, manipulation of the human form and she uses a very unique treatment of typography. I was able to snap some photos to share with you.</description></item><item><title>Quicksilver Revolution</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/quicksilver-revolution/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2004 21:22:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/quicksilver-revolution/</guid><description>As soon as I realized something was flirting with perfection I discover it gets even better. Over the past three years I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced Mac OS X evolve into, in my opinion, the most effective operating system on the planet. This revolution has spawned many enhancing third party applications. After reading the hype about Quicksilver I finally gave it some attention. Seconds after installing my jaw dropped.
I take my laptop everywhere and its my sole computer.</description></item><item><title>Gleaming the Cube</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/gleaming-the-cube/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2004 19:37:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/gleaming-the-cube/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been brushing up on my skills as a skateboarder behind a local Italian Restaurant. It began in my friends basement when we found a beat up skateboard during a regular weekend gathering. This sparked our interest further so we ended up buying some generic boards from a local skate shop. They were black underneath and screaming for artwork.
Last weekend we bought some spray paint (hot pink is unbelievably hard to find) and mylar.</description></item><item><title>A Modern Experience</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/a-modern-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2004 21:17:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/a-modern-experience/</guid><description>The Guggenheim in Manhattan recently had an Exhibition entitled &amp;ldquo;Singular Forms (Sometimes Repeated)&amp;rdquo; Art from 1951 to the Present. Not your typical exhibition where you study lavish master works. The topic was Minimalism and, at first, I was somewhat timid; this being my virgin modernist exhibition. I began reading the blocks of text describing each piece while the people next too me stared hopelessly into blank canvases. I was fascinated.</description></item><item><title>Back and Changed Forever</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/back-and-changed-forever/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2004 19:01:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/back-and-changed-forever/</guid><description>Back from Manhattan and feeling refreshed. Later this week I plan to post some photos and audio from the trip. Pending on how much stuff awaits me at work.
Some highlights include a group chat with Milton Glaser and Mirko Ilic, an exhibition by Christopher Dresser, East Village, Greenwich Village, SoHo, Fashion District, Upright Citizens Brigade, indy galleries, cafes in the morning, comic book and vintage book stores, walking with no direction, pizza and subway entertainment.</description></item><item><title>First Things First</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/first-things-first/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2004 19:30:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/first-things-first/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering many questions regarding my place as a designer. I feel I may have lost sight of certain goals which have lead me to question my purpose. Design will always be my first love, however, I need to be true to that which I love.
I spent time last night rereading The First Things First Manifesto. I recommend FTF to all designers, for it will stir up the same questions floating around in my head.</description></item><item><title>Kinetic Art</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kinetic-art/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2004 13:06:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kinetic-art/</guid><description>Over the weekend I&amp;rsquo;ve been preparing for my trip to Manhattan that is taking place next week. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading up on some new artists and refreshing myself on Art History because it makes the gallery and museum experience much more enjoyable when you have some knowledge behind what your looking at.
I came across one of my favorite artists that always seems to capture my attention. Alexander Calder&amp;rsquo;s mobiles are so fascinating to me and I always seem to stumble upon them in museums.</description></item><item><title>Indy Support</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/indy-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2004 13:08:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/indy-support/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been distancing myself from &amp;ldquo;corporate america.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to completely do unless your Ted Kaczynski but even he had to buy stamps. (Now I&amp;rsquo;m going to get weird Google referrals on Ted Kaczynski). Anyway, I have good reason for choosing this direction.
My family has a history of entrepreneurs that range from a Grandfather that sold &amp;ldquo;Nimrods&amp;rdquo; to a mom that makes and sells women&amp;rsquo;s clothing. This compels me to spend an extra dollar here and there in support of other entrepreneurs.</description></item><item><title>Not So Lucky</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/not-so-lucky/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2004 19:17:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/not-so-lucky/</guid><description>In response to my good friend Ryan&amp;rsquo;s entry on iTunes I&amp;rsquo;d just like to say I haven&amp;rsquo;t won a single song with that Pepsi promo. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s just bad luck or I just don&amp;rsquo;t drink enough Pepsi. I bought a Sierra Mist today and thought for sure I&amp;rsquo;d win but instead I was presented with &amp;ldquo;Please try again.&amp;rdquo;
Anyone want a first generation iPod? I&amp;rsquo;m selling it for 50 bucks, 75 with an iTrip.</description></item><item><title>Lack of Words</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lack-of-words/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2004 19:16:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lack-of-words/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty lame with my entries lately. Mainly due to work, work and freelance work. Good things are around the corner so bare with me. In the mean time I&amp;rsquo;ve come across some good reads:
If it ain&amp;rsquo;t broke, don&amp;rsquo;t fix it? Drop Shadow League Understanding Design</description></item><item><title>So Many Chairs</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/so-many-chairs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2004 19:14:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/so-many-chairs/</guid><description>I want to talk about style. What does it really mean? How do you get it? Does it really matter? I mainly just want to further my understanding of style by writing down some thoughts and ideas. Warning! The following is completely opinionated.
What does style mean? It means you&amp;rsquo;ve carved out a niche where you can be easily recognizable. People seek you for your ability to look a particular way.</description></item><item><title>Wireless Revolution</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/wireless-revolution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2004 19:13:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/wireless-revolution/</guid><description>In my quest to eliminate wires I purchased the Apple Bluetooth Pro Mouse. It&amp;rsquo;s a very charming piece of hardware. I&amp;rsquo;ve already gone through two of the regular Apple Pro mice. I have a tendency of wrapping the cord around the mouse when I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;on the go&amp;rdquo; and eventually the wire inside breaks. However they&amp;rsquo;ve been good to me and so far I&amp;rsquo;ve been very pleased with the Bluetooth derivative. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed when I&amp;rsquo;m transferring large amounts of data over our WiFi at work the mouse becomes really jumpy.</description></item><item><title>The Reading Trail</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/the-reading-trail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2004 19:12:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/the-reading-trail/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be finishing up the Da Vinci Code tonight. Once thats over I&amp;rsquo;m going to get back on the learning train. Cutting back on entertainment television, movies and other distractions. Time to get down to business.
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to sharpen my skills as an Information Architect. I&amp;rsquo;ve always enjoyed the organization of large amounts of data and felt like I was pretty good at it. However, I feel there is much more to learn.</description></item><item><title>Monster</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/monster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2004 12:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/monster/</guid><description>This weekend I went to see Monster. I saw the preview and sort of knew what I was getting myself into. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be an uplifting movie but I could tell these people had something to say. Some parts were hard to digest and some really made me question how I treat and view other people. It&amp;rsquo;s a movie that needs to be scene with an open mind and heart.</description></item><item><title>Just Do It</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/just-do-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2004 12:55:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/just-do-it/</guid><description>One of my most influential professors from college would always say, &amp;ldquo;Just do it!&amp;rdquo; in his thick Bosnian accent during sketch critiques. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether he was saying it before Nike but recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to &amp;ldquo;just do it.&amp;rdquo;
We all have these lists of things we want to do in life. Things we want to accomplish, practice, learn, experience. We recall the list in our day dreams but loose sight of how easy it is to &amp;ldquo;just do it.</description></item><item><title>Soundtrack of Life</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2003/soundtrack-of-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2003 18:59:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2003/soundtrack-of-life/</guid><description>You may find this odd but have you ever consciously listened to a particular CD during a particular time of your life in hopes that the music will in some way encapsulate those memories?
When I was in New York last March I listened to The Postal Service over and over and now every time I listen to that CD I remember walking up and down broadway and roaming around the subways.</description></item><item><title>Cross-Processing Film</title><link>https://nathan.run/posts/2003/cross-processing-film/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2003 18:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/posts/2003/cross-processing-film/</guid><description>Today I got my first roll of cross-processed negative film produced by my new Lomo. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty impressed. It took me a while to find a place in town that would cross process negative film but a little mom and pop shop pulled through for me.
What is cross processing you ask? Well basically you use the opposite chemicals to develop the film. Normally negative film is processed with C-41 chemicals and slide film is processed with E6.</description></item></channel></rss>