<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2004-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Stopdesign and Mezzoblue Critique</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/stopdesign-and-mezzoblue-critique/"/><published>2004-05-26T21:27:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/stopdesign-and-mezzoblue-critique/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I hope the following designers don&rsquo;t mind my friendly critique (they shouldn&rsquo;t, design is meant to be critiqued).</p>
<p>Douglas Bowman of <a href="http://www.stopdesign.com/">Stopdesign</a> recently &ldquo;ditched&rdquo; his styles and &ldquo;start[ed] over with a blank slate.&rdquo; I immediately noticed the identity. Very well done. The new mark is reminiscent of the previous, however, this one is fresher and more bold. The type treatment on the logo is quite interesting as well. Playful but doesn&rsquo;t set itself apart from the mark. Balancing the logo and name can be very challenging but Douglas shows no hesitation. Next I was drawn too is the white space. I loooove whitespace. When it&rsquo;s used properly your eye floats through the design, appreciating subtleties rather than getting lost in eye candy. I miss the color palate Douglas used on the old site. Providing a distinguishing design element like color to set apart different sections can be very pleasing. Overall, well done. I&rsquo;m anxious to see Stopdesign&rsquo;s evolution.</p>
<p>On to Dave Shea&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.mezzoblue.com/">Mezzoblue</a> version 4. Lots of things going on in this redesign. I could tell from reading his post and exploring the navigation that a lot has gone into the programing side of things. However, on the front end I think too much is going on. The color scheme works well but the style is confusing. I can&rsquo;t tell if he&rsquo;s shooting for the &ldquo;pixel&rdquo; style or something I haven&rsquo;t seen before. The navigation is different and nice. Everything contained in three tabs expanding into additional tabs that give corresponding information. Efficient way of stacking content into a small space. I also enjoy the reply <a href="http://mezzoblue.com/archives/2004/05/25/reply_highli/">highlighting</a>. The overall structure of the site is well thought out and well executed, however, more time needs to be spent on the purpose and meaning of the design elements.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.hillmancurtis.com/">Hillman Curtis</a> quoted Hemingway in an interview saying:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Write the story, take out all the good lines and see if the story still works. What he&rsquo;s saying is write your story. Take out all the fancy stuff. The stuff you think is so great. All the descriptions, all the adjectives, all the beautiful stuff; yank it all out of there. See if you have a story. The beauty of it for me, being a designer, is actually watching my design come to life as I pull stuff out, not add stuff in.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I reflect on this quote frequently throughout my design process to help gauge when I&rsquo;ve done too much or to little. I hope this critique helps in some way. I miss formal critiques and I plan on doing more.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Lapsang Souchong</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lapsang-souchong/"/><published>2004-05-17T21:26:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lapsang-souchong/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>This weekend was very rejuvenating. The weather was beautiful and the town was minus over 5,000 college students. <a href="http://www.missouristate.edu/">Campus</a> was a ghost town, perfect for a little amateur skateboarding. <a href="http://www.simplydowntown.com">Downtown</a> was pretty desolate as well. Sunny weather invited me to do some outdoor sketching at the square. I drove by my future apartment enough to give my soon-to-be neighbors the impression of a stalker. Added a new Black Tea to my collection called <a href="http://eat.epicurious.com/dictionary/food/index.ssf?DEF_ID=2468">Lapsang Souchong</a>, it smells like campfire.</p>
<p>That was my weeend, tell me about yours?</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Truth Beauty Power</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/truth-beauty-power/"/><published>2004-05-13T21:24:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/truth-beauty-power/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Recently I&rsquo;ve been reading <a href="http://tinyurl.com/ytgym">Studies In Design</a> by Christopher Dresser. The book was initially published in 1875 as an inspirational guide for designers. Dresser was most notable for his contributions to the Victorian era with his intricately designed textiles, furniture and ceramics. The following are passages I felt like sharing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Decorations, to be satisfying to the educated, must manifest knowledge&hellip; for unless the decoration is done wisely as well as with understanding , it may yet fail to please those who are best able to appreciate good ornament.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>In all attempts at the production of what is new, there is a danger of being extreme, eccentric, or unrefined.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Study, I say, whatever has gone before; not with the view of becoming a copyist, but with the object of gaining knowledge, and of seeking out general truths and broad principles, which will serve you as they have served the noble and good in times long past.</p>
<p>Dresser&rsquo;s inspiration can be seen in many <a href="http://www.squidfingers.com/patterns/">different</a> <a href="http://www.24-7media.de/ingram/">forms</a> of current works. I spent some time in Greenwich Village studying iron fence decorations that reflect the same victorian style Dresser pioneered.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Lukova Exhibition</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lukova-exhibition/"/><published>2004-05-10T21:24:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lukova-exhibition/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Recently <a href="http://lubalukova.home.att.net/LubaLukovaStudio.html">Luba Lukova</a> graced our local Art and Design Gallery with some of her current works and sketches. I&rsquo;ve always been a fan of her style and philosophy. She currently teaches at the <a href="http://www.schoolofvisualarts.edu/">School of Visual Arts</a> in Manhattan.</p>
<p>Her unique style focuses on metaphorical references, manipulation of the human form and she uses a very unique treatment of typography. I was able to snap some photos to share with you.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Quicksilver Revolution</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/quicksilver-revolution/"/><published>2004-05-08T21:22:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/quicksilver-revolution/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>As soon as I realized something was flirting with perfection I discover it gets even better. Over the past three years I&rsquo;ve experienced Mac OS X evolve into, in my opinion, the most effective operating system on the planet. This revolution has spawned many enhancing third party applications. After reading the hype about Quicksilver I finally gave it some <a href="http://whatdoiknow.org/archives/001601.shtml">attention</a>. Seconds after installing my jaw dropped.</p>
<p>I take my laptop everywhere and its my sole computer. I find it easier just to stay on one machine due to the enormous amount of stuff I use (files, music, movies, photos, bookmarks, apps, contacts). I try to stay organized, but I still spend time digging for things. Quicksilver amazingly eliminates most digging and puts everything at your fingertips.</p>
<p>After installing I set the interface to Bezel and then started typing. It quickly provides you with excellent results and still allows you to dig deeper if need be. You can customize the catalogue of searchable items to taylor results to your needs. It also searches your address book, itunes library, iphoto library, finder, and more. This is truly a time saver and something that has greatly enhanced my OS X experience. Quick, go download it it&rsquo;s open source and [FREE] (<a href="http://blacktree.com/apps/quicksilver/)">http://blacktree.com/apps/quicksilver/)</a>!</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Gleaming the Cube</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/gleaming-the-cube/"/><published>2004-05-06T19:37:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/gleaming-the-cube/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Recently I&rsquo;ve been brushing up on my skills as a skateboarder behind a local Italian Restaurant. It began in my friends basement when we found a beat up skateboard during a regular weekend gathering. This sparked our interest further so we ended up buying some generic boards from a local skate shop. They were black underneath and screaming for artwork.</p>
<p>Last weekend we bought some spray paint (hot pink is unbelievably hard to find) and mylar. I used the mylar to cut out a stencil that I had printed off and then we tapped that onto the bottom of the board and sprayed a few coats and presto.</p>
<p>Anyone know of a good health insurance plan?</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>A Modern Experience</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/a-modern-experience/"/><published>2004-05-03T21:17:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/a-modern-experience/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>The Guggenheim in Manhattan recently had an Exhibition entitled &ldquo;Singular Forms (Sometimes Repeated)&rdquo; Art from 1951 to the Present. Not your typical exhibition where you study lavish master works. The topic was Minimalism and, at first, I was somewhat timid; this being my virgin modernist exhibition. I began reading the blocks of text describing each piece while the people next too me stared hopelessly into blank canvases. I was fascinated.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&hellip;unique economy of formal means to explore the aesthetic potential of pure shape, structure, and surface. To annul all sense of illusion, artist associated with minimalism often relied on mathematical systems; manifested in serial repetition or the use of a grid; as a guiding compositional grid.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I briefly studied the Modernist movement in college, never giving it due attention. Many criticize this period as being meaningless or a waste of talent. I&rsquo;ve found it to be much more. The amount of thought and planning behind modern work is astonishing, inspiration stemming from obscure sources.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mangold would use the negative space of nature to create geometric forms.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Their purpose wasn&rsquo;t to satisfy viewers, it was the deconstruction of Art. Taking all that was familiar to art and dismantling it. Exposing its underpinnings. This was something that had not been done publicly. Similar too opening the back of a watch to reveal the complexity and simplicity behind the movement of three spinning hands on a circular form.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Minimalism&rsquo;s immediate impact upon development of contemporary art explored a range of concerns including process, the dematerialization of the object, the performative nature of art, and the structural properties of light.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This deconstruction is merely a process to better understand Art. The more an Artist understands the underpinnings of their creations, the better they can serve their purpose.</p>
<p>The following are Minimalist Artists that are worth understanding:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.guggenheimcollection.org/site/artist_bio_3.html">Carl Andre</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.guggenheimcollection.org/site/artist_bio_46.html">Dan Flavin</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.guggenheimcollection.org/site/artist_bio_97.html">Robert Mangold</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.guggenheimcollection.org/site/artist_bio_70.html">Donald Judd</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.guggenheimcollection.org/site/artist_bio_101.html">Brice Marden</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.guggenheimcollection.org/site/artist_bio_87A.html">Sol LeWitt</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.guggenheimcollection.org/site/artist_bio_103.html">Agnes Martin</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.guggenheimcollection.org/site/artist_bio_115.html">Robert Morris</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.guggenheimcollection.org/site/artist_bio_140.html">Robert Ryman</a></li>
</ul>
<p>All of the above quotes were taken from the &ldquo;Singular Forms&rdquo; Exhibition in the Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Back and Changed Forever</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/back-and-changed-forever/"/><published>2004-03-28T19:01:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/back-and-changed-forever/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en">
&lt;p>Back from Manhattan and feeling refreshed. Later this week I plan to post some photos and audio from the trip. Pending on how much stuff awaits me at work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some highlights include a group chat with Milton Glaser and Mirko Ilic, an exhibition by Christopher Dresser, East Village, Greenwich Village, SoHo, Fashion District, Upright Citizens Brigade, indy galleries, cafes in the morning, comic book and vintage book stores, walking with no direction, pizza and subway entertainment.&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>First Things First</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/first-things-first/"/><published>2004-03-19T19:30:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/first-things-first/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Lately I&rsquo;ve been pondering many questions regarding my place as a designer. I feel I may have lost sight of certain goals which have lead me to question my purpose. Design will always be my first love, however, I need to be true to that which I love.</p>
<p>I spent time last night rereading The <a href="http://www.adbusters.org/campaigns/first/toolbox/manifesto.pdf">First Things First Manifesto</a>. I recommend FTF to all designers, for it will stir up the same questions floating around in my head.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m leaving for Manhattan tomorrow for a week. I need a break and I need to clear my head. We&rsquo;re planning to visit <a href="http://www.karlssonwilker.com/">Karlson Wilker</a>, <a href="http://www.rga.com/">R/GA</a>, <a href="http://www.pentagram.com/">Pentagram</a>, <a href="http://www.miltonglaser.com/">Milton Glaser</a>, <a href="http://www.mirkoilic.com/">Mirko Ilic</a>, and as many <a href="http://www.whitney.org/">galleries</a> <a href="http://www.icp.org/">as</a> <a href="http://www.metmuseum.org/">we</a> <a href="http://www.moma.org/">have</a> <a href="http://www.guggenheim.org/new_york_index.shtml">time</a> <a href="http://ndm.si.edu/">for</a>.</p>
<p>Hopefully this experience will bring answers to my pondering, however, it might just bring more questions.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Kinetic Art</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kinetic-art/"/><published>2004-03-14T13:06:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kinetic-art/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Over the weekend I&rsquo;ve been preparing for my trip to Manhattan that is taking place next week. I&rsquo;ve been reading up on some new artists and refreshing myself on Art History because it makes the gallery and museum experience much more enjoyable when you have some knowledge behind what your looking at.</p>
<p>I came across one of my favorite artists that always seems to capture my attention. <a href="http://www.calder.org/">Alexander Calder&rsquo;s</a> mobiles are so fascinating to me and I always seem to stumble upon them in museums. Some really <a href="http://www.whitney.org/american_voices/541/index.html">small</a>, some so big they take up the entire entry way like the one in <a href="http://www.nga.gov/cgi-bin/pimage?56253+0+0">Washington D.C.&rsquo;s Museum of Contemporary Art</a>. Each of them related with very different personalities. They are always moving ever so softly through the stagnate museum air. Always changing shape and balance prompting me to stop dead in my tracks, mesmerized. Photos in books do these works no justice; they must be witnessed in person in order to fully feel their presents and infinite tango with the shadows.</p>
<p>Calder was really on to something. You can tell the heavy influence of <a href="http://www.guggenheimcollection.org/site/artist_works_112_0.html">Piet Mondrian</a>, another of my favorites.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>