<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2005/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2005-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Hear Me Purr</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2005/hear-me-purr/"/><published>2005-04-30T18:18:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/hear-me-purr/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Time to chim in on Tiger. Dashboard, Spotlight, Automator, Oh My! I was worried 
at first, things were slow and hard drive was crankin'. Once Spotlight finished 
indexing my mess of over six years of files I breathed a sigh of relief.</p>
<p>Apple has posted a handy little <a href="http://developer.apple.com/documentation/AppleApplications/Conceptual/Dashboard_Tutorial/index.html">Dashboard Programming Guide</a> 
with all sorts of design guidlines and API info. They have done the same for 
<a href="http://developer.apple.com/documentation/AppleApplications/Conceptual/AutomatorConcepts/index.html">Automator</a>. 
This little app can save scary amounts of time. BBEdit has realsed some nice 
<a href="http://www.apple.com/downloads/macosx/automator/bbeditautomatoractions.html">Actions</a> 
in 8.2. Spotlight is the girl I never had. Once you program yourself to press 
&ldquo;command-spacebar&rdquo; you&rsquo;ll never need that pesky finder dock icon. Still not sure 
what to say about Safari RSS, its crashed about five times now. WebKit is 
apparently much better but I have a feeling 10.4.1 will be a major bug fixer so 
some may want to wait a week or two.</p>
<p>While there is some new eye candy, Tiger is all about saving time and becoming 
more efficiant. Hopefully some of the philosophies will spill into other areas 
of work.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>PHP on Rails</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2005/php-on-rails/"/><published>2005-04-19T18:22:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/php-on-rails/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p><a href="http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/">Ruby</a> buzz has been making its rounds these last 
few months. I&rsquo;m anxious to use <a href="http://www.rubyonrails.com">Rails</a> but my ISP 
nor my employer support it. So I&rsquo;ve been stuck staring at the colorful lollypop 
from a distance.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.cakephp.com/">Cake</a> may be the solution to my problems, at least 
until Ruby becomes more widely supported. Cake is a PHP framework based on the 
Rails design. It&rsquo;s still in its infancy but it looks pretty solid. The developer 
has shown his commitment by releasing four updates in a row this month.</p>
<p><strong>UPDATE</strong> As of April 18th Cake has been updated to <a href="https://trac.cakephp.org/wiki/Cake/Download">0.2.7</a> with some nice new enhancements. 
There is now a code generator, however, it only works in Windows. This update 
also includes Flay (Textile like formating class), form generators, Folder 
class, and the beginnings of data validation with the Model using regular 
expressions.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>The Bands</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2005/the-bands/"/><published>2005-04-17T18:23:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/the-bands/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en">
&lt;p>The Faint, The Ataris, The Features, The Futureheads, The Cure, The Hives, The
Killers, The Music, The People, The Prodigy, The Roots, The Bravery, The Kills,
The Samples, The Shins, The Doors, The Stills, The Streets, The Strokes, The
Used, The Walkmen, The Darkness, The Who, The Ramones, The Sights, The National,
The Wrights, The Republic, The Congos, The Zincs, The Stix, The Perishers, The
Police, Rapture, The Unicorns, The Kinks, The Mollys, The Soviettes, The
Winners, The Velons, The Smugglers, The Makers, The Upsidedown, The Donnas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Did I forget anybody?&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>Selling Your Soul</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2005/selling-your-soul/"/><published>2005-04-13T18:23:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/selling-your-soul/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Lately I&rsquo;ve been going back and forth with my colleagues regarding pre-built 
admin tools. My position has been the benefits of adopting a framework outweigh 
any off-the-shelf tool.</p>
<p>What is the difference between a framework and an off-the-shelf system? It&rsquo;s 
like buying fake plants instead of real ones. off-the-shelf products leave very 
little wiggle room for growth and are inevitably more than what you need. They 
also exhibit poor usability, with there shiny plastic leaves and all.</p>
<p>A framework is the opposite. It&rsquo;s like having the pot, soil, and seeds. All you 
do is water and provide sunshine. This allows your tools to grow into the 
environment they are intended rather than trying to fit a square peg into a 
round hole. This also establishes a standard way of coding so when new 
programers come on board all they need to do is learn the framework and they&rsquo;re 
ready to roll.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rubyonrails.com">Ruby on Rails</a> is an example of a rising framework. 
<a href="http://www.phppatterns.com">PHP Patterns</a> also provide an enormous listing of 
design patterns that can be bundled together to create honest frameworks.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Soft Launch</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2005/soft-launch/"/><published>2005-04-12T18:24:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/soft-launch/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>This launch is softer than a baby&rsquo;s bum. Please excuse the possible broken 
links, sparse content, grayed out links, and unusually shaped big toe.</p>
<p>Things should be up to speed by the end of this week so keep checking back from 
time to time. Also, if you don&rsquo;t mind, I&rsquo;ll throw you a me update:</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m done photo blogging. It was fun while it lasted but I&rsquo;m out of good photos 
so back to writing. I&rsquo;ll continue keeping my <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sketch22/">Flicker account</a> stocked with shiny visuals. Still 
wondering the streets of Kansas City. Currently working on some cool projects 
that I can&rsquo;t wait to share <em>more on those later</em>. I&rsquo;ve been getting a lot of 
emails about Jupiter, my project management software. This has lead me to 
believe that I should finish that damn thing, soon. All is well for the most 
part.</p>
<p>The evolution of this site should be fun and interesting so stay tuned.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Broken Window Theory</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2005/broken-window-theory/"/><published>2005-04-08T18:25:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2005/broken-window-theory/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Lately I&rsquo;ve become a little obsessed with the &ldquo;Broken Window Theory.&rdquo; I was 
introduced to this theory by <a href="http://www.squidfingers.com">Travis</a> and <a href="http://www.alwayscurious.com">Charlie</a>. Soon after, it began popping into my head at 
work, home, or while I was coding. Then I started noticing it in <a href="http://www.gladwell.com/tippingpoint/">books</a> and on the <a href="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=4520866">radio</a>.</p>
<p>The theory is normally applied to urban decay and crime, however, it can be 
applied to almost anything. How did your apartment get so dirty? How did your 
code get out of control? Well, it&rsquo;s all because of one sock, one poorly placed 
if statement, or one broken window.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>One broken window, left unrepaired for any substantial length of time, instills 
a sense of abandonment — a sense that the powers that be don&rsquo;t care. So another 
window gets broken. People start littering. Graffiti appears. Serious structural 
damage begins. In a relativly short space of time, the structure becomes damaged 
beyond the desire to fix it, and the sense of abandonment becomes reality.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The preceding quote was taken from <a href="http://www.pragmaticprogrammer.com/ppbook/">The Pragmatic Programmer</a> by Andrew Hunt and David Thomas. It 
basically means watch out for the small stuff. If you can keep the tiny cracks 
out early they won&rsquo;t turn into gorges. The hope is that if your projects are 
pristine and another person is invited to change or update something they will 
take notice in its perfection and not want to be the first to break a window.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>