<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2007/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2014-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Austin bound</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/austin-bound/"/><published>2007-03-08T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/austin-bound/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;m headed to Austin, Texas today to partake in the South by Southwest
festivities. The panel linup this year looks scrumptious. Unlike my pal Jeff
(<a href="http://www2.jeffcroft.com/blog/2007/mar/01/where-find-me-sxsw/)">http://www2.jeffcroft.com/blog/2007/mar/01/where-find-me-sxsw/)</a>, I have no idea
what I&rsquo;ll be attending. I will, however, be attending as many evening parties as
I can possibly stumble into. I&rsquo;ll definitely be attending the AMODA
(<a href="http://www.amoda.org/">http://www.amoda.org/</a>) Digital Showcase, which was fantastic last year, and the
Austin On Rails Happy Hour sporting my Django (<a href="http://www.djangoproject.com">http://www.djangoproject.com</a>)
shirt no less. I also highly recommend Drinks with Lifehacker, those dudes know
how to party.</p>
<p>Hope to see some of you there. If we&rsquo;ve never met don&rsquo;t hesitate to introduce
yourself. My SXSW Flickr stream (<a href="http://flickr.com/photos/sketch22/sets/72157594576670321/">http://flickr.com/photos/sketch22/sets/72157594576670321/</a>)
should be dripping with nightly photos or join the Flickr pool (<a href="http://www.flickr.com/groups/sxswi2007/)">http://www.flickr.com/groups/sxswi2007/)</a>.</p>
<p>Oh yeah, if I see any of you at the Happy Hour Sponsored by Microsoft Expression
Studio, I may have to hurt you.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Rating system breakdown</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/rating-system-breakdown/"/><published>2007-03-05T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/rating-system-breakdown/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I wanna discuss rating systems for a bit. From what I gather there are three
flavors: a simple &ldquo;one vote&rdquo; method, a thumbs up or down, and the scale. Each
solutions goal is to find out what people think of your content. This is helpful
when trying to understand your audience.</p>
<h1 id="the-one-vote-method">The &ldquo;one vote&rdquo; method</h1>
<p>As simple as it gets. If someone likes a piece of content they simply click a
button saying so. Nothing more nothing less. This is a visceral response, a
&ldquo;blink&rdquo; reaction which requires minimal thought. The downside is you can&rsquo;t infer
that a non-vote means people dislike content. A non-vote most likely means they
didn&rsquo;t read the content enough to care which could suggest weak content but it&rsquo;s
a little grey.</p>
<h1 id="thumbs-up-thumbs-down">Thumbs up, thumbs down</h1>
<p>This one makes me think of Siskel and Ebert and their black and white critiques
of film.  Probably the most widely used style because of its simplicity. Like
the &ldquo;one vote&rdquo; method, it relies on gut reactions but allows people to express
their dislike for a piece of content. The style sometimes borrows the
visualization side of the scale system below.</p>
<h1 id="scale">Scale</h1>
<p>Frequently represented as stars, we commonly see this method used along with
reviews and entertainment ratings. This system requires the most amount of
thought from a person which often leads to poor return. It&rsquo;s best used in
situations where a person is investing time into writing a review.</p>
<h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h1>
<p>Implementing a rating system isn&rsquo;t for the faint of heart. You need to be
comfortable with powers of online democracy. Oddly enough rating systems are
why Google works. They&rsquo;re Page Rank system is based almost entirely on the
&ldquo;one vote&rdquo; method where a link from one site to another stands as a &ldquo;vote.&rdquo;
&ldquo;Democracy on the web works.&quot;](<a href="http://www.google.com/corporate/tenthings.html">http://www.google.com/corporate/tenthings.html</a>)
This can be seen on Newsvine, Digg, Delicious, Flickr, and more.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Playground is back</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/playground-is-back/"/><published>2007-02-28T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/playground-is-back/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>With every rendition of my person site I must emphasize that this is a work in
progress. With that said, welcome to my new playground. Sorry about the neurotic
name changes. I can assure you they are over and I&rsquo;m pretty darn happy with the
new digs.</p>
<h2 id="why-redesign">Why redesign?</h2>
<p>I wanted to return to my roots. I started out as Playground Blues and this is
where I belong. I also wanted something with room to grow. Something that had
lots of drawers and cubby holes for me to put random bits. As much as I love
structure and organization, taxonomies and folksonomies; I wanted to be able to
throw things out there, like little easter eggs. This design lets me do just
that.</p>
<h2 id="to-be-expected">To be expected.</h2>
<p>Don&rsquo;t expect anything from me. It&rsquo;s better that way. I can only surprise you from
here on out. My hopes are that you&rsquo;ll begin to see more of those ?&rsquo;s disappear.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m really excited about this new direction. I hope too see some of you in
Austin at this years South by Southwest!</p>
<p>Update: Here&rsquo;s the Photoshop (<a href="http://playgroundblues.com/media/source/playground-blues.zip">http://playgroundblues.com/media/source/playground-blues.zip</a>)
for this design. Feel free to remix and play.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Easing into Leopard</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/easing-into-leopard/"/><published>2007-01-11T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/easing-into-leopard/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;m a UI geek and the first thing I noticed during the iPhone demo was how fun scrolling seems. With small devices and even regular sized computers a majority of our time is spent scrolling various collections of content. Only a company like Apple can step back, recognize this, and make it fun. This will no doubt engage users, bringing them closer to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)">flow</a>.</p>
<p>Easing has been around a long time. I remember learning how to do it in Flash with the aid of <a href="http://www.joshuadavis.com/">Joshua Davis</a>. You could fling that scroll bar right across the screen and have to bounce right back. Then <a href="http://www.robertpenner.com/">Robert Penner</a> made everyones life easier with his ubiquitous easing equations.</p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t help but imagine this new iPhone UI hinted at a lot of what we&rsquo;ll be seeing in Leopard. I don&rsquo;t know if everyone would want easing in Leopard but, if done right, it could bring to life a hella fun interface. It might also help some of us that design huge content sites :)</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>