<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2004-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Indy Support</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/indy-support/"/><published>2004-03-04T13:08:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/indy-support/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Recently I&rsquo;ve been distancing myself from &ldquo;corporate america.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s impossible to completely do unless your <a href="http://www.crimelibrary.com/terrorists_spies/terrorists/kaczynski/1.html">Ted Kaczynski</a> but even he had to buy stamps. (Now I&rsquo;m going to get weird Google referrals on Ted Kaczynski). Anyway, I have good reason for choosing this direction.</p>
<p>My family has a history of entrepreneurs that range from a Grandfather that sold &ldquo;Nimrods&rdquo; to a mom that makes and sells women&rsquo;s clothing. This compels me to spend an extra dollar here and there in support of other entrepreneurs. I highly respect what they do and hope to be one myself someday.</p>
<p>I value the atmosphere and uniqueness of indy shops. More and more &ldquo;corporate&rdquo; businesses are turning to <a href="http://www.apple.com/retail/">cookie cutter</a> designs for their establishments. This is somewhat disheartening, however, I understand why they do it. Consistency helps them but also dulls them. Yesterday I walked into a local cafe to grab coffee before work; some great jazz was playing in the background that set the mood for the rest of my day. Today I bought a <a href="http://www.noisefactoryrecords.com/bss.htm">CD</a> at a local record store and got some info on new bands from the owner. I also visited a new clothing boutique with some really unique clothing that you wouldn&rsquo;t find anywhere else in this city. During all these experiences I&rsquo;m greeted by familiar, helpful people.</p>
<p>Independent businesses not only provides quality products, great people and unique atmospheres; they also have the ability enrich our lives.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Not So Lucky</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/not-so-lucky/"/><published>2004-02-25T19:17:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/not-so-lucky/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>In response to my good friend <a href="http://www.justwatchthesky.com">Ryan&rsquo;s</a> entry on 
iTunes I&rsquo;d just like to say I haven&rsquo;t won a single song with that Pepsi promo. 
I guess it&rsquo;s just bad luck or I just don&rsquo;t drink enough Pepsi. I bought a Sierra 
Mist today and thought for sure I&rsquo;d win but instead I was presented with &ldquo;Please 
try again.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Anyone want a first generation iPod? I&rsquo;m selling it for 50 bucks, 75 with an 
iTrip. Works just fine, I just need a larger one.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Lack of Words</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lack-of-words/"/><published>2004-02-14T19:16:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/lack-of-words/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>If you&rsquo;ve noticed I&rsquo;ve been pretty lame with my entries lately. Mainly due to 
<a href="http://www.neubix.com/">work</a>, <a href="http://www.smsu.edu/">work</a> and freelance work. 
Good things are around the corner so bare with me. In the mean time I&rsquo;ve come 
across some good reads:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.kottke.org/04/02/innovation">If it ain&rsquo;t broke, don&rsquo;t fix it?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://zeldman.com/daily/0204h.shtml">Drop Shadow League</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mezzoblue.com/archives/2004/02/23/understandin/">Understanding Design</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>So Many Chairs</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/so-many-chairs/"/><published>2004-02-08T19:14:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/so-many-chairs/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I want to talk about style. What does it really mean? How do you get it? Does it 
really matter? I mainly just want to further my understanding of style by 
writing down some thoughts and ideas. <strong>Warning! The following is 
completely opinionated.</strong></p>
<h3 id="what-does-style-mean">What does style mean?</h3>
<p>It means you&rsquo;ve carved out a niche where you can be easily recognizable. People 
seek you for your ability to look a particular way. Sort of like wearing Banana 
Republic because you like smooth sleek colors and fabrics. Or eating Mexican 
food for the spicy entrees.</p>
<h3 id="how-do-you-attain-style">How do you attain style?</h3>
<p>I don&rsquo;t really know. It&rsquo;s like saying how do you find love? Some say love finds 
you, well, maybe style finds you. I would like to think this quest involves hard 
work, research and dedication. However, I&rsquo;m sure that alone doesn&rsquo;t provide you 
with a unique style. It&rsquo;s almost like pacing around a large room with many 
different types of chairs. Some exotic looking, some very simplistic. Every now 
and then you have a seat, paying close attention to how it feels, looks and 
functions. Then you move to the next. Over time you learn about all the chairs 
in the room and begin to build your very own where you can finally sit with 
comfort and assurance. At least thats my guess.</p>
<h3 id="does-having-a-style-really-matter">Does having a style really matter?</h3>
<p>No, not really. In some instances it hinders you because your confining 
yourself. If a company or firm is recognized for their style it can hinder them 
more because they become known for that style in the industry and risk being 
pushed to the curb. If you look at companies like <a href="http://www.sagmeister.com/">Sagmeister Inc.</a>, <a href="http://www.weworkforthem.com">Weworkforthem</a> and 
<a href="http://www.cyclone-design.com/">Cyclone Design</a> they are highly recognized by 
their great styles. Eventually three more companies will come along with fresh 
new styles that attract attention and they&rsquo;ll be flavor of the week. If you look 
at companies like <a href="http://www.pentagram.com">Pentagram</a>, <a href="http://www.rga.com">R/GA</a> and <a href="http://www.hallmark.com">Hallmark</a> that have stood the 
test of time; you&rsquo;ll see they don&rsquo;t really have a style. They have an eclectic 
collection of designers that create solutions that evolve with time.</p>
<p>Personally I stay away from locking myself in a style. If it happens to find me 
later on in life I&rsquo;ll probably be ok but at this point I&rsquo;m still testing out all 
the chairs.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Wireless Revolution</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/wireless-revolution/"/><published>2004-02-05T19:13:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/wireless-revolution/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>In my quest to eliminate wires I purchased the <a href="http://www.bluetooth.com/">Apple Bluetooth</a> Pro Mouse. It&rsquo;s a very charming piece of hardware. 
I&rsquo;ve already gone through two of the regular Apple Pro mice. I have a tendency 
of wrapping the cord around the mouse when I&rsquo;m &ldquo;on the go&rdquo; and eventually the 
wire inside breaks. However they&rsquo;ve been good to me and so far I&rsquo;ve been very 
pleased with the Bluetooth derivative. I&rsquo;ve noticed when I&rsquo;m transferring large 
amounts of data over our <a href="http://www.warchalking.org/">WiFi</a> at <a href="http://www.neubix.com">work</a> the mouse becomes really jumpy. I guess this is too be 
expected with a wireless device? Other than that it&rsquo;s performed wonderfully.</p>
<p>All thats left is bluetooth headphones (Apple please come out with some) and a 
way to power my laptop cordlessly&hellip; (I can only dream).</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>The Reading Trail</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/the-reading-trail/"/><published>2004-02-04T19:12:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/the-reading-trail/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;ll be finishing up the Da Vinci Code tonight. Once thats over I&rsquo;m going to get 
back on the learning train. Cutting back on entertainment television, movies and 
other distractions. Time to get down to business.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve decided to sharpen my skills as an Information Architect. I&rsquo;ve always 
enjoyed the organization of large amounts of data and felt like I was pretty 
good at it. However, I feel there is much more to learn.</p>
<p>My first selection will be a classic, The Visual Display of Quantitative 
Information by Edward R. Tufte. Scientific American describes it as, &ldquo;original, 
beautifully presented, sharp and learned, this book is a work of art. The art 
here is cognitive art, the graphic display of relations and empirical data, now 
an indispensable tool of science and engineering.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll be sure to post a review when I&rsquo;m finished.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Monster</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/monster/"/><published>2004-01-26T12:58:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/monster/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>This weekend I went to see Monster. I saw the preview and sort of knew what I was getting myself into. It wasn&rsquo;t going to be an uplifting movie but I could tell these people had something to say. Some parts were hard to digest and some really made me question how I treat and view other people. It&rsquo;s a movie that needs to be scene with an open mind and heart. Charlize Theron deserves high recognition for pouring her soul into this film.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Just Do It</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/just-do-it/"/><published>2004-01-04T12:55:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/just-do-it/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>One of my most influential <a href="http://art.smsu.edu/peophtm/kosto.htm">professors</a> from college would always say, &ldquo;Just do it!&rdquo; in his thick Bosnian accent during sketch critiques. I&rsquo;m not sure whether he was saying it before <a href="http://www.nikelab.com">Nike</a> but recently I&rsquo;ve been trying to &ldquo;just do it.&rdquo;</p>
<p>We all have these lists of things we want to do in life. Things we want to <a href="http://www.risd.edu">accomplish</a>, <a href="http://www.actionscript.org">practice</a>, <a href="http://www.propellerhead.se/">learn</a>, <a href="http://www.bugeurope.com/">experience</a>. We recall the list in our day dreams but loose sight of how easy it is to &ldquo;just do it.&rdquo; Then we come up with excuses and reasons why it&rsquo;s impossible to &ldquo;just do it&rdquo; or decide it&rsquo;s not the right time to &ldquo;just do it.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Recently I&rsquo;ve been trying to abolish some of my brick walls that prevent me to &ldquo;just do it.&rdquo; I started this weekend by purchasing a keyboard. I&rsquo;ve always wanted to experiment with playing and creating music. Once I get a MIDI converter for my laptop and pending I start to sound good :) I&rsquo;ll post some of my creations in the Lab.</p>
<p>Good luck with your wall demolition.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>