<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2004-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Wireless Lack</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/wireless-lack/"/><published>2004-07-04T13:11:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/wireless-lack/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Today my coffee house was closed for the holiday. If you could only see the look on my face. It seems to be the only downside to holidays. This didn&rsquo;t detour me from finding a hotspot that provided legally addictive &ldquo;stimulants.&rdquo;</p>
<p>After much driving my choices were narrowed down to Starbucks and Panera. Starbucks uses T-mobile for wifi which costs money so I chose Panera with its free wifi provided by <a href="http://www.goqgo.com/">QGO</a>.</p>
<p>After realizing this isn&rsquo;t the crowd I&rsquo;m used too I found a nice little spot in the corner to get down to business. I was first presented with a Panera screen in my browser asking me to agree with its Wi-Fi Terms. After reading over the four page document and knowing that all rights to privacy will be infringed upon I clicked Agree and went on my way. I must note, this is the first time I&rsquo;ve had to do this ever, anywhere. I hear its the same way at Starbucks but I&rsquo;ve grown accustom to independent shops that don&rsquo;t care what you do while respecting your privacy.</p>
<p>Needless to say Panera&rsquo;s wifi is very slow and, privacy aside, not worth it due to their lack of coffee making abilities. I hope more free hotspots open up. I&rsquo;ve never understood why places charge for wifi, it&rsquo;s very cheep for the store to provide and attracts customers.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Far from Modest</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/far-from-modest/"/><published>2004-07-03T19:21:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/far-from-modest/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Has anyone else really listened to the lyrics on the new Modest Mouse album? For lack of better words, they&rsquo;re amazing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The moths beat themselves to death against the lights.
Adding their breeze to the summer nights.
Outside water like air was great.
I didn&rsquo;t know what I had that day.
Walk a little farther to another plan.
You said that you did, but you didn&rsquo;t understand.
— The World At Large</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many of them take on religious themes and provoke thought regarding life and death.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If God controls the land and disease,
keeps a watchful eye on me,
If he&rsquo;s really so damn mighty,
my problem is I can&rsquo;t see,
well who would wanna be?
Who would wanna be such a control freak?
— Bukowski</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Well that is that and this is this.
Will you tell me what you saw and I&rsquo;ll tell you what you missed,
when the ocean met the sky.
You missed when time on life shook hands and said goodbye.
When the earth folded in on itself.
And said &ldquo;Good luck, for your sake I hope heaven and hell
are really there, but I wouldn&rsquo;t hold my breath.&rdquo;
You wasted life, why wouldn&rsquo;t you waste death?
— Ocean Breathes Salty</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some are just ironically uplifting.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Well, a fake Jamaican took every last dime with a scam
It was worth it just to learn from sleight-of-hand
Bad news comes don&rsquo;t you worry even when it lands
Good news will work its way to all them plans
We both got fired on exactly the same day
Well we&rsquo;ll float on good news is on the way.
— Float On</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And some are just eerily true.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>For every invention made how much time did we save?
We&rsquo;re not much farther that we were in the cave.
— The View</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It&rsquo;s one thing to have an album with great beats and rhythms but it&rsquo;s another to have rich, thought provoking lyrics. This is just the tip of the iceberg. [Modest Mouse]((<a href="http://www.modestmouse.com/">http://www.modestmouse.com/</a>) put something really powerful out there. Good News For People Who Love Bad News will instigate pondering and keep your foot tapping.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Kottke Critique</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kottke-critique/"/><published>2004-06-29T19:05:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kottke-critique/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p><a href="http://www.kottke.org/about">Jason Kottke</a> recently released the next 
incarnation of <a href="http://www.kottke.org">Kottke.org</a>. I must say, even though 
visually things are very similar to the previous version, Jason has done an 
excellent job of perfecting his structure and usability.</p>
<p>Jason&rsquo;s text dominant design reminds us of the power of typography. His subtle 
choices of font sizes, weights, leading and link color are methodically chosen 
along with simple dividers to create a harmonious feel. From the looks of things 
the famous green header has been on the Atkins diet. It may have slimmed up a 
bit but it&rsquo;s just enough to remind you, This Is Kottke.</p>
<p>Kottke tweaked the two column layout, widening the left column a bit. I&rsquo;ve 
always enjoyed the way Jason nestles his daily links into his blog column. This 
works exceptionally well from a usability standpoint and gives the links more 
attention in the hierarchy.</p>
<p>From the comments form (<a href="http://www.kottke.org/remainder/04/06/5909.html">http://www.kottke.org/remainder/04/06/5909.html</a>) to the 
photo gallery (<a href="http://www.kottke.org/photos/highline0204/index.html">http://www.kottke.org/photos/highline0204/index.html</a>) and beyond 
you can tell that a lot of care and thought went into every element of this 
redesign. Well done Jason, take a bow.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Fragile Sunday</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/fragile-sunday/"/><published>2004-06-27T19:35:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/fragile-sunday/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Sunday&rsquo;s are supposed to invite rest and relaxation, however, this was like no other Sunday I anticipated. Saturday evening was great. I stumbled upon a public showing of Waking Life in an old art studio downtown. We enjoyed tea and sat on a variety of vintage chairs watching one of my favorite films. Afterwards I was feeling very reflective and philosophical so I read some and went to bed early.</p>
<p>Around 4:22am my ears caught the sound of rain. I lay there enjoying the drops hitting my window hoping it would only add to my already adventurous dream. Something wasn&rsquo;t quite right, the rain was very sporadic. My eyes opened to a bright orange filled room. I glanced at my clock, 4:23am. Sun doesn&rsquo;t rise this early, nor does it shine through my north window. Decided to peak through my blinds only to be presented with hellish flames swallowing the building thirty feet away from me. Fear, only to be overcome by panic. What do I grab? Where are my pants, shoes, glasses? Grab film negatives, laptop and the first camera you see. Bolting for the door I said a quick goodbye to my apartment just in case. Seven fire engines, dozens of Springfield&rsquo;s finest firefighters, and gallons of water later the fire subsided. By the graces of god all twenty one residents were safe with no injuries. My building, amazingly unscathed. The same couldn&rsquo;t be said for my neighbors.</p>
<p>As they salvage their charred homes with boxes from the Red Cross, hoping to find those few untouched items I can&rsquo;t help but think how fragile we are. Lives weren&rsquo;t lost but they are changed.</p>
<p>The cause was attributed to a single cigarette. Astonishing how such a small item of bad habit can disrupt and endanger the lives of innocent people. I&rsquo;m moving to a new apartment soon and I plan to purchase a fire extinguisher, renters insurance, learn more about gas stoves and equip every room with a smoke/carbon monoxide detector. Thank you Firefighters, Red Cross and Police. We are indebted to the extraordinary service and care you provide.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Someone Find The Cat</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/someone-find-the-cat/"/><published>2004-06-26T19:04:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/someone-find-the-cat/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Why do we still have mice? Seriously, haven&rsquo;t we reached the point in computer 
evolution where we can discard the mouse completely? <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/">Modern operating systems</a> have the ability to solely rely on voice 
commands, pen devices and touch screens. Why is it taking us so long to rid 
ourselves of a device that is responsible for such a <a href="http://familydoctor.org/023.xml">painful syndrome</a>.</p>
<p>Mice are a thing of the past, much like CRT monitors, parallel ports, walkmans 
and even the compact disc. It&rsquo;s time to let go, look to the future of usability 
and functionality. For regular users (i.e. email, word processing, chatting, 
etc.) the absence of the mouse would be an easier transition, however, the 
utilization of a pen device would have to be retained for web browsing and other 
tasks that utilize buttons or links too small for fingers to press.</p>
<p>I believe that direct interaction with a surface that provides feedback can be a 
very positive experience for the user. You become more involved in the activity 
at hand rather than indirectly moving a mouse around and arbitrarily clicking. I 
long for the day when my sketchbook uploads to my laptop, logging my daily ideas 
where I can call them up based on day, keywords, project or mood.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Textpattern Flow</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/textpattern-flow/"/><published>2004-06-23T19:03:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/textpattern-flow/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;d like to pose a question to my readers that use Textpattern. Last week I 
noticed <a href="http://www.hicksdesign.co.uk">Jon Hicks</a> switched over which sparked my 
interest. I&rsquo;ve been meaning to switch over to a PHP based system for a while and 
from what I&rsquo;ve seen <a href="http://www.textpattern.com">Textpattern</a> is very nice. One 
of my issues is how to structure my content using the Section, Category, Page, 
etc. method that Textpattern uses. Can anyone out there provide an example or 
input on how they achieved a solid architecture?</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Rise of the Documentary</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/rise-of-the-documentary/"/><published>2004-06-06T21:39:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/rise-of-the-documentary/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;ve always been a connoisseur of documentary film and rarely do I read fiction opposed to non-fiction. Learning about the actions and habits of society, whether opinionated or not, has always intrigued me. It appears documentary film is rising in popularity. Not surprising due to the rise of Reality TV, they fit right in. Documentaries have allowed those with a story and small voice to speak 
aloud. Unfortunately, unless you live in a big city you may never get a chance to listen. Some documentaries on the horizon include:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/trailers/independent/mayorofthesunsetstrip.html">Mayor of the Sunset Strip</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/trailers/independent/the_agronomist.html">The Agronomist</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.fahrenheit911.com/">Fahrenheit 9/11</a></li>
<li><a href="http://supersizeme.com/">Super Size Me</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thecorporation.tv/trailer/">The Corporation</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/trailers/sony/winged_migration.html">Winged Migration</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="some-past-favorites">Some past favorites:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/trailers/sony/thefogofwar.html">Fog of War</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/trailers/mgm/bowling_for_columbine/">Bowling for Columbine</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/trailers/newline/american_splendor/">American Splendor</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/trailers/miramax/comedian.html">The Comedian</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/JackieBehindtheMyth-1092283/preview.php">Jackie: Behind the Myth</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Flipping Zines</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/flipping-zines/"/><published>2004-06-06T19:33:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/flipping-zines/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;ve got a bone to pick with design magazines. I used to buy them frequently based on issue topics. I never subscribe, mainly because I don&rsquo;t want to confine myself to one magazine; sounds weird, deal with it. I haven&rsquo;t purchased any new issues in about four months due to the overwhelming amount of advertisements. No-longer can you &ldquo;flip&rdquo; through these magazines without getting stuck on paper company ads or booklets on Adobe. The great importance of advertising is understood, however, I just find the current state of ads intrusive to my magazine reading experience. Also noticed is increased diluted content and for 
these reasons I have ceased my consumption of <a href="http://www.howdesign.com">HOW</a>, <a href="http://www.commarts.com">Communication Arts</a>, <a href="http://www.printmag.com/">Print</a> 
and <a href="http://www.stepinsidedesign.com">Step</a>.</p>
<p>Until they redeem themselves I&rsquo;m filling my &ldquo;flipping&rdquo; void with <a href="http://www.res.com/">Res</a>, <a href="http://www.thewire.co.uk/">Wire</a>, <a href="http://tokion.com/">Tokion</a>, <a href="http://www.wadmag.com/">Wad</a>, <a href="http://www.idnworld.com/">Idn</a>, <a href="http://www.colorsmagazine.com/">Colors</a> and <a href="http://www.metropolismag.com/">Metropolis</a>. These selections aren&rsquo;t solely devoted to design but I&rsquo;ve found reading about film, music, culture, fashion, art, and architecture to be much more inspiring.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Stopdesign Critique</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/stopdesign-critique/"/><published>2004-06-06T19:03:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/stopdesign-critique/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I felt like revisiting Douglas Bowman&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.stopdesign.com/">Stopdesign</a> 
since my previous critique was premature. Douglas did a fine job on many fronts. 
The architecture is a three column joy. Strategic attention was given to the 
front page where a great deal of content is displayed without overloading your 
eye. The subtle use of color to distinguish a hierarchy makes this possible. As 
you dig deeper content expands to a two column layout. The right bar is like a 
companion at your side always informing you of relevant and/or alternate links.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always been a fan of iconography. Douglas does a fine job at paying close 
attention to icons that not only add detail but inform. It&rsquo;s very important to 
have a method or reason behind everything and his icons express whether you&rsquo;re 
about to view a document, comment, click away or click into the site.</p>
<p>With each section there is a drastically different look utilizing blurred images 
and color, however the structure stays consistent. I&rsquo;ve heard some say this is 
too drastic and it&rsquo;s hard for me to decide. I enjoy the distinct difference 
between the <a href="http://www.stopdesign.com/portfolio/">portfolio</a> and the <a href="http://www.stopdesign.com/log/">log</a>. It bluntly informs you these are completely 
different sections and could act alone. This shows versatility and it&rsquo;s 
something you don&rsquo;t expect which can be startling but in the long run, 
effective.</p>
<p>Well done Mr. Bowman. Take a bow.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Gmail Big Brother</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/gmail-big-brother/"/><published>2004-06-01T21:37:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/gmail-big-brother/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;ve been wondering what angle Google planned to take with its new Gmail service, currently in beta form. After <a href="http://news.com.com/Google%27s+Web+mail+no+joke/2100-1032_3-5184090.html?tag=st.rn">some</a> 
<a href="http://democrats.sen.ca.gov/servlet/gov.ca.senate.democrats.pub.members.memDisplayPress?district=sd10&amp;amp;ID=2102">reading</a> it all makes perfect sense. Google will offer 1GB of email space in return for the ability to scan your messages and place <a href="http://fury.com/article/1990.php">ads</a> based on the content. After the excitement of 1GB wears, I&rsquo;m starting to wonder if the trade off is morally right?</p>
<p>Example: I receive an email regarding a relatives grave health problems; to the right ads are displayed regarding funeral homes. However, it could be helpful if your corresponding with a friend regarding your cars transmission and ads relating to car repair are provided.</p>
<p>From the personal privacy perspective it&rsquo;s a bit intrusive but if machines are performing the intrusion I feel somewhat at ease. Google is an amazing phenomenon and has an exciting future ahead. I&rsquo;m anxious to see how Gmail pans out.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>