<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2004-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Double the Pleasure</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/double-the-pleasure/"/><published>2004-11-07T19:19:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/double-the-pleasure/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Last night two new albums pitched a tent  on my &ldquo;oh my god&rdquo; list of music. <a href="http://www.thefaint.com">The Faint</a> &ldquo;Wet From Birth&rdquo; and <a href="http://www.officialtomwaits.com">Tom Waits</a> &ldquo;Real Gone&rdquo; are so unbelievably necessary I don&rsquo;t even know why you&rsquo;re still reading. Go get them!</p>
<p>The Faint marches forward with its sexy themes and lucius lyrics. My 
uncertainties about how they would top <em>Blank-Wave Arcade</em> were shattered by the first track and continued to crumble through track two until they were disintegrated with &ldquo;Southern Belles in London Sing.&rdquo; Each track presents a unique personality ranging from violin accompaniment to a melodic choir of female vocals. Plus you can&rsquo;t beat an album that has a song entitled &ldquo;Erection.&rdquo; (no pun intended).</p>
<p>As for Mr. Waits&hellip; Waits challenges the human ear with his contorted vocals and crafted percussion. <em>Real Gone</em> takes you on an unforgettable journey of bizarre scenarios none of which are completely comprehendible. Light a cigar, pour some whisky, press play and put a note on the door, &ldquo;Real Gone.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Kansas City Migration</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kansas-city-migration/"/><published>2004-11-06T12:59:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/kansas-city-migration/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;ve successfully migrated to Downtown Kansas City from Springfield. It took about a week to get all my stuff in order and my mind is catching up.</p>
<p>Tried Middle Eastern food for the first time, go Gyros! If you haven&rsquo;t had Chile Relleno I suggest you dart to a good Mexican restaurant and give it a taste.</p>
<p>The First Friday Art Walk happened to be last friday. <a href="http://www.hammerpress.net">Hammerpress</a> unveiled their Christmas collection. The work is top notch. If you haven&rsquo;t flipped the newest <a href="http://www.printmag.com">Print Mag</a> I suggest you earmark Missouri, watch out <a href="http://gigposters.com/designers.php?designer">Art Chantry</a>.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Yo La Weekend</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/yo-la-weekend/"/><published>2004-10-04T13:01:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/yo-la-weekend/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>This weekend I saw <a href="http://www.yolatengo.com">Yo La Tengo</a> for the first time in Kansas City. Definitely worth the bones if they&rsquo;re in your area. Amazing jams and a really hot drummer girl. If you&rsquo;re not familiar with them I recommend first getting &ldquo;I Can Hear the Heart Beating as One&rdquo; and then &ldquo;Summer Sun.&rdquo; If your hooked you&rsquo;ll also like &ldquo;And Then Nothing Turned Itself Inside-Out.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Also did a little apartment hunting before I begin playing/working with the <a href="http://www.alwayscurious.com">fine</a> <a href="http://www.squidfingers.com">lads</a> at <a href="http://www.lookandfeel.com">Look and Feel</a>. I&rsquo;m very excited and I&rsquo;m sure I&rsquo;ll have many adventures to post in the coming months ;)</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Rip Alvin iPod</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/rip-alvin-ipod/"/><published>2004-09-29T19:23:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/rip-alvin-ipod/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Today is a sad day. I went for a bike ride downtown and in a moment of 
braveness, tragedy struck. After making a successful jump from a very large curb 
a sense of accomplishment ended when my pedal clipped the curb halting my bike 
and catapulting me through the air. The silence that followed seemed to be more 
painful than my bleeding arm.</p>
<p>Alvin was a good iPod. The first generation of his time. He provided me with listening pleasure and 
inspiration through many important moments during the past two and a half years. 
One of my favorite moments was when I got lost in East Village, Manhattan. Never 
once did I feel scared because Alvin always kept me in <a href="http://www.brokensocialscene.com/">good spirits</a>. I will miss you Alvin iPod. Rest in peace 
my good friend. Oh, <a href="http://www.griffintechnology.com/products/itrip/">iTrip</a> 
says goodbye too.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>More Adventurous</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/more-adventurous/"/><published>2004-09-28T19:23:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/more-adventurous/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>About a year ago a friend of mine introduced me to a little world called <a href="http://www.rilokiley.com">Rilo 
Kiley</a>. Her two albums, &ldquo;Execution of All Things&rdquo; and 
&ldquo;Takeoffs and Landings&rdquo;, bring sunshine to a rainy day and lift you up to a 
place not often visited through music. Jenny Lewis&rsquo;s voice never seems to grow 
old. They&rsquo;re songs are so diverse and colorful.</p>
<p>I honestly didn&rsquo;t believe they could top their last two releases. &ldquo;More 
Adventurous&rdquo; proves me wrong and lives up to its name. The only way to describe 
it is if you took a petal from each of your favorite flowers and pasted them all 
together creating a colleague of fragrance. You can hear a little bit of the 
past, present and get a gimps of the future. This band has a lot of potential 
and definitely worth experiencing.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Jupiter</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/jupiter/"/><published>2004-09-26T19:22:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/jupiter/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;d like to introduce a new project of mine. It&rsquo;s called Jupiter. Jupiter is a 
project management solution that began August 1, 2004 after heavy research. 
Roughly two months of ironing out the database scheme and functionality I&rsquo;m 
ready to get feedback and suggestions. Keep in mind things are in the beginning 
stages and this is by no means a finished/polished product.</p>
<p>I was planning to provide a run down of all the bells and whistles but I think I 
would rather get everyones first impressions and go from there. So here we go:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://jupiter.playgroundblues.com">jupiter.playgroundblues.com</a></li>
<li>Login: demo</li>
<li>Password: demo</li>
</ul>
<p>Feel free to add projects, notes, milestones, tasks or files. Mess around with 
it as much as you can. Let me know what you love, hate, or wish existed.</p>
<p><strong>UPDATE 10-7-2004:</strong> I&rsquo;ll be releasing 0.10b within the next week. Usability 
tweaks and a smoother interface. Thanks everyone for your comments and 
suggestions. Stay tuned.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Textpattern Blues</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/textpattern-blues/"/><published>2004-09-09T19:21:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/textpattern-blues/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;ve slowly been warming up to Textpattern over the past few months. At the spur 
of the moment I purchased a nice little plot over at <a href="http://www.dreamhost.com">Dreamhost</a> and starting some planting. I&rsquo;m about finished 
tilling the land and beginning to plant some seeds, however, you might stumble 
across some rocky areas.</p>
<p>On another note, since when did IE6 not support min-width and max-width? Yet 
another disappointment handed down from the pearly white gates. If anyone knows 
a fix for this chime in please.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>A Revolution of Education</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/a-revolution-of-education/"/><published>2004-09-04T19:21:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/a-revolution-of-education/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I believe it&rsquo;s time for a Education Revolution. While I may not be an expert in 
learning science I did participate in the Education system for 17 years and 
continue to work for an University.</p>
<p>Currently a majority of institutions force students to subscribe to General 
Education pressuring them to learn History, Physical Education, Mathematics and 
so on. While these topics carry an extreme importance this method of delivery is 
wrong. Students shouldn&rsquo;t be pressured into learning anything. During my 
freshman year in college I despised going to my Physical Education class because 
it was so boring and a waste of my time and effort. However, I now realize the 
positive affects exercise can have in my life and work. This is where the 
problem lies. That course should have excited me about the affects that physical 
activity can bring to my desired goals in life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Students learn best when motivated, when they care. They need to be 
emotionally involved, to be drawn to the excitement of the topic. Learning<br>
need not be a dull or dreary exercise, not even learning about what are 
normally considered dull and dreary topics: every topic can be made exciting, 
every topic excites the emotions of someone, so why not excite everyone?
&ndash; Donald Norman, Emotional Design</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What if we broke down the barriers of Education. Instead of offering courses we 
enrolled in what I&rsquo;ll call Communities. Each Community would have a focus: Art, 
Science, Mathematics; within each community Groups, with related focuses, would 
form. For example the Art Community would have a Group which focuses on Design 
or Pottery. The students of these communities would not organize in classrooms 
nor would they participate in courses. Each Community would reside in its very 
own research library. I use the term library loosely because the environment 
would need to cater to a wide variety of situations: discussion, research, 
building, brainstorming, and so on. Each student would draft goals for 
themselves, for the Group, and for the Community. Within the Communities 
professors would apply general education discussions based on the goals of the 
Community. Students need to learn History so the Communities promote learning 
about the Middle Ages and how it relates to the students individual goals, there 
by validating its importance to the overall purpose of the Community. Students 
would then begin to realize how imperative it is to understand not just one 
subject, but all subjects in relation to their goals thereby creating a well 
rounded diverse society.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It is time for lessons to become alive, for history to be seen as a human 
struggle, for students to understand and appreciate the structure of art, 
music, science, and mathematics. How can these topics be made exciting? By 
making them relevant to the lives of each individual student.
&ndash; Donald Norman, Emotional Design</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Education is the cornerstone of society. Without Education society breaks down. 
As we grow and mature throughout our life we should never cease to learn. Our 
Education institutions must promote life long learning rather than handing out 
diplomas and saying next. While this idea may or may not succeed I feel it&rsquo;s 
important to continually evolve our methods of teaching and learning in order to 
evolve as a society. With that in mind I invite your thoughts and criticism.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Heads or Tails</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/heads-or-tails/"/><published>2004-09-02T19:19:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/heads-or-tails/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;ve been somewhat silent lately with a few whispers here and there. The past 
couple weeks have been very interesting, stressful to say the least. Job, home 
and personal changes.</p>
<p>After much thought and pondering I accepted a position at Southwest Missouri 
State University as Multimedia Producer. I bid a humble farewell to <a href="http://www.neubix.com/">Neubix 
Studios</a>. The gamut of knowledge and wisdom <a href="http://www.justwatchthesky.com/">Ryan</a> and I provided each other was priceless. I&rsquo;m 
grateful to have been apart of their transformation and growth. For now I&rsquo;ll be 
overseeing the production of interactive and film projects, as well as 
advocating standards support and adoption of Open technologies.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve also moved to a very old apartment next to a very busy street. Outside my 
window rests an Art supplies store and many restaurants. I can walk to work, 
grocery store, and downtown which makes me oh so happy. Pictures are on the way.</p>
<p>On a personal level I&rsquo;m looking forward to creating more Fine Art. The past year 
hasn&rsquo;t provided much time for this, my goal is to pursue painting and mixed 
media. I&rsquo;ll also be brushing up on my programming skills to satisfy the left 
side of my brain.</p>
<p>As with every coin there is a flip side that I unfortunately can&rsquo;t reveal at 
this time. Stay tuned for more articles and updates.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Inspirational Journeys</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2004/inspirational-journeys/"/><published>2004-07-18T13:12:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/posts/2004/inspirational-journeys/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>In 1947 sculptor, Korczak Ziolkowski, moved too Thunder Mountain. He constructed a 741 foot staircase to the peak of the Mountain to begin, with his lone jackhammer, possibly the worlds largest sculpture, <a href="http://www.crazyhorse.org/carving/face/index.shtml">Crazy Horse</a>. For the next 33 years he chipped away at the mammoth mountain side until his death.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>His eye is 12 feet wide, his outstretched arm the length of a subway train. And by the time his horse is finished, we&rsquo;ll all be dead. Ready Made</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The recent issue of <a href="http://readymademag.com/currentissue.php">Ready Made</a> has its top inspirational ESCape&rsquo;s. They include: <a href="http://www.crazyhorse.org/">Crazy Horse Memorial</a>, <a href="http://www.pricetower.org">Price Tower</a>, 
<a href="http://www.roadtripamerica.com/places/forest.htm">Underground Gardens</a>, <a href="http://www.chinati.org">Marfa</a>, <a href="http://www.bestfriends.org">Animal Sanctuary</a>, and <a href="http://www.monks.org">Gethesmani</a>. I&rsquo;m seriously thinking about spending a couple nights in &ldquo;the tree that escaped the crowded forest,&rdquo; then hopping over too &ldquo;The mounted man of South Dakota,&rdquo; and finishing the trip off with a visit too &ldquo;A solitary man&rsquo;s subterranean legacy.&rdquo; This is definitely an issue worth checking out.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>