<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2007/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2014-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>First impressions</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/first-impressions/"/><published>2007-07-01T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/first-impressions/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>How does a machine have soul? We could try and answer by throwing around terms like usefulness, elegance and grace but all our attempts would sound prosaic next to the device I recently became acquainted with. Run and hide Crackberry, the iPhone is here.</p>
<p>For people to be drooling over a 4.8 ounce device is not unfathomable especially coming from Apple. This is different. During my first hours with the iPhone I literally felt nervous. I felt like I didn&rsquo;t deserve this, it seemed unreal.</p>
<p>11:00am Saturday: Headed to the coffee house. Do I need my laptop or my notebook, or magazine? Was I really walking down the street listening to my phone? Wait&hellip; Whoa&hellip; phone call. <em>Pinch</em> Hello&hellip; <em>conversation</em> goodbye. Music!!!</p>
<p>Some of my friends think I&rsquo;m crazy but for a UI designer this is as close to nirvana as I&rsquo;ve ever experienced.</p>
<p>9:00pm Saturday: Driving to the liquor store. Wait, are they open? iPhone eight ball returns: <a href="http://www2.ljworld.com/marketplace/businesses/mass-beverage/">decidedly so</a>. Again&hellip; I&rsquo;m not worthy.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s like those little knowledge cracks in your life are slowly getting sealed. Anything you wanted or needed to know is now within a few gestures. Why remember? Leave it up to the cloud, let your iPhone be your Receiver.</p>
<p>This device represents a new bar for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human-computer_interaction">HCI</a>. It also poses many exciting questions and possibilities. My only hope is that Apple will offer an SDK in the coming months so the collective can contribute. I have confidence the will. Need we be reminded where cover-flow came from? We definitely can&rsquo;t rely on the browser sandbox. It doesn&rsquo;t offer the same grace and fluidity applications garner.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>The waves of creativity</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/the-waves-of-creativity/"/><published>2007-05-17T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/the-waves-of-creativity/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>There are a lot of environmental factors that go into fostering a creative environment. As creative persons mature, we become more in-tune with what works best for us when it&rsquo;s time to dream up new ideas and solutions. Some of us trek to coffeehouses while others listen to Bach, Satie or Mogwai. Whatever we do we&rsquo;re all essentially trying to achieve a certain state of mind.</p>
<p>Before I go any further here is a quick explanation of the human brain by neuronal scientist, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Restak">Richard Restak</a>):</p>
<p>My very basic understanding is that synapses are essentially electrochemical connections that vibrate at varying frequencies. These frequencies <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brainwaves">can be measured</a> and grouped into four different categories: Beta, Alpha, Theta and Delta.</p>
<p>By now you&rsquo;re probably wondering what the hell does this have to do with creativity. Well let me quickly explain these four &ldquo;states of mind.&rdquo; Beta is the frequency we find ourselves in all too often. It&rsquo;s associated with being tense, alert, or afraid. Alpha is a state of relaxation without the loss of awareness. Theta is a day dream state and Delta is a state of unconsciousness, a sleep state.</p>
<p>When we seek out our ideal creative environments we are essentially trying to lower our brainwaves from Beta to Alpha. This takes time and cannot be done instantaneously. We can immediately go from Delta to Beta but not vise versa. We have to be someplace familiar where we feel safe and secure. A place were we can let our guard down.</p>
<p>Certain types of people exist in a constant state of Beta, some job types require it. When you intermingle Beta&rsquo;s with Alpha&rsquo;s and Theta&rsquo;s you undoubtedly create a source of tension. This is because the Beta&rsquo;s set the tone for the room and raise everyone to their frequency. This is why you rarely see sales and account management mixed with designers and illustrators.</p>
<p>Environment is worth more than any salary. I think most designers would agree when I say I&rsquo;d much rather be making peanuts at a Googleplex than six figures at Joe&rsquo;s Banner Ad Emporium.</p>
<p>More info can be found here:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.doctorhugo.org/brainwaves/brainwaves.html">What are Brainwaves?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0609604457">Mozart&rsquo;s Brain and the Fighter Pilot</a></li>
<li><a href="http://brain.web-us.com/brainwavesfunction.htm">Brainwave functions</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Disclaimer: I&rsquo;m no scientist. I just think this stuff is interesting and worth spreading. Correct me in the comments if necessary.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Transmedia newspapers</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/transmedia-newspapers/"/><published>2007-05-06T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/transmedia-newspapers/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I just finished reading chapter three of <a href="%5B/library/books/convergence-culture/%5D(https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convergence_culture)">Convergence Culture</a> where Jenkins discusses transmedia storytelling. He focuses on the Matrix franchise and how it basically rewrote the rules for Hollywoods future. It got me thinking on my walk home from the coffeehouse, why aren&rsquo;t newspapers doing this?</p>
<p>We&rsquo;re all familiar with the Matrix and have varying depths of involvement with it. Most of us have seen the first film, some the second and third but have any of us played the video game, or seen the Animatrix, or been to <a href="http://www.matrixonline.com">Matrix Online</a>? It all represents facets of transmedia storytelling, the very essence of convergence. Danny Bilson explains the transmedia relationship between the Matrix film and its game:</p>
<p>The news is delivered in a parallel fashion which isn&rsquo;t going to last, in fact, it&rsquo;s what&rsquo;s killing the old product. I can get the same Washington Post online as I can from the printed version and it&rsquo;s obvious which one I choose. A transmedia approach needs to replace the parallel delivery model. Give people up-to-the-minute details online, then print in-depth coverage. Show me how it relates to current culture with lessons and anecdotes, make it enjoyable and interesting and if the package is pretty I&rsquo;ll proudly display it on my shelves.</p>
<p>Why don&rsquo;t newspapers live up to their medium? Print isn&rsquo;t bad, it&rsquo;s fantastic with huge staying power but you&rsquo;ve gotta produce something I&rsquo;m gonna want to keep around. I buy books because I want to savor them and I like the way they look on my shelves. Stop being so throwaway. The print medium isn&rsquo;t dead but delivering up-to-the-minute news with ink is on life support. The industry really needs to rethink what gets inked and how their readers will savor it.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not suggesting in-depth storytelling should be relegated to print but it kinda makes sense as a starting point. I flat out won&rsquo;t stare at a light-bulb and read pages of a story even if it is interesting. There are things you can do in print that you simply cannot do online and of you don&rsquo;t believe me get your hands on a Cranbrook Academy of Art academic catalog.</p>
<p>A perfect example of news transmedia storytelling is the New York Times Magazine. It&rsquo;s the only time I buy a newspaper and all I really want is the magazine. It&rsquo;s kind of like a fortune cookie, I don&rsquo;t really enjoy the cookie but I savor the fortune. The publication provides select stories that are well thought out and insightful which usually draw from the previous weeks worth of news bites. It features great illustrations and photographs. I could get it online through their Times Select but I&rsquo;d rather not.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>LJWorld redesign</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/ljworld-redesign/"/><published>2007-05-02T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/ljworld-redesign/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>So for the past five months or so we&rsquo;ve been working on a redesign for the <a href="http://ljworld.com">Lawrence Journal-World</a>. For those of you that don&rsquo;t know, it&rsquo;s a daily newspaper that circulates the town of Lawrence, Kansas. It&rsquo;s quite small compared to surrounding markets which makes it very agile and free from shareholders and their evil agendas.</p>
<p>I had a feeling this project would be special and challenging but I had no idea of the scale. Turns out, around the same time I was tasked with designing <a href="http://ljworld.com/marketplace">Marketplace</a>, a directory of 4000+ local businesses. I must also mention, news doesn&rsquo;t stop for redesigns. It&rsquo;s definitely a juggling act when your trying to complete a site thats constantly having to push out news features and various timely events like <a href="http://www2.ljworld.com/elections/2007/apr/03/races/lawrence_city_commission/">local elections</a>. There were, shall I say, growing pains.
Details aside, the design is <a href="http://www2.ljworld.com/news/politics/kansas_legislature/">simple</a>. In fact the design is designed to disappear. Content is what really matters so I decided to take an approach that would make the overall design feel supportive rather than overbearing. This isn&rsquo;t easy for anyone and requires extreme discipline. Discipline I never thought I had.</p>
<p>The site will continue to take shape over time. We&rsquo;re hoping that redesigns are a thing of the past and constant iterations are a thing of the future. We&rsquo;ll see how long that lasts ;-)
This project wouldn&rsquo;t have been possible without the involvement of <a href="http://www.b-list.org/">James Bennett</a>, Dan Cox, <a href="http://www.jeffcroft.com/">Jeff Croft</a>, <a href="http://postneo.com/">Matt Croydon</a>, <a href="http://www.jacobian.org/">Jacob Kaplan-Moss</a>, Joel Mathis, <a href="http://www.mintchaos.com/">Christian Metts</a>, David Ryan, Tom Tobin, all the web producers and all the editors and reporters that allow us to do what we do.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Javascript Flash round 2</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/javascript-flash-round-2/"/><published>2007-04-20T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/javascript-flash-round-2/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>FIguring out the Javascript/Flash integration kit has lead to a much simpler solution. Looks like Macromedia has slipped in another nugget of usefulness in the Flash 8 release which, I might add,  has penetrated the market remarkably fast. It&rsquo;s called External Interface. I gotta thank <a href="http://bobbykellogg.com/">Bobby</a> for finding this one.</p>
<p>So forget the last post if you&rsquo;re a progressive designer like myself, marching to the Flash 8 bugle. Using the same example as <a href="/2007/make-flash-and-javascript-sing">before</a> replace your Actionscript with the following.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-js" data-lang="js"><span style="color:#66d9ef">import</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">flash</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">external</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">ExternalInterface</span>;

<span style="color:#a6e22e">ExternalInterface</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">addCallback</span>(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;moveBall&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#66d9ef">this</span>, <span style="color:#a6e22e">moveBall</span>);

<span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">moveBall</span> (<span style="color:#a6e22e">p_x</span><span style="color:#f92672">:</span>Number, <span style="color:#a6e22e">p_y</span><span style="color:#f92672">:</span>Number)<span style="color:#f92672">:</span><span style="color:#a6e22e">Void</span> {
    <span style="color:#a6e22e">ball_mc</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">_x</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">p_x</span>;
    <span style="color:#a6e22e">ball_mc</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">_y</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">p_y</span>;
}
</code></pre></div><p>And then replace your javascript with the following.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-js" data-lang="js"><span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">move_ball</span> () {
    <span style="color:#a6e22e">x</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> document.<span style="color:#a6e22e">moveball</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">x</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">value</span>;
    <span style="color:#a6e22e">y</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> document.<span style="color:#a6e22e">moveball</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">y</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">value</span>;

    <span style="color:#66d9ef">if</span> (<span style="color:#a6e22e">navigator</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">appName</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">indexOf</span>(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;Microsoft&#34;</span>) <span style="color:#f92672">!=</span> <span style="color:#f92672">-</span><span style="color:#ae81ff">1</span>) {
      window[<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;ball&#39;</span>].<span style="color:#a6e22e">moveBall</span>(<span style="color:#a6e22e">x</span>, <span style="color:#a6e22e">y</span>);
    } <span style="color:#66d9ef">else</span> {
      document[<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;ball&#39;</span>].<span style="color:#a6e22e">moveBall</span>(<span style="color:#a6e22e">x</span>, <span style="color:#a6e22e">y</span>);
    }
}
</code></pre></div><p>Thats it! Just make sure you name your flash file &ldquo;ball&rdquo; and you&rsquo;ve set allowScriptAccess to all or sameDomain. Get rid of all the extraneous files from before too, you don&rsquo;t need them! <a href="http://www.playgroundblues.com/media/source/JavaScript_Flash_Tutorial2/">View example</a>.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>InspectDB to the rescue</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/inspectdb-to-the-rescue/"/><published>2007-04-19T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/inspectdb-to-the-rescue/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>In a past life I used to build admin tools using <a href="http://www.rubyonrails.com">Ruby on Rails</a>. I thoroughly enjoyed spending weekends improving my little tools and libraries but I eventually realized I was spending more time on back-end stuff than front-end. Enter Django. For the past nine months I&rsquo;ve touched nothing but Django so you can imagine how easy it was for me to hop on the Rails bicycle when Dreamhost decided to upgrade Rails.</p>
<p>You see, I failed to Freeze my Rails releases so they would be impervious to backwards incompatible changes. This presented a problem and I needed a solution like Don Imus needs a job.
I decided it wasn&rsquo;t worth investigating why my code broke between Rails version 1.2 to 1.2.3. My solution was to just rewrite the damn things in Django. While ranting at work about my situation my good friend <a href="http://www.b-list.org">James</a> pointed out a nice little tool called <a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/documentation/django-admin/#inspectdb">inspectdb</a> part of django-admin.py. All I had to do was create a new Django project, point it to my old Rails database and inspectdb spits out all the necessary model code so Django can start using that database.</p>
<p>I simplified my overly complex Rails admin tool (my fault again) and migrated the new data by setting up a template to print out SQL inserts to match the new simplified database schema. I literally did this in less than two hours on a tool that previously took over two days to build. Not to mention I got better authentication, caching, and peace of mind.
I must point out this is not a failure of Rails, merely a lack of time and commitment on my part. It would, however, be nice if Rails would be more mindful of backwards compatibility :)</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Bringing back the personal</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/bringing-back-the-personal/"/><published>2007-04-11T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/bringing-back-the-personal/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;ve heard wisperings about the death of blogs lately. More and more we see our
favorite writters fading into the ether. This begs the question, what next? What
do we do with the barren ghost towns that once thrived on eager readers making
sure their cache was cleared before stalking their favorites.</p>
<p>Personal sites should be cornucopias which chronicle our lives. They should be
open sketchbooks crammed with a maze of twists and turns. We should be able to
post without shame or regret things that later on demonstrate our progress. I
want to browse sites like Chris Glass (<a href="http://www.chrisglass.com/">http://www.chrisglass.com/</a>) which feels
like a time capsule where I can rummage around and get a sense of someone&rsquo;s life.
It&rsquo;s incredibly motivating to see his travel logs, journal entries, photos and
favorites. All neatly packaged with thought and purpose. You can tell this site
not only serves his audience, but seems to play an important role for him.</p>
<p>I think it&rsquo;s obvious that 2007 is a turning point for blogging but it&rsquo;s also a
chance to question what we should strive for in a personal site. Social
networking seems to have decentralized our lives and allowed us to stray farther
away from our personal sites, but thanks to API&rsquo;s we&rsquo;re beginning to gain back
some centralization. We really shouldn&rsquo;t shackle ourselves to the output of an
API, nor should we restrict ourselves to &ldquo;dynamic content&rdquo; that comes from a CMS.
Most of us are highly skilled in HTML/CSS and we shouldn&rsquo;t fear one off pages
and designs. I remember the days of updating my blog via HTML, when I had
something to show I didn&rsquo;t ask how it was going to live in a CMS, I just threw
it up.</p>
<p>With this in mind I don&rsquo;t exactly know where Playground Blues is headed. There
is a lot of data that I&rsquo;m collecting that I haven&rsquo;t figured out how to share or
even if it makes sense to share. I am, however, eager to explore the Art of
maintaining a personal site and in the coming weeks I&rsquo;d like to discuss this
more along with some of my concerns regarding digital preservation. Stay tuned.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Making old content new</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/making-old-content-new/"/><published>2007-03-27T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/making-old-content-new/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Why does old content have to fade so quickly? Blogs, zines, news articles all
suffer from &ldquo;out with the old, in with the new&rdquo; mentality. There is a lot of
old content that retains relevancy far beyond its publish date. The problem is,
how do we resurrect it?</p>
<p>Simple, stats tracking. Amazon solved this problem a long time ago. They
meticulously track peoples browsing and buying habits and offer up
recommendations based on trends. Chris Anderson&rsquo;s article from 2004, The Long
Tail (<a href="http://www.wired.com/wired/archive/12.10/tail.html">http://www.wired.com/wired/archive/12.10/tail.html</a>) will really blow your
skirt up. Anderson starts off by explaining how Joe Simpson&rsquo;s book, Touching the
Void (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/0060730552/)">http://www.amazon.com/dp/0060730552/)</a>, brought little fan fair in 1988
until ten years latter when Amazon noticed the buying trends of a new title,
Into Thin Air (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/0385494785/">http://www.amazon.com/dp/0385494785/</a>) by Jon Krakauer. Amazon&rsquo;s
recommendation algorithm began serving up <em>Touching the Void</em> as a &ldquo;buy this
book with&hellip;&rdquo; recommendation. Touching the Void ultimately out-sold Into Thin Air.</p>
<p>Why couldn&rsquo;t the same approach be taken for time insensitive content on sites
like A List Apart, NYTimes, CNN, even this blog? How much relevancy should we
give old content? Stats have always been fun to look at with tools like Mint
(<a href="http://www.haveamint.com">http://www.haveamint.com</a>) and Google Analytics, but when do we start
capitalizing on them and using them in clever ways to help direct our readers
to the content they so desire? How do we make old content the new black?</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Make Flash and Javascript Sing</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/make-flash-and-javascript-sing/"/><published>2007-03-18T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/make-flash-and-javascript-sing/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Yes its true. You can make Javascript and Flash play together! Way back in 2005 the company formerly known as Macromedia threw together a nice <a href="http://weblogs.macromedia.com/flashjavascript/">little kit</a> to make these two languages play nicely. Here&rsquo;s how.</p>
<p>First we need to secure some crutial files. The first is a SWF called JavaScriptFlashGateway.swf which allows us to setup a &ldquo;proxy&rdquo; between our Flash and Javascript. Second, make sure you link up JavaScriptFlashGateway.js. Third, put JavaScriptSerializer.as and JavaScriptProxy.as in your Actionscript class path so you can import them into your Flash movies.</p>
<p>Once all that is in place it&rsquo;s time to write some code. For this example I&rsquo;m going to make a ball move across the screen using two input fields in an HTML form which will allow a person to enter X and Y values to move the ball across the screen. Before we can get any further we need establish an ID so things are nice a secure between our Flash and Javascript. We&rsquo;re going to use the current time as our ID like so:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-js" data-lang="js"><span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">uid</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> Date().<span style="color:#a6e22e">getTime</span>();
<span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">flashproxy</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">FlashProxy</span>(<span style="color:#a6e22e">uid</span>, <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;JavaScriptFlashGateway.swf&#39;</span>);
</code></pre></div><p>Now lets add some code to our flash movie. In the first frame add:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-js" data-lang="js"><span style="color:#66d9ef">import</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">JavaScriptProxy</span>;

<span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">Ball</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> {}
<span style="color:#a6e22e">Ball</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">moveBall</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span> (<span style="color:#a6e22e">p_x</span><span style="color:#f92672">:</span>Number, <span style="color:#a6e22e">p_y</span><span style="color:#f92672">:</span>Number) {
    <span style="color:#a6e22e">ball_mc</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">_x</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">p_x</span>;
    <span style="color:#a6e22e">ball_mc</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">_y</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">p_y</span>;
}

<span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">proxy</span><span style="color:#f92672">:</span><span style="color:#a6e22e">JavaScriptProxy</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">JavaScriptProxy</span>(<span style="color:#a6e22e">_root</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">lcId</span>, <span style="color:#a6e22e">Ball</span>);
</code></pre></div><p>We&rsquo;re simply importing the JavaScriptProxy class and creating a Ball class. The Ball class gets a method called moveBall which is what we&rsquo;ll call via javascript. Notice the JavaScriptProxy is passed our ID that we created earlier and a reference to the Ball class. Lets turn back to our HTML file and add some more Javascript to complete the deal.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-js" data-lang="js"><span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">tag</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">FlashTag</span>(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;flash/ball.swf&#39;</span>, <span style="color:#ae81ff">400</span>, <span style="color:#ae81ff">350</span>);
<span style="color:#a6e22e">tag</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">setFlashvars</span>(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;lcId=&#39;</span><span style="color:#f92672">+</span><span style="color:#a6e22e">uid</span>);
<span style="color:#a6e22e">tag</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">write</span>(document);

<span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">move_ball</span> () {
    <span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">x</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> document.<span style="color:#a6e22e">moveball</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">x</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">value</span>;
    <span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">y</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> document.<span style="color:#a6e22e">moveball</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">y</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">value</span>;
    <span style="color:#a6e22e">flashproxy</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">call</span>(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;moveBall&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#a6e22e">x</span>, <span style="color:#a6e22e">y</span>)
}
</code></pre></div><p>Here we&rsquo;re using the handy FlashTag class to embed our ball.swf into our page. We&rsquo;re also passing the ID we created earlier, very important. The move_ball function is what we&rsquo;ll call upon submission of the HTML form. It uses the flashproxy instance to call our Actionscript method &ldquo;moveBall&rdquo; passing it the x and y coordinates into the SWF thus moving the ball.</p>
<p>Hope this makes a little sense. The code can be <a href="http://www.playgroundblues.com/media/source/JavaScript_Flash_Tutorial.zip">downloaded here</a> or you can just look at it <a href="http://www.playgroundblues.com/media/source/JavaScript_Flash_Tutorial/">here</a>. I&rsquo;ve also created <a href="http://www.playgroundblues.com/laboratory/">another example</a> that utilizes a Flash video player and playlist. You can also call Javascript functions from within your Flash movie. There is one gotcha that I&rsquo;ve come across in order to do this. Be sure to set the Flash parameter allowScriptAccess to &ldquo;always&rdquo;. Otherwise communication from Flash to Javascript won&rsquo;t work.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Not so convergent</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/not-so-convergent/"/><published>2007-03-14T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/not-so-convergent/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Talking about &ldquo;convergence&rdquo; is like talking about &ldquo;the war on terror.&rdquo; They&rsquo;re
two incredibly broad terms with unforeseeable outcomes. Convergence has been
vogue for a while and I&rsquo;m a little skeptical about its usage to describe media
convergence. At this years SXSW, for the first time, someone summed up what
I&rsquo;ve been trying to understand.</p>
<p>When I think of convergence I do so in terms of the classic media outlets
converging with the Internet. There is a lot of convergence rhetoric at my job
and in the field of news. Advertising is also experiencing the pains of
understanding what the web is and how to leverage it. Convergence seems more
like a trojan horse to me, creeping into peoples minds making them think it will
deliver harmony between old and new. It&rsquo;s just not true.</p>
<p>While old media tries to &ldquo;converge&rdquo; over the next few years we&rsquo;re going to see
more Salon&rsquo;s, Newsvine&rsquo;s, and Digg&rsquo;s take over. They&rsquo;ll do so because they don&rsquo;t
have to change old minds. The Google / Viacom battle
(<a href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/hr/content_display/features/columns/e3if463a30783104b1095bfd087a35ac0f5">http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/hr/content_display/features/columns/e3if463a30783104b1095bfd087a35ac0f5</a>)
will be nothing short of entertaining. This is how the old always dies off,
clinging to what they know and understand.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>