<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Work on Nathan Borror</title><link>https://nathan.run/work/</link><description>Recent content in Work on Nathan Borror</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://nathan.run/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dropbox</title><link>https://nathan.run/work/dropbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/work/dropbox/</guid><description>April 2014 – June 2015 Product Designer Shortly after I joined Dropbox, a small research and development team formed to investigate new products to compliment the main storage and syncing offering. I helped focus efforts around improving team communication between people using shared folders. We designed and prototyped a number of potential products, eventually launching an internal communication tool just before I left in 2015.
Mobile App We started off trying to figure out how to add chat and collaboration tools to the existing iOS app.</description></item><item><title>Facebook</title><link>https://nathan.run/work/facebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/work/facebook/</guid><description>August 2018 – Present Product Design Director During my first couple years back I worked on projects that helped bring the Family more closer together. Now I&amp;rsquo;m helping imagine a future full of healthy regulation.
February 2011 – April 2014 Product Designer &amp;amp; Product Design Manager Facebook was my first job at (what was still considered at the time) a startup. Before joining I was trying to quickly upgrade rural newspapers across the country to a more hopeful future from a basement in Kansas.</description></item><item><title>Lawrence Journal-World</title><link>https://nathan.run/work/journal-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/work/journal-world/</guid><description>2006 – 2011 Generalist</description></item><item><title>Public Studio</title><link>https://nathan.run/work/public-studio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/work/public-studio/</guid><description>June 2015 – August 2018 Generalist Public Studio was an opportunity to work with Aaron Sittig and Justin Shaffer to build new independent companies around sustainable ideas. I helped think through product ideas and build the initial implementations of the clients and services needed to grow the companies. Over three years we produced two companies:
Relay Relay was an attempt to build a modern version of the communities we experienced during the early days of the internet.</description></item></channel></rss>