<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2007/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2014-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Flash, meet H.264</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/flash-meet-h.264/"/><published>2007-12-04T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/flash-meet-h.264/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Adobe just <a href="http://www.adobe.com/aboutadobe/pressroom/pressreleases/200712/120407adobemoviestar.html">released</a> Update 3 of Flash Player 9. This is HUGE. Streaming video is no longer a laughing matter. Streaming High Definition video will become common place and it starts today.</p>
<p>Everyone talks about BlueRay and HD-DVD, but what they don&rsquo;t realize is they&rsquo;ve already been obsolesced before catching stride. VHS is dead, brick and mortar video rental is on life support, and DVD just checked in with chest pains.</p>
<h3 id="how-long-will-it-take">How long will it take?</h3>
<p>I give Adobe four months to capture 80% of the market share. It usually takes about a year to cover 90% of the web with a new Flash version, but once YouTube and MySpace deliver, the game&rsquo;s over.</p>
<h3 id="what-does-this-mean">What does this mean?</h3>
<p>It means you can cancel your cable. I recently did because I&rsquo;m getting most of my content from iTunes and YouTube. I paid around $100 a month for cable and watched nothing worthwhile. Now I could <strong>own</strong> around fifty shows a month for the same price &ndash; not to mention most of the stuff I like is free. Let&rsquo;s also not forget the portability factor :)
This is a huge step forward in providing tools to people who need them. Now go <a href="http://www.adobe.com/go/getflashplayer">upgrade</a>.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Django Basic Apps</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/django-basic-apps/"/><published>2007-12-02T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/django-basic-apps/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I&rsquo;ve been working on abstracting some Django applications from past projects so they can effortlessly be plugged into future projects. I hate writing the same blog application repeatedly, so this is an attempt to make life easier. I think this will be a fun, little suite of plug-n-play Django apps that everyone can benefit from.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m calling this suite Basic Apps with the hopes they&rsquo;ll live up to their name. They&rsquo;re freely distributed under the <a href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php">New BSD License</a> and hosted at Google Code. The goal is to use the month of December to get feedback from everyone and finalize the models, so <strong>beware of model changes.</strong>
The apps I&rsquo;ll be introducing today include Basic Blog, Basic Places, Basic People, Basic Library, and Basic Profiles. Before you run off keep in mind these are <em>basic</em> apps. You won&rsquo;t see anything earth shattering. The idea is to be simple and pluggable so when it comes time to add a blog or user profiles to your project you&rsquo;ve got a jumping off point. That said, I&rsquo;d like to provide a brief description of each app:</p>
<h3 id="basic-bloghttpcodegooglecompdjango-basic-blog"><a href="http://code.google.com/p/django-basic-blog/">Basic Blog</a></h3>
<p>This is a blog, nothing more nothing less. There is a Post model and a Category model. The dependancies include Django Comments and <a href="http://code.google.com/p/django-tagging/">Django Tagging</a>.</p>
<h3 id="basic-placeshttpcodegooglecompdjango-basic-places"><a href="http://code.google.com/p/django-basic-places/">Basic Places</a></h3>
<p>This app stores place information, (gasp!) The models include Place Type, City, Point, and Place. Django Tagging is the only dependancy.</p>
<h3 id="basic-peoplehttpcodegooglecompdjango-basic-people"><a href="http://code.google.com/p/django-basic-people/">Basic People</a></h3>
<p>This app stores people information. (you&rsquo;re kidding!) This app has nothing to do with Users. The people that go here are individuals that will never have access to your project. It is used heavily with the library app. The models include Person Type and Person.</p>
<h3 id="basic-libraryhttpcodegooglecompdjango-basic-library"><a href="http://code.google.com/p/django-basic-library/">Basic Library</a></h3>
<p>This actually contains three apps: Music, Movies, and Books. All three are independent and should be placed independently in your PYTHONPATH. Movies has one model, Movie. Books has two, Book and Publisher. Music has Label, Band, Album, and Song. All three depend on the Basic People app. They all have a Genre model to boot!</p>
<h3 id="basic-profileshttpcodegooglecompdjango-basic-profiles"><a href="http://code.google.com/p/django-basic-profiles/">Basic Profiles</a></h3>
<p>This app extends the Django User app, providing added user information. The models include Profile, Mobile Service, Link, Service, and Service Type.
All of these apps need Python 2.4 or higher and Django 0.97 or higher. If you have any feature requests or notice any issues please create a ticket on the corresponding Google Code site using the Issues tab. I&rsquo;ve also started a <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/django-basic-apps">Django Basic Apps</a> discussion over at Google Groups. Now, let&rsquo;s build some shit.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Django Sprint</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/django-sprint/"/><published>2007-12-01T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/django-sprint/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Armed with high levels of legally addictive stimulants, silver laptops, and brilliant minds, Django will get even closer to 1.0 <a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/weblog/2007/nov/07/sprint/">today</a>. If you have any interest in being apart of today&rsquo;s event, scurry over to the Django site and scan for tickets that catch your eye and expertise. Join us in IRC (irc.freenode.net) in the #django-sprint room or if you&rsquo;re lucky enough to live near Lawrence, Kansas come join us!</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Juggling Django settings modules</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/juggling-django-settings-modules/"/><published>2007-11-06T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/juggling-django-settings-modules/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>If you find yourself juggling multiple Django projects and constantly changing the DJANGO_SETTINGS_MODULE variable, try this simple shortcut.</p>
<p>Upon diving into a particular project I define an alias in my .bash_profile that gets me to the project directory in as few keystrokes as possible. For example, to get to my playgroundblues directory I simply type &lsquo;pb&rsquo; and I&rsquo;m in the root of playgroundblues.com. Here is the line of code in my .bash_profile:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-sh" data-lang="sh">alias pb<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;cd /Working/www/playgroundblues.com/&#34;</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Pretty straight forward, however, since I&rsquo;m going to that project I might as well set the DJANGO_SETTINGS_MODULE at the same time so I&rsquo;ve altered the line above to:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-sh" data-lang="sh">alias pb<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;cd /Working/www/playgroundblues.com/; export DJANGO_SETTINGS_MODULE=playgroundblues.settings&#34;</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Now I&rsquo;m in the proper directory with the proper settings file is in focus. Bliss.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Care to scrum?</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/care-to-scrum/"/><published>2007-10-17T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/care-to-scrum/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>We need more scrums and less meetings. A scrum (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stand-up_meeting">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stand-up_meeting</a>)
is a 5-10 minute stand-up meeting. About 80% of the meetings I&rsquo;ve ever attended
have included at least five people. Any meeting over three becomes a presentation
while one bloviates and others wander.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since my last scrum. It included seven people, complete
participation, no dominance, one referee, and was contained within a 10 minute
package. Rather than walking away in a typical post-meeting cloud of confusion,
I left the scrum feeling clear and informed. It was the best mode of collaborative
communication I&rsquo;ve been a part of. Again, I say more scrums, less meetings.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Trials of the I-70 commute</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/trials-of-the-i-70-commute/"/><published>2007-10-15T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/trials-of-the-i-70-commute/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>A while ago I began working back in the big city while remaining in modest
Lawrence. This required a 40 min. x 2 drive into the sun five days a week. It
wasn&rsquo;t so bad at first, but the race through traffic and mass of incandescent
gas started taking its toll.</p>
<p>I decided to evaluate what was wearing me out. The sun, for one, was melting my
retinas and giving me headaches. This stress could easily be eliminated with the
right shades, polarized to be exact. They immediately reduced eye strain and
lowered my stress level. I was still experiencing anxiety that led to being
drained at work and home. This had to be stemming from my colleagues on the road.</p>
<p>Driving I-70 during rush hour is like threading a needle. You&rsquo;re constantly
struggling to out-pace traffic so you can relax and cruise the rest of the way
home. Only problem is your cruising doesn&rsquo;t happen until the last 10-15 miles.
I averaged 80 to 85 mph and decided one day just go the speed limit, 70 mph.</p>
<p>The results were immediate. I didn&rsquo;t have to pass anyone! That alone leveled my
stress. Then I realized I wasn&rsquo;t getting into any traffic jams because they were
all hurdling past me. I could hold a steady cruising speed without having to
touch my brake. This also upped my miles per gallon giving me an extra trip on
a full tank.</p>
<p>The irony was seeing everyone who passed me at the toll booth or the first
stoplight, so I knew I wasn&rsquo;t losing any time.</p>
<p>After spreading the word about this revelation, a coworker was telling me about
some research comparing fluid dynamics and traffic waves (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Traffic_wave)">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Traffic_wave)</a>.
The Wikipedia page describes it best:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A deeper understanding of traffic waves is a goal of the physical study of
traffic flow. When looking at traffic waves, the traffic itself can often be
looked at in a manner of fluid dynamics. It has been said that by knowing how
traffic waves are created, drivers can sometimes reduce their effects by
increasing vehicle headways and reducing the use of brakes, ultimately
alleviating traffic congestion for everyone in the area.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So to my dear fellow I-70 commuters, you don&rsquo;t have to thank me; but just
remember who&rsquo;s making your life easier. See you at the toll booth!</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Subliminal Culture</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/subliminal-culture/"/><published>2007-09-21T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/subliminal-culture/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Lately I&rsquo;ve been reading more of Lev Manovich&rsquo;s (<a href="http://www.manovich.com">http://www.manovich.com</a>)
Language of New Media. Manovich discusses the methods in which we access new
media. He mentions some research done by Paul Virilio on the collapsing effect
technology has on the distances between people and content. Before, if a person
wanted to see the works of Da Vinci they&rsquo;d have to travel to a book store or an
art museum. With the advent of new media it&rsquo;s as simple as pulling up a browser.</p>
<p>The consequences of this immediacy are somewhat evident. The moment of seeing a
work like Ginevra de Benci (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ginevra_de%27_Benci">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ginevra_de%27_Benci</a>)
on a screen is most likely followed up with going to Digg or checking email but
seeing this 15th century master work at the National Gallery
(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Gallery_of_Art">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Gallery_of_Art</a>) is followed with
indescribable emotions. The immediacy of content to some degree robs us of these
experiences, but we&rsquo;re still absorbing content on a subliminal level.</p>
<p>These fleeting moments of content absorption can heighten the experience of
standing in front of the real thing. By skimming da Vinci&rsquo;s Wikipedia entry I&rsquo;ll
have seen Ginevra and maybe even read a few lines about her so upon seeing the
piece in person I may have a slight familiarity which leads to a better
appreciation of the work thus heightening the experience. In advertising we call
this subliminal advertising and judging by this little experiment
(<a href="http://youtube.com/watch?v=ZyQjr1YL0zg)">http://youtube.com/watch?v=ZyQjr1YL0zg)</a>, it proves to be very effective.</p>
<p>Virilio seems to think the immediacy of the web will stunt peoples physical
interactions with content thus stunting reflection and critical thinking. I see
his point but I think it has the potential to heighten and increase our
experiences.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Manually Compressing PNGs</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/manually-compressing-pngs/"/><published>2007-09-18T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/manually-compressing-pngs/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>With the advent of some very clean hacks to make PNGs work in IE I&rsquo;ve found
myself working them into my designs more. Using them has allowed me to achieve
some effects that were next to impossible with JPEGs and GIFs. The biggest
hurdle in using PNGs is their file size. The export tools in Photoshop tie your
hands behind your back, not allowing you to tweak anything that may lead to a
more compact file. Until Photoshop adds some functionality I think I may have a
handy solution.</p>
<p>To understand the solution we need to understand the composition of a PNG. The
most popular use case for PNG is it&rsquo;s levels of transparency (or alpha channel),
256 to be exact. Along with this it has a 24bit color palate. In photoshop there
are two settings in Save for Web, 8bit PNG and 24bit PNG. The 24bit is most
desirable because it enables the alpha channel. The PNG format has many many
other features but I&rsquo;m only going to focus on these few to move this post along.</p>
<p>So we can deduce from the above that we have an image with two qualities, 24bit
color and 256 alpha channel. Both are being compressed somewhat independently.
The only problem is, Photoshop doesn&rsquo;t let us change the compression on the
24bit part or on the alpha channel part. If we focus on compressing the 24bit
part we can potentially shave off a lot of the fat.</p>
<p>For this example I&rsquo;m going to use a box that has a lot of texture and a drop
shadow. To compress the inside part that doesn&rsquo;t have a drop shadow I&rsquo;m simply
going to select it, copy it, create a new document and paste it in. Then I&rsquo;m
going to use Save for Web to export it as a JPEG and use the photoshop
compression tools to make it an acceptable file size. Then I&rsquo;m going to open my
compressed JPEG that I just saved and copy it into my original document. After
lining things up with the compressed JPEG on top I&rsquo;m now ready to Save for Web
and use the PNG 24bit compression. The results are pretty dramatic. What
normally would be a 68k image is now a 48k. In some cases I&rsquo;ve cut files size
in half!</p>
<p>!http://playgroundblues.com/media/source/png_compress_tutorial.jpg</p>
<p>I&rsquo;d love to hear other techniques.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>iPhone dead; $30 rental?</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/iphone-dead-30-rental/"/><published>2007-08-15T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/iphone-dead-30-rental/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>This morning I woke up on my own. Normally I hear little crickets chirping around 7am which is my <a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone">iPhone</a> letting me know it&rsquo;s time to face the coming day. This morning, no crickets. At first I thought maybe the battery was flat, but that&rsquo;s not possible. I charged it the day before and didn&rsquo;t put it through any rigorous usage. So <a href="http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?artnum=305743">iPhone CPR</a> commences.</p>
<p>First I try a hard restart, holding down the home and on/off button for a few seconds. No dice. Then I plug it in, nothing, another hard restart, nothing. Let it sit for a while plugged in, restart, nothing. She&rsquo;s flat-lined and any amount of resuscitation is not getting her little heart pumping again. By this point it&rsquo;s time for work.</p>
<p>I roll into work around 9am with a cold iPhone in my pocket. She still feels good but her soul is lost. 10am rolls around, I can&rsquo;t wait. I head to Apple Store on the Plaza hoping they can shock her back into existence. The Genius looks it over, does exactly what I did earlier that morning. Realizes he can&rsquo;t do much so offers to send it back to Apple for repair. This sucks, two days sans phone is not acceptable. I&rsquo;ve never had to send a phone in for repairs, I&rsquo;ve never had a phone just break. I <em>need</em> a phone at all times. I can&rsquo;t say for sure if this is Apple&rsquo;s fault but I know for a fact that I have not done anything out of the ordinary to cause my iPhone to die. So I&rsquo;m forced to pay $30 to rent a phone while mine is being repaired. This is lame.
Apple shouldn&rsquo;t be charging it&rsquo;s loyal $30 to rent an iPhone while theirs is being repaired, especially if the error is on Apple. This doesn&rsquo;t seem like good customer service to me. I would gladly put down a deposit for the rental but I should get that deposit back.</p>
<p>While my phone travels in her temporary sarcophagus to the bowels of Cupertino I&rsquo;m left with the sting of loosing $30 for an error that is undoubtedly Apples. <strong>grumble</strong>
I would like to thank the guys at the <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Apple Store<!-- raw HTML omitted -->, they were very cordial and accommodating.</p>
<h3 id="update-august-28-2007">Update: August 28, 2007</h3>
<p>I recieved my &ldquo;fixed&rdquo; phone in the mail via Apple. Only problem was the little guy refused to recognize my SIM card. I tried all sorts of things, even other SIM cards, nothing. Apple was kind enough to replace the phone. What a relief. After about two weeks of usage things were back to normal until this evening while browsing the web I was greeted with a colorful half streaked screen. I don&rsquo;t know about anyone else but the Aurora Borealis belongs in the sky, not on the lower half of my iPhone screen. My luck just gets better by the iPhone.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Blueprints are not final</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2007/blueprints-are-not-final/"/><published>2007-08-10T00:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2007/blueprints-are-not-final/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>So apparently a little framework called Blueprint (<a href="http://bjorkoy.com/blueprint">http://bjorkoy.com/blueprint</a>)
has reared it&rsquo;s head, born from a few stylesheets that look very familiar. I&rsquo;m
somewhat conflicted with its release because I don&rsquo;t think it should be used.
Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, it&rsquo;s great, but don&rsquo;t use it.</p>
<p>About five or so months ago I was working on the Journal-World (<a href="http://www.ljworld.com">http://www.ljworld.com</a>)
redesign. News sites tend to be very column heavy and I was getting tired of
writing the same code over and over to accommodate for my design iterations.
One day Jeff (<a href="http://www.jeffcroft.com">http://www.jeffcroft.com</a>) and I discussed some ways to maximized
code reuse and speed up this process of going from Photoshop to markup. Later
that night I sketched out a method for easily defining grid structures and
columns. My attempt was pretty crude and over the next week or so it become a
lot more solid with the help of Jeff and Christian (<a href="http://mintchaos.com/)">http://mintchaos.com/)</a>.
After adding styles for type and common lists we had formed a pretty powerful
time saving solution. I could quickly prototype mockups in hours. The only
problem was it wasn&rsquo;t semantic. Things like span-4, unit, and block polluted
the HTML and CSS.</p>
<p>At first I was okay with this because my focus was getting the redesign on the
right track, however, looking back it was the wrong decision. Un-semantic code
goes against everything the Standards movement has fought for.</p>
<p>Do I shed a tear? No. I&rsquo;m not an elitist in this area anymore and I don&rsquo;t go
sniffing for validation errors because I value usability, style and harmony
more. But, the blatant un-semantic-ness of this framework still disgusts me.</p>
<p>So I was quite surprised and sickened to find out Olav launched this almost
identical framework, Blueprint. Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, it&rsquo;s great for prototyping
but don&rsquo;t settle for it. Good semantic names are worth every penny. Also,
frameworks don&rsquo;t belong in markup languages. They just don&rsquo;t.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>