<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2005/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2005-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Worm Club</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2005/worm-club/"/><published>2005-11-13T18:09:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2005/worm-club/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Friends and cohorts keep asking me me to recommend books so in an effort to 
slightly curb this I&rsquo;ve manifested the list below. Warning: I cannot guarantee 
I&rsquo;ve finished these books. I have a tendency, possibly fear, of finishing books. 
I literally get to the last chapter and it sits on my coffee table for weeks. 
So far, these have been intriguing books to me:</p>
<p><strong>Blink and The Tipping Point</strong> by Malcom Gladwell. I group these two together 
because they go hand in hand. Blink is about snap judgement. It takes a very 
micro approach on how we make decisions in the blink of an eye. Tipping Point 
slaps on a macro lens and dives into how we as a society come to fall in love 
with products. Both are fascinating and suited well for anyone interested in the 
human psyche.</p>
<p><strong>A Whole New Mind</strong> by Daniel Pink. The Information Age is nearing it&rsquo;s slow 
death and we&rsquo;re beginning to witness the rise of the Conceptual Age. Think twice 
about getting that MBA. With the outsourcing of &ldquo;information jobs&rdquo; to Asia you 
may want to investigate the fruits of the MFA. This book is a portal to many 
resources and it&rsquo;s been keeping me very busy.</p>
<p><strong>Voices of a People&rsquo;s History of the United States</strong> by Howard Zinn. How did I 
end up believing Christopher Columbus was a &ldquo;great man&rdquo; and worthy of his own 
day. This was a man that &ldquo;kidnapped, maimed and killed the indigenous people of 
Hispanola in pursuit of gold.&rdquo; This book sheds much needed light on those who in 
the face of opposition and hardship spoke out. This undeniable view of history 
is shocking and raw.</p>
<p>Graphic Designers Guide to Clients by Ellen Shapiro. I used to be very defensive 
around clients. Mainly because I lacked the ability to put myself in their 
shoes. Shapiro provides numerous real world examples of successful client 
relationships.</p>
<p>Story, Substance, Structure, Style, and The Principles of Screenwriting by 
Robert McKee. Why should a web designer care about story? It happens to be the 
vehicle to our minds. A good story can elicit any number of emotions. Emotions 
are products of the right side of our brain which is the gateway to the left. 
In advertising or design we must be in tune with this so our message effectively 
captivates its audience. McKee intricately dissects the building blocks of good 
story.</p>
<p>Hopefully this will wet your appetite. Any number of these will make you think 
differently after setting them down. I&rsquo;ve been permanently altered by all of 
them.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Ruby Text Search</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2005/ruby-text-search/"/><published>2005-11-05T18:10:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2005/ruby-text-search/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I found some great Ruby code to assist in <em>creating a simplistic search engine</em> 
for your Rails app. It can be found on the Rails Wiki under <a href="http://wiki.rubyonrails.com/rails/pages/TextSearch">TextSearch</a>. I recommend clicking on 
the &ldquo;edit&rdquo; button at the bottom to copy and paste the code out of the text field 
because some of the syntax gets lost on the page version. Just don&rsquo;t click save :)</p>
<p>You may want to add &lsquo;%&quot; on either side of the search terms. This will increase 
results by returning words like &ldquo;redesign&rdquo; when the term &ldquo;design&rdquo; has been 
searched. There is also some code on the page to help search multiple keywords 
instead of phrases. This could be altered to act like Google where if you want 
to search by a phrase you encapsulate the phrase with quotes. You would then 
just do a check for quotes before breaking the words into an array.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Four Horsemen</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2005/four-horsemen/"/><published>2005-10-14T18:11:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2005/four-horsemen/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>No the rumors are not true. I haven&rsquo;t been kidnapped by the government in 
suspicion of plotting the end of the world. Although some may suggest it is the 
dawn of the end. Jesus, yes I do mean you, what the hell is going on? <em>Earth is 
shakin, wind is blowin, water is getting everywhere, and birds are out of 
control!</em></p>
<p>Not too worry, it hasn&rsquo;t disrupted the good old midwest, yet. <a href="http://www.brmethod.com">We&rsquo;re</a> hard at work in these parts. I&rsquo;ve all but given up on 
PHP for a sexier gem called Ruby. The holy trinity of Ruby, ActionScript 3.0, 
and Javascript are upon us. If you throw in XML you could call them the Four 
Horsemen of the Apocalypse but I&rsquo;d like to refrain from the Armageddon 
references. A show of hands please, is everyone ready for Web 2.0? If not here 
are some great links that will help.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=4762944544960468107">Kevin Lynch at Web 2.0 Conference</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.veen.com/jeff/archives/000793.html">Jeffrey Veen at Web Essentials &lsquo;05</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/a/oreilly/tim/news/2005/09/30/what-is-web-20.html">What is Web 2.0?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://script.aculo.us/">Scriptaculous</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.macromedia.com/software/flex/special/web2/">Flex 2</a></li>
<li><a href="http://we05.com/">Web Essentials &lsquo;05</a></li>
</ul>
<p>On another note. You may or may not have noticed some changes to this site. The 
RSS feed now features integrated bookmarks and photoblog entries. I&rsquo;ve also 
fixed all the IE6 bugs, sorry 95% of my audience :)</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Innocent Bystander</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2005/innocent-bystander/"/><published>2005-09-24T18:12:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2005/innocent-bystander/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Everyone should participate in a little people watching activities. It allows 
you to jump out of your inner chaotic life and realize that you&rsquo;re not alone. 
Now, there are a few keys to successful people watching. I&rsquo;ll share some of 
mine, then you can pass yours along if you wish.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Avoid eye contact.</em> In order to remain a fly on the wall you must avoid eye 
contact at all costs. After a while you begin to anticipate when someone will 
look at you. This is a honed skill that comes with time and patients. A good
pair of sunglasses can help beginners.</li>
<li><em>Daydreaming is a side effect, and its Okay.</em> This allows you to &ldquo;figure stuff 
out.&rdquo; In my opinion we don&rsquo;t daydream enough. We get so caught up in <em>doing</em> 
and we forget <em>why.</em> Those are perfect moments to gain understanding with 
the help of those around you.</li>
<li><em>Location is key.</em> I like coffee hang outs. Villages, Malls, Districts, or any 
high traffic parts of your metropolis where eclecticism is prevalent. I prefer 
a corner in midtown where coffee houses collide, a lonely clothing store 
awaits hipsters, and bars are armed with dollar draws and outdoor patios. The 
collage of people has the characteristics of a Rauschenberg 
(<a href="http://images.google.com/images?q=rauschenberg">http://images.google.com/images?q=rauschenberg</a>) exhibit.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now its your turn. How, where, and why do you people watch? What strange stories 
have you made up or overheard during your excursions? Do tell :)</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Full Steam Ahead</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2005/full-steam-ahead/"/><published>2005-09-05T18:12:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2005/full-steam-ahead/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Playground Blues is officially on <a href="http://www.rubyonrails.com">Rails</a>. 
Approximately <a href="http://playgroundblues.com/archive/bejeweled">two weeks</a> ago I 
started chugging along and with this new language. Surprisingly it&rsquo;s been quite 
welcoming and easy to learn. I only wish it were just as easy to ween clients 
over to this oasis.</p>
<p>Along with the change of language came some other needed changes. One of them 
being my move from Textile to <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a> 
otherwise known as <a href="http://www.deveiate.org/projects/BlueCloth">BlueCloth</a> in 
Rails. Markdown just seemed more natural to the way I type. Another change 
included a new Flash Photoblog that is built using an <a href="http://www.actionscript.org/tutorials/intermediate/Flash_Broadcasters_and_Listeners/index.shtml">asynchronous event model</a> 
philosophy. I&rsquo;ve been trying to wrap my mind around this more and I think I&rsquo;m 
beginning to understand its major benefits.</p>
<p>Stay tuned. This is an exciting endeavor and I&rsquo;ve got a lot more tricks up my 
sleeve.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Art Mobs</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2005/art-mobs/"/><published>2005-08-28T18:14:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2005/art-mobs/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I have a new PodCast to add to your library. It&rsquo;s by <a href="http://mod.blogs.com/">Art Mobs</a> and its called <a href="http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=74263942">Art Mobs MoMA Guides</a>.
The descriptions is &ldquo;A &lsquo;Commons&rsquo; for audio guides to artworks at the <a href="http://www.moma.org">Museum of
Modern Art</a>, NYC.&rdquo; Basically an entertaining discussion
about modern art. I think this is by far the most creative use of PodCasting,
no pun intended.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Bejeweled</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2005/bejeweled/"/><published>2005-08-15T18:15:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2005/bejeweled/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>I spent last weekend learning Ruby on Rails (<a href="http://www.rubyonrails.com">http://www.rubyonrails.com</a>) and now 
I can&rsquo;t help but wonder why the hell it took me so long. My work 
(<a href="http://www.bradv.com">http://www.bradv.com</a>) was kind enough to fetch me a copy of Agile Web 
Development with Rails (<a href="http://pragmaticprogrammer.com/titles/rails/index.html">http://pragmaticprogrammer.com/titles/rails/index.html</a>) 
and I&rsquo;ve had a hard time focusing on anything else.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve already started porting some of my apps (<a href="http://glide.playgroundblues.com">http://glide.playgroundblues.com</a>) 
to Rails and its surprisingly elegant and fun. After figuring out associations 
between database tables I feel well on my way. There is still a lot to get used 
to. Mainly Ruby&rsquo;s syntax. It&rsquo;s very different than any language I&rsquo;ve used. I&rsquo;m 
really diggin' the &ldquo;everything is an object&rdquo; mentality.</p>
<p>Some tips if your interested&hellip; Install FastCGI 
(<a href="http://wiki.rubyonrails.com/rails/show/FastCGI%20on%20OS%20X)">http://wiki.rubyonrails.com/rails/show/FastCGI%20on%20OS%20X)</a>. It will 
dramatically increase the responsiveness of Ruby. Dreamhost has this option in 
their panel. Be on the lookout for some MySQL issues 
(<a href="http://wiki.rubyonrails.com/rails/show/HowtoInstallOnOSXTiger">http://wiki.rubyonrails.com/rails/show/HowtoInstallOnOSXTiger</a>) if your using 
Tiger. Also make sure to point your VirtualHost entry to the /public folder in 
your rails app. You could also do this with a .htaccess file in the root.</p>
<p>Be on the look out for a Rubified Playground Blues in the near future :)</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Pre-Order Rant</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2005/pre-order-rant/"/><published>2005-05-31T18:16:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2005/pre-order-rant/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Why would anybody want to pre-order an album off of iTunes? The whole idea of 
the &ldquo;pre-order&rdquo; is that your John Hancock gets placed on a list of elite few who 
get first dibs on a product before it sells out. It is virtually impossible for 
iTunes to sell out of a song, which makes me wonder what yahoo in the war room 
decided it&rsquo;d be cool to have &ldquo;pre-orders&rdquo; in iTunes. Downloadable music is 
branded as instant satisfaction which makes this confusing.</p>
<p>I understand it sort of serves as a teaser but this is the web and thats just a 
lame use of it. Offer me an exclusive song and tell me it&rsquo;ll be followed up by 
an album (which they already do and seems to work). I pray for the server 
administrators that sweat their bandwidth skyrocket when the clock strikes 
twelve and um-teen-thousand albums are automatically dispersed. (End of rant)</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Background Becoming Foreground</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2005/background-becoming-foreground/"/><published>2005-05-10T18:17:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2005/background-becoming-foreground/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>Since the release of Tiger and particularly Quicktime 7 sporting the new H.264 
codec I&rsquo;m beginning to wonder if we&rsquo;re glimpsing a bigger picture here. If you 
haven&rsquo;t checked out the unbelievable quality of H.264 go over to the <a href="http://www.apple.com/quicktime/hdgallery/">HD Gallery</a> and witness the days of pixilation 
disappear.</p>
<p>With this brings some interesting thoughts; does Apple have a roadmap for video 
on demand? Well, they&rsquo;ve already started doing it with iTunes 4.8. We now have 
the choice to buy music videos and video extras that would normally be found on 
CD&rsquo;s. This however doesn&rsquo;t seem to be using the H.264 codec at the moment but 
I&rsquo;m sure it will follow. Will the iPod soon have video functionality to echo 
iTunes?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>People love listening to music as a background activity when they&rsquo;re 
exercising, when they&rsquo;re commuting and when they&rsquo;re just hanging out. Music is 
a wonderful thing because A, it&rsquo;s music, and B, because it can be listened to 
as a background activity. And a lot of these other things that people are 
talking about building in, such as video and things like that, are foreground 
activities.
&ndash; Steve Jobs</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It appears the iPod is slowly creeping into our foreground. Right behind it 
could be a video-on-demand Mac Mini. I only hope they choose to offer not-so 
mainstream content like Independent Films and Documentaries that you wouldn&rsquo;t 
normally find on television. Could this also pave the way for a new bread of 
video podcasts? Vidcasts?</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Farewell and Hello</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2005/farewell-and-hello/"/><published>2005-05-02T18:17:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2005/farewell-and-hello/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p>This is my last week at my current employer, <a href="http://www.lookandfeel.com">Look and Feel</a> which would explain my lack of good posts. I can&rsquo;t 
express how fortunate I am to have spent time with the fine lads of LaF. I will 
miss them dearly, although, I&rsquo;ll still be living in the neighborhood so I&rsquo;m sure 
our paths will cross.</p>
<p>My near future rests at a place called <a href="http://www.brmethod.com">Method</a> within 
<a href="http://www.bernstein-rein.com">Bernstein-Rein</a>. A fortune teller has forcasted 
very long hours but many laughs and Belgium beer flowing from the hill tops. Ok, 
maybe not the last one so much. I&rsquo;ll be #7 of an extremely talented group 
scrambling to keep up.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>