<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools on Nathan Borror</title><link>https://nathan.run/tools/</link><description>Recent content in Tools on Nathan Borror</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://nathan.run/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Logger</title><link>https://nathan.run/tools/logger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/tools/logger/</guid><description>Logger lets you quickly send messages to yourself as a means of fast note taking. All messages you send to yourself show up chronologically. Tapping the spacebar before entering any text puts you in a search mode for easy filtering. Hashtags can be used to categorize notes. All data is stored on your device and not shared with the cloud. Download from the App Store
This was my first personal project to go into the App Store.</description></item><item><title>Play</title><link>https://nathan.run/tools/play/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/tools/play/</guid><description>How I built a Sonos replacement app in 2014 Back in 2014 in my spare time I built an app to replace the default Sonos app used to control multiple speakers in a home. It was a little challenging so I thought I’d share the process. You can check out most of the code on Github.
Finding the API First off I needed to understand how the existing app was communicating with speakers on the local network.</description></item><item><title>Podster</title><link>https://nathan.run/tools/podster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/tools/podster/</guid><description>My attempt at a very simple client-side RSS parser for podcasts after so much frustration with Apple&amp;rsquo;s Podcast app. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been working on this as much lately since Apple seems to have made some major strides but I still think I can get this to be faster using Go for all the feed fetching.</description></item><item><title>Readernaut</title><link>https://nathan.run/tools/readernaut/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/tools/readernaut/</guid><description>Readernaut is a social network for people who want to share what they&amp;rsquo;re reading. This has been a passion project since 2008. Register for a free account.
Currently working on an update that resurrects the activity feed and makes it a little more visually appealing.
Work in progress.</description></item><item><title>Steady</title><link>https://nathan.run/tools/steady/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.run/tools/steady/</guid><description>Steady is an experimental tool for tracking personal routines. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to come up with ways to incentivize and track more steady routines. Having a visualization that kind of encourages a streak seems to help me. Sorta stole this idea from Strava when I realized how much I tried to fill out their daily bar graph.
Current overall look of the app. Currently testing but should have something in the App Store this Spring 2021.</description></item></channel></rss>