<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nathan Borror</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nathan.run/posts/2019/index.xml"/><rights>Copyright © 2022, Nathan Borror</rights><updated>2019-12-31T09:31:04-0800</updated><entry><title>Running Cone Peak Trails</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2019/running-cone-peak-trails/"/><published>2019-12-02T12:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2019/running-cone-peak-trails/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p><em>Vincente Flat Trail → Cone Peak Rd → Cone Peak Trail ◭ Cone Peak Trail → Cone Peak Rd → Vincente Flat Trail</em></p>
<figure class="small right hang">
        <a href="/photos/IMG_0392.png"  target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0392.png" alt="Feed in the sand with clear water washing over them."></a>
        
    </figure>
<p>Last Sunday I packed up all my running gear for another long and steep trail run. Nate recently acquired an old van from the 90s that would be our ride to Big Sur. Old vehicles kinda put me on edge but this one felt oddly familiar because growing up at Lake of the Ozarks we had a van like this so all kinds of memories were lighting up.</p>
<p>The drive to Big Sur can be a little boring until you get closer to Monterey where the coast begins to interrupt conversations. We stopped in Carmel for coffee and a walk on the white sands. A sociable red lab was grabbing the attention of every person and dog walking by, cementing my love for red labradors.</p>
<p>We continued down Highway 1 to Big Sur for some lunch at a bakery. Ordering expensive avocado toast in Northern California might be the most cliché thing you can do, but it&rsquo;s so good!</p>
<figure class="small left hang">
        <a href="/photos/IMG_0409.png"  target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0409.png" alt="Avocado toast on a white plate."></a>
        
    </figure>
<p>We made our way to a campground just before sunset and walked around looking for sea otters and whales. We saw two spouts far north of us, an occasional tail, more spouts &ndash; my second time seeing whales in California. A little trail guided us down to the shore with an arched rock framing the sunset.</p>
<p>Nate cooked dinner from the back of the van before we got some rest. We were about three days from a New Moon and the Milky Way was smeared across the sky. I hadn&rsquo;t seen stars like that in years.</p>
<p>Monday morning came fast, Nate made a caffeine concoction of instant coffee, black tea and chai to get us moving. We didn&rsquo;t waste much time moving the van to the trailhead. I love just getting up and going in the morning, leaving no room for hesitation.</p>
<div class="gallery">
    
  <a href="/photos/IMG_0439.png" target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0439.png" alt="My partner Nate kneeling on a cliff, looking off to the side as the sun goes down."></a>
  <a href="/photos/IMG_0442.png" target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0442.png" alt="Soft blue sky, blue ocean waves hitting the shore and cliffs lit orange by the sunset."></a>
  <a href="/photos/IMG_0452.png" target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0452.png" alt="Sun setting through a rock arch with waves crashing in the distance."></a>
  <a href="/photos/IMG_0475.png" target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0475.png" alt="Warm sunset colors outside the door of our van."></a>
  <a href="/photos/IMG_0487.png" target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0487.png" alt="Nate cooking out the back of our van with lights on inside."></a>

</div>
<p>Vincente Flat Trail was a constant but not exhausting climb. I have a tendency to focus too much on the immediate path ahead so each time I looked up the increasingly vast coastal scenery would be overwhelming. The temptation to pull out my camera was hard to resist.</p>
<p>Aside from the scenery some of my favorite moments were descending into the valleys with streams and the smell of damp forrest. There were a few campers that morning so with quiet feet we moved through campsites and greeted sleepy eyes. One valley felt like an obstacle course with fallen trees and hard to see paths, luckily Nate was familiar with the area and guided us through with ease.</p>
<div class="gallery">
    
  <a href="/photos/IMG_0510.png" target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0510.png" alt="Nate driving the van while talking. Ocean in the distance."></a>
  <a href="/photos/IMG_0525.png" target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0525.png" alt="Sun rising over some hills and cliffs with the ocean to the west."></a>
  <a href="/photos/IMG_0529.png" target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0529.png" alt="Nate hiking up the trail with a creek running alongside us."></a>

</div>
<p>I&rsquo;m still pretty new to long distance and trail running so it was nice to have her keeping conversation pace and giving me subtle cues to eat when she ate. Runs like this are a great way to get to know someone.</p>
<p>We reached the summit after passing a couple volunteer park rangers. The wind was fierce so we didn&rsquo;t waste much time. After some chit-chat with the volunteers we made our descent. Most of it felt like a controlled fall, Nate bombs down hills and I could tell she was enjoying this part. My quads were on fire but determined to keep up.</p>
<div class="gallery">
    
  <a href="/photos/IMG_0532.png" target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0532.png" alt="A distant view of Cone Peak in the morning sunlight."></a>
  <a href="/photos/IMG_0551.png" target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0551.png" alt="Lookout shelter ontop of Cone Peak. Very blue sky and ocean in the distance."></a>
  <a href="/photos/IMG_0553.png" target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0553.png" alt="Mid-day sun lighting up the green hills below, ocean to the west."></a>

</div>
<p>At around mile 15 I was beginning to feel pretty exhausted. It was becoming clear I had not eaten enough on the way up. Around Mile 17 I ran out of water and hesitated to fill up at a stream. Lesson learned: when faced with stream water vs no water, always chose stream water. I honestly don&rsquo;t even remember the final mile because my body just took over and did everything it could to finish. Once we reached the van I totally spaced out chugging water in the front seat. Nate handed me a tangerine that lit up my tastebuds and snapped me back into existence.</p>
<p>We ran 21 miles up 6,782 feet over the course of about five and a half hours. This was my longest and highest run to date. Pretty sure I rode an endorphin high for the next three days!</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Running Muir Woods Trails</title><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://nathan.run/2019/running-muir-woods-trails/"/><published>2019-11-08T12:00:00-0800</published><author><name>Nathan Borror</name><uri>https://nathan.run</uri></author><id>https://nathan.run/2019/running-muir-woods-trails/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nathan.run/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
        <p><em>Dipsea → Sun Trail → Redwood Trail → Panoramic Trail → Ocean View Trail → Matt Davis Trail → Old Mine Trail → Coastal Trail → Redwood Creek Trail → Ben Johnson Trail → Hillside Trail → Dipsea</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Beyond the very extreme of fatigue and distress, we may find amounts of ease and power we never dreamed ourselves to own; sources of strength never taxed at all because we never push through the obstruction.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Woke up around 5AM yesterday anxious to get on the trail. After some morning prep I walked outside to my car and immediately felt the cold air. Almost nine years of Northern California has decimated my resolve towards cold temperatures and there&rsquo;s only one way to warm up this morning!</p>
<p>The short drive to Mill Valley is one of my favorites. The Golden Gate Bridge will forever symbolize adventure to me. Anything I&rsquo;ve ever done up north has felt like an escape with the Bridge as my welcoming party.</p>
<figure class="small right hang">
        <a href="/photos/IMG_0259.png"  target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0259.png" alt=""></a>
        
    </figure>
<p>Arriving at the trailhead a little early meant I could grab an espresso at Equator. A couple old men sat inside sipping coffee in the comfort of the morning&rsquo;s newspaper. I was hoping the cafe would be warm, a last minute reprieve from the cold, but they had the doors and windows wide open signaling to me to just get on with it.</p>
<p>With a small pack and gloves I tied on a green bandana and took off for the Dipsea stairs. The roughly 700 foot climb is just the warm up I needed although a bit dizzying at times. Sun Trail was a nice change of pace with golden views of the western valley as the sun rose. Little birds hang out in the bushes along this trail, as I passed they&rsquo;d shuffle around nervously.</p>
<figure class="small left hang">
        <a href="/photos/IMG_0260.png"  target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0260.png" alt=""></a>
        
    </figure>
<p>Sun Trail turns into Redwood Trail pretty quickly as I darted through some damper paths with trees holding the sun at bay. Poison oak was everywhere which always makes me a little cautious. Panoramic and Ocean View Trails lived up to their names as the steady climb continued. Through all my excitement I kept having to remind myself to slow down, this wasn&rsquo;t a typical 10K run today.</p>
<p>Matt Davis Trail was the first stretch where I could forget about the map and relax a little. After cutting across Panoramic Highway I enjoyed some much earned downhill. The Old Mine Trail felt like a luxury with its plentiful paths, a nice reward for the 1,500 foot climb.</p>
<p>The absence of fog created some breathtaking views from the Coastal Trail. At first I was a little put off seeing the city skyline I was attempting to escape, but the overwhelming layers of nature&rsquo;s skyline helped make the city look less significant.</p>
<figure class="medium right hang">
        <a href="/photos/IMG_0305.png"  target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0305.png" alt=""></a>
        
    </figure>
<p>The switchbacks of Heather Cutoff created a zen-like descent into the valley. Wind was blocked by warm hills, all I could hear were birds chirping and careful footsteps. Each sharp turn marked by big boulders forced me to slow and focus on movement.</p>
<p>Redwood Creek Trail was all smells and chilly. Tried to enjoy it knowing I was about to make a steep thousand foot climb. The Dipsea and Deer Park Fire Road weave back and forth to create a confusing path. At times I&rsquo;d realize I was on one when my map said I should be on the other but it didn&rsquo;t matter. The climb was mentally challenging so I tried to distract myself with some calories and a methodical water routine. Reaching my whits end I saw a little grove of redwoods reminding me why I love this area so much. Those towering works of nature distracted me from the exhaustion and set me up for an invigorating turn onto the Ben Johnson Trail.</p>
<figure>
        <a href="/photos/IMG_0330.png"  target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0330.png" alt=""></a>
        
    </figure>
<p>The descent into Muir Woods engaged all senses and eliminated any doubt about completing this journey. It was hard not to greet each sleepy eyed tourist with enthusiasm along Hillside Trail. I had already completed my three hour goal for the day and the rest was a bonus ride. Exiting the park put me face-to-face with yet another Dipsea climb, the last before reuniting with the stairs. The struggle up to Panoramic Highway took every last bit of energy. Approaching the stairs down to Mill Valley signaled the completion of one of the best mornings I&rsquo;ve had in California.</p>
<figure>
        <a href="/photos/IMG_0331.png"  target="_blank"><img src="/photos/IMG_0331.png" alt=""></a>
        
    </figure>
<p>I was able to run 18 miles over the course of three and a half hours, exceeding my goal for the day and setting a personal record of distance and time. I&rsquo;ve got a little over a month to work up to six hours and hopefully 30 miles before the New Year&rsquo;s run. This journey reminds me of a William James quote that Scott Jurek likes to preach:</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>